<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_TITLE">
			<Text>Tokugawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_QUOTE">
			<Text>I think I can be stronger than I am now, but long perseverance has made me what I am today. If my descendants want to be strong, they must study patience.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Tokugawa (last name, first name Ieyasu) is a brilliant military and peacetime strategist. He is the decisive winner of Japan’s chaotic Sengoku period and the architect of the subsequent Edo period.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The chaos of the Sengoku Jidai (period) in Japanese history has become iconic. In the subsequent prosperity and peace of the Edo period, samurai had little to do but entertain each other with stories about the great battles, leaders, and goings-on of that time – ninjas, generals, armies, sieges, and the like. Much of what we imagine about feudal Japan is itself a product of these stories, embellished and romanticized.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The Sengoku period was a massive war between rival clans to seek power. The weak Ashikaga shogunate collapsed, leaving the emperor a mere figurehead and the more powerful position of shōgun (military guardian of the Emperor) open. For over a century, rival daimyō (regional lords) and samurai (knights) fought for this title. Into the fray, too, came other elements: Christians, armed by Europeans with muskets, the anti-monarchical ikkō-ikki, and the ninja – these last being military strategists without a concept of honor who could commit scandalous acts to benefit their lord. Three samurai emerge into the spotlight: Oda Nobunaga, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, and Tokugawa Ieyasu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>There is a story that reflects an aspect of the personalities and motivations of these leaders. Imagine the three of them sitting together looking at a little bird that refuses to sing. Oda opens with a threat: “bird, if you do not sing, I will kill you.” Hideyoshi tries manipulation, “bird, if you do not sing, I will convince you.” But Tokugawa, the canniest of the three, simply says, “bird, I can wait.” Here, patience and a cool head win the day – and so it was with Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Oda, the “demon king,” lived up to his name. As the head of the Oda clan, Nobunaga rallied his troops to sweep across the main island of Japan, defeating the ikkō-ikki and removing the Ashikaga shogunate entirely. The last remaining obstacle was the powerful western clan Mōri, who may well have been defeated, too, were it not for a betrayal from within Oda’s own ranks. Seeing Akechi, the traitorous general, coming towards him as he sat relatively unguarded having tea in a temple in Kyoto, Oda committed suicide. The to-be shōgun Tokugawa, too, fled in the company of the ninja (well, samurai at that time) Hattori Hanzō.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>The Toyotomi clan was the next to take up Oda’s banner. Former retainer, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, took up the banner and, too, seized temporary control. Indeed, it was under Hideyoshi that Japanese forces sought to take Korea, and not for the last time. But even the greatest of kings dies, and Hideyoshi, with his focus on overseas expansion, had drained the coffers. A succession crisis ensued between clan loyalists and the new Tokugawa clan, itself formed from a regional vassal clan of Oda’s, under Tokugawa Ieyasu. In the climactic Battle of Sekigahara, Tokugawa achieved dominance and set about picking up the pieces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Japan was a mess. New ideas were flooding in – republicanism (meaning here rule by the people) and Christianity. Guns and European trade, too, presented an issue. Tokugawa singlehandedly stopped this by implementing sakoku – isolation. Japan’s borders would be closed, except for Nagasaki. This would end both the influx of new and dangerous challenges to the new Tokugawa Shogunate but also an end to the kind of foreign adventures that had led to Hideyoshi’s financial woes. Sakoku was… not disastrous for Japan. Local production flourished, and over what became known as the Edo period (Edo being the home of the shogunate), Japan experienced peace and prosperity… and its neighbors no longer had to worry about samurai showing up on their shores.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>The system of control here was brutal. There were still nobles, but Tokugawa had an ingenious strategy for controlling them. While nobles ruled their home provinces, their families remained behind as hostages (of a sort) in Edo. This meant that any rebellion could immediately be squashed via a simple threat to the rebel’s family and also the growth of court life in Edo. Bored but wealthy samurai told stories, and would-be warriors fought duels over honor instead of for land. The famous ukiyo-e, the “floating world” of entertainment, grew, as did artists and writers associated with it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>This was to crack open in the 1800s, with the arrival (and, significantly, threats to not depart) of American ships demanding trade. Japan realized that the world had developed without them and that things like guns and cannons had gotten quite dangerous. While their opening was traumatic, and the subsequent Meiji period eliminated much of the feudal system of Japan, the infrastructure was already in place to enable Meiji to, within a few decades, take on and defeat some of the most powerful states in the world. But that is a story for another time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Japan under Tokugawa likes to isolate itself by creating lots of Domestic [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes and districts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>The Meiji Restoration ability gives large adjacency bonuses to Japan’s districts. Districts also receive +1 [ICON_Tourism] Tourism if they are in a city near the [ICON_Capital] Capital from Tokugawa’s ability. His ability also greatly increases Domestic [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route’s yields for every district. But be aware that International [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes are much weaker. The Electronics Factory will help him towards a Culture or Science Victory.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_TITLE">
			<Text>Nader Shah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_QUOTE">
			<Text>If there is no war in paradise, how may there be any delights there?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Nader Shah, the King of Kings, the Shah of Shahs, emerged in the 18th century to re-establish Persia (as it is called in Greek, the locals always called their state Iran) in Central Asia. His rise was brutal but decisive, carving independence out for Iran away from Ottoman domination. In a chain from Genghis Khan to Timur, Nader Shah is the final link.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Safavid Iran was a powerful state, emerging in the 1500s to rule for 200 years as a Shi’ia redoubt in the midst of a Sunni-controlled area and also an area with powerful and long-lasting Christian influences. But while the Safavids could contain the old threats of Central Asian warlords, they could not contain the rise of the Ottomans and the rise of Russia pressing in on two sides. Further, the growth of European sea trade networks cut off a vital source of income for Central Asian states – this was the point of early colonialism, to remove middlemen from trade with China. The fall of the bankrupt Safavids came from all fronts – from Russia, Turkey, and, finally, from a rising Afghan power.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Nader was a slave, a Turkic-speaking nomad who achieved fame for his military skill. When the Safavids fell, Nader took his musket and went into rebellion. He defeated the Afghans first, then turned to the Ottomans and the Russians. After killing the Ottoman general and signing a peace treaty with Russia, Nader declared himself Shah. In this, he echoed Timur and Genghis Khan, both personal idols of his.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Whereas the Safavids were a Shi’ia exclusive group, under Nader, Iran became multi-religious and more tolerant. It was a selling point to the Sunni Ottomans with whom, after they fought to a stalemate, Nader Shah sought closer ties. This tolerance in terms of religion is in part owing to his own background – as a former slave and present-day military commander, he cared little for religion and, in his own life, moved between Sunni and Shi’ia as was convenient. Better to invest in the army than in priests, as the former would secure peace. Elsewhere in the empire, Nader Shah created a standardized coinage pegged to the Mughal rupee and resettled nomadic tribes in the area.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Nader embarked on a reign of terror across Central Asia after solidifying his reign. He invaded India and seized Delhi, as the Mughals had become weak – they would, in coming decades, become weaker still as the British invaded via Bengal. He seized the Peacock Throne and, while he could not hold it, used the occupation to plunder that realm’s wealth. The campaign was marked with Nader’s trademark military acumen, forcing his soldiers to outflank the enemy both strategically in the realm as well as tactically on the battlefield. Later campaigns against the Ottoman Arabian possessions were likewise successful, though not nearly as daring.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Towards the end of his life, Nader Shah became increasingly unhinged. He ordered his own son blinded, then regretted it. He built towers of skulls of his enemies. At the end of his conquests, he was the richest man in the world. But he had made enemies – he was assassinated by conspirators, including his nephew, and the empire crumbled.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Fight opposing Civilizations with Nader Shah’s combat bonus against full Health units and bask in the wealth from Persia’s Domestic [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NADER_SHAH_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Nader Shah should go for Iron Working and Political Philosophy right out of the gate. Iron Working gives him access to his powerful Immortals. These Immortals can crush their opponents with their Ranged Attack and the +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength against full Health opponents. On the way towards Political Philosophy, you will unlock Foreign Trade and Early Empire. The first of these, Foreign Trade, will give you access to [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes which receive benefits from both Nader Shah and Persia’s abilities. After Foreign Trade you will unlock the Pairidaeza improvement which are great for [ICON_Gold] Gold and [ICON_Culture] Culture. Once you unlock Political Philosophy, an extra [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route is your reward. The two victories Persia is best at are Culture with their Pairidaezas or Domination with their Immortals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SULEIMAN_TITLE">
			<Text>Suleiman (Kanuni)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SULEIMAN_ALT_TITLE">
			<Text>Suleiman (Muhteşem)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SULEIMAN_ALT_QUOTE">
			<Text>My companion, my everything, my shiny moon.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SULEIMAN_ALT_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Suleiman celebrates the Golden Age of the Ottomans with increased [ICON_Science] Science and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. If he falls into a Dark Age his opponents should beware. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SULEIMAN_ALT_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Suleiman’s strategy depends on whether he is in a Golden or Dark Age. If he is in a [ICON_GLORY_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age he receives +15% [ICON_Science] Science and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, so focus on progressing and enlightening your empire. When he does fall into a Dark or Normal Age use his +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength against other civilizations who are not in a [ICON_GLORY_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age. His bonuses to siege warfare gives an extra push to conquer his enemies. The Grand Bazaar gives the Ottomans stability and prosperity to a growing empire with its extra [ICON_Amenities] Amenities, [Icon_Gold] Gold, and Strategic Resources. Use the Barbary Corsairs to maintain control of the waterways. The Ottomans are mostly geared for Domination Victories, but if they string enough Golden Ages together, they can achieve a Science Victory instead.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
