<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_TITLE">
			<Text>Yongle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>Many a state has fallen because a ruler does not know the affairs of his people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The most forward-thinking and outward-looking of the Ming emperors, Yongle built the foundation for Ming’s international system and rebuilt its infrastructure. He did so via a ruthless bid for legitimacy, in which he destroyed all opposition to his claim but then expanded outward, gathering support and foreign gold for what was to become China’s quintessential empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Ming Dynasty was a moment of reconsolidation for China, where, after years of foreign rule, the Han Chinese established a Han-centric power that was to last and remain prosperous for centuries. Ming was wealthy, peaceful, and… for a time… advanced. Ming was also successful in incorporating its neighbors into its orbit; the tributary system pulled much of East Asia together into a protection alliance that would lead to regional stability and the expansion of Confucian values. But over time, Ming fell into complacency and isolation, and while Ming entered the race well ahead of its competition, it emerged weakened, over-dependent on foreign gold, and unprepared for how the world had changed around it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Such events might not have happened had the Yongle emperor had his way.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Yongle was born Zhu Di in 1360. He was the second son of another great Ming emperor – the Hongwu emperor. As such, he was an important person and a military commander who had been fighting the Mongols – both the remnants of the Yuan Dynasty as well as the great Khanates of the west. Zhu Di was next in line for the throne after his older brother, Zhu Biao. Well… so the story goes – others say Zhu Di was not at all the son of the Emperor’s primary consort but of a lesser concubine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>But Zhu Biao was his father’s favorite. And this favor extended to Biao’s family, including his son. So when Zhu Biao died suddenly, the Hongwu emperor named Zhu Biao’s son, not Zhu Di, as next in line… and Zhu Di went into rebellion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Zhu Di fought a three-year war and won, renaming himself the Yongle Emperor. He then swept the bureaucracy ruthlessly for any trace of his nephew’s influence. This was considerable – recall the Confucian edicts to accept a peaceful rule, many scholars opposed the takeover. But many others were swept up in association - Yongle ordered the death of his enemies, especially the famous Fang Xiarou, but also everyone who had passed their exams during Fang’s tenure, all of Fang’s relatives (out to the tenth degree), and on, and on. Thousands were killed. Further, Yongle banned Mongolian cultural forms, something which had been predominant under the Yuan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Yongle then set about making a new society. He expanded the role of the eunuchs, even including a secret police (the Eastern Depot) loyal to the emperor. He expanded, too, the scholars and historians – at least those who agreed to strike his nephew from history (and, some say, to rewrite history making Yongle the son of the Empress, not a Korean concubine). This rule extended, too, from a new source: the Forbidden City, built to mark Beijing as a new capital, closer to the Mongol lines (so as to better lead the war) and closer to Yongle’s old military outposts. With this came a reconstruction and re-fortification of the Great Wall and a re-opening of the Grand Canal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Hongwu (Yongle’s father) was an isolationist; indeed, isolation was to be the plague of the Ming. But Yongle was rather the opposite. He actively cultivated and expanded the tribute system – indeed, this was what Zheng He’s voyages were all about – finding new potential tributaries. These trips went out to India, the Persian Gulf, and Africa, although tributaries really only came from East Asia. Significant here was the courting of Tibet – recall that Tibet remains a source of Buddhist knowledge for much of Chinese history; Ming is no different. Militarily speaking, Yongle attacked the Mongols and Vietnam, incorporating the latter into the Chinese empire and sparking the massacre of the Tran nobles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>Another achievement was the Yongle Dadian Encyclopedia, a massive work that encapsulated all Chinese knowledge to that point. There’s little new here, but a compilation of everything previously known.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10">
			<Text>Yongle died during a military campaign against the Mongols in 1424, at the age of 64.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Yongle controls his cities with Projects at first, and larger cities receive additional [ICON_Gold] Gold, [Icon_Science] Science, and [ICON_Culture] Culture from their population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_YONGLE_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Yongle wants to control his population with his Lijia ability. In his cities, unique projects convert their [ICON_Production] Production into [ICON_Food] Food, [ICON_Faith] Faith or [ICON_Gold] Gold. Then, when the city reaches 10 population, the population celebrates with additional [ICON_Gold] Gold, [Icon_Science] Science, and [ICON_Culture] Culture. His civilization ability further helps his [Icon_Science] Science and [ICON_Culture] Culture progression with free and better Eurekas and Inspirations. The Crouching Tiger helps protect his empire from invaders, but it is the Great Wall that makes him a powerful force towards a Culture Victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_TITLE">
			<Text>Wu Zetian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_QUOTE">
			<Text>Human beings cannot be resurrected. This is all destiny. The important thing is that those who are alive must continue to live.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The first and only woman to sit on China’s throne, Wu Zetian got to where she got to via assassinations, manipulation, and cunning court strategy. While she was focused on the court, she also altered the way that Chinese politics worked towards a more meritocratic system and away from noble patronage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>We are accustomed to speaking of the 600s as a dark age. But this is a perspective that only sees Europe. In the rest of the world, this is a time of expansion and interconnection, whether or not this be about the growth of the Islamic world, the consolidation of the Chola empires, etc. In China, Tang was the re-emergence of a large empire in the wake of Han. But Tang went further, building a multi-ethnic series of dependencies as well as a flourishing of the arts that would set the stage for later and greater Chinese empires.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Tang was an era of court culture. Porcelain, tea, and all the profits from the Silk Road contributed to the empire’s success, and its capital of Chang’an was the largest city in the world in its time. Tribute systems, while not at the level of later Ming systems, were established, as well as protectorates that reached as far as India and Iran. Most of all, poetry and the arts were at their height during Tang.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>A court culture needs a court villain. And here enters Wu Zetian. The Wu family were wealthy timber merchants, and, like many powerful families, it was the custom to send a daughter to be a concubine of the Imperial court under Emperor Taizong. But Taizong died, and the sickly Gaozong took over.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Gaozong had a wife, the Empress Wang, but favored and had children with a concubine, Xiao. Wang sought to divert Gaozong’s attention from this rival and sought to promote Wu within the court. It backfired. Wu rose, and both Wang and Xiao fell – and fell so badly that Wang had Wu’s daughter strangled in her crib (or, according to others, Wu killed her own daughter and blamed Wang for it). After their deaths in relative obscurity, Wu claimed to be haunted by their spirits.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Wu’s influence over Gaozong grew, especially as his health failed. Her influence was primarily focused on palace intrigue, although she did caution against a conquest of Goguryeo (northern Korea). She began advising him behind a pearl screen, being present at all of his meetings. Upon his death, her son, Li Zhe (the Zhongzong Emperor), takes over, but quickly favors his own in-laws instead of his mother. This set up a clash between the two families and between Wu’s shadow rule and the standard workings of power, a clash that Wu was to win. She deposed her own son and replaced him with his younger, more pliable brother, Li Dan (Ruizhong), in 684.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Here, Wu’s power was more nakedly open. She openly gave orders and, in 690, declared herself Empress regnant and founded her own dynasty, Zhou. She was the first and only woman to ever sit on China’s throne. But as she herself declined in later years, she began to rely more and more on her councilors, especially two brothers, Zhang Yizhi and Zhang Changzong. With power came ambition, and the two Zhang brothers began to resent any other connections or appointments that Wu would make outside of their own. Eventually, rivals in the court plot the Zhang brothers’ death, and, for once, Wu was unable to stop her enemies. The Zhang brothers were killed, and Wu – finally – deposed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Domestically, Wu initiated a number of reforms that both reflected her own – relatively – humble origins as well as set barriers to anyone who would seek to follow in her footsteps. She initiated public reforms curbing female performers and putting limits on women’s fashion but also opened administrative examinations to all men, regardless of status. Further, in a stunning display of power, she eliminated entire branches of the imperial family, shifting the focus of power in China away from powerful families and towards the centralized bureaucracy. Wu’s regime was enforced via her secret police and involved the threat of hidden violence against all who would oppose her. But this was violence largely directed at the court. For commoners, Wu’s reign would have been relatively enlightened – she cut the military, promoted skilled officials, and gave much of royal land to commoners.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>Internationally, Wu promoted Buddhism, even declaring herself to be Maitreya, the Buddha-to-be, but openly clashed with Tibet as well as western Turkic tribes. While Tibet remained independent, the Tibetan Empire lost the ground that it had taken in years past. And while Wu made inroads into Turkic areas, the Western nomadic powers were to have their day several centuries hence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>There are those leaders who will fight you head-on, and then there is Wu Zetian. Her skills are launching offensive spy missions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>China under Wu Zetian focuses on building her empire up while tearing down her opponents’ civilization from the inside. Her bonuses toward Espionage give her an extra Spy and also help her offensive spy operations. When she is successful spying on her enemies, she receives [Icon_Science] Science and [ICON_Culture] Culture to advance in the Technology and Civics Trees. This [Icon_Science] Science and [ICON_Culture] Culture is even more useful when progressing, as Eurekas and Inspirations go even farther with China’s Dynastic Cycle ability. A Culture Victory is best with Wu Zetian, given her ability to steal Great Works easily and the Great Wall’s [ICON_Tourism] Tourism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_QIN_TITLE">
			<Text>Qin (Mandate of Heaven)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_QIN_ALT_TITLE">
			<Text>Qin (Unifier)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_QIN_ALT_QUOTE">
			<Text>I have collected all the writings of the Empire and burnt those which were of no use.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_QIN_ALT_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Barbarians are your allies to recruit with your Melee units to unify the world under Qin’s banner.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_QIN_ALT_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Qin is best when he lets Barbarians begin their invasion, and then turns them over to his side, a strategy that may involve sacrificing a Melee unit to get an army of Barbarians. He can further protect his empire with the Great Wall’s added defense and the Crouching Tiger. Use his extra Eurekas and Inspirations to unlock more powerful units, and move forward to a Domination victory with your Barbarian converts.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
