<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- Ramses-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_YONGLE_NAME">
			<Text>Yongle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_YONGLE_NAME">
			<Text>Lijia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_YONGLE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>All Cities receive Projects where they can convert 50% of their [Icon_Production] Production into [Icon_Food] Food, [Icon_Faith] Faith, or 100% if it is [Icon_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_YONGLE_XP_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>All Cities receive Projects where they can convert 50% of their [Icon_Production] Production into [Icon_Food] Food,  [Icon_Faith] Faith, or 100% if it is [Icon_GOLD] Gold. Cities with 10 or more Population receive +2 [Icon_Gold] Gold, +1 [Icon_Science] Science, and +1 [Icon_Culture] Culture per turn for each Population in the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Qin Alt-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_QIN_ORIGINAL_NAME">
			<Text>Qin (Mandate of Heaven)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_QIN_ALT_NAME">
			<Text>Qin (Unifier)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_QIN_ALT_NAME">
			<Text>Thirty-Six Stratagems</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_QIN_ALT_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Melee units receive the Convert Barbarians action. This action converts Barbarian units into your units, but it removes the melee unit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Wu Zetian-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_NAME">
			<Text>Wu Zetian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_NAME">
			<Text>Manual of Entrapment</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>All offensive Spies operate at 1 level higher. Whenever an offensive spy mission is successful, you also gain 50% of the [ICON_Culture] Culture and [ICON_SCIENCE] Science that the targeted city earned that turn. Receive a free spy (and extra spy capacity) after discovering Defensive Tactics.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_YONGLE">
			<Text>The world awaits, great Yongle Emperor of Ming China. Stretch out your hand and grasp its riches and its knowledge. Place your nation at the center of all things, and let all come to you in supplication. Let none speak ill of you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_WU_ZETIAN">
			<Text>From humble beginnings to the center of the world you rose, Wu Zetian, Empress of China. Do not let the machinations of your court halt you, for you outwit them all. Whether by the painter’s brush, your skill with words, or the poisoned blade you will rise above your foes, and cause the world to bow to you – out of love or fear, there is little difference.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
