<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sejong</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Luís II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Teodora</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Hangul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Ao concluir a primeira Tecnologia de uma nova Era, receba [ICON_CULTURE] cultura igual ao dobro do seu ganho de [ICON_SCIENCE] ciência por turno.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Rei Cisne</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Maravilhas, mesmo que não concluídas, recebem +2 de [ICON_CULTURE] cultura para cada distrito adjacente. Esse ganho de [ICON_CULTURE] cultura é mostrado na produção da cidade. Todas as adjacências de [ICON_CULTURE] cultura fornecem [ICON_TOURISM] turismo após a descoberta de Castelos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Metanoia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Locais Sagrados concedem [ICON_CULTURE] cultura igual ao seu bônus de adjacência. Fazendas concedem um bônus de adjacência de [ICON_FAITH] fé para Hipódromos e Locais Sagrados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sejong Dewang, Sejong, o Grande. Soberano de Joseon, as suas declarações por escrito moldam o curso da história. Uma nova sociedade e uma nova maneira de viver estão em suas mãos. Permita que seu povo viva em harmonia seguindo o seu exemplo e que a sua sabedoria e seu conhecimento guiem a Coreia ao seu destino.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Rei Luís, você é chamado de louco, mas a sua loucura é a loucura dos sonhos, da poesia e dos contos de fadas. Você imaginou que o mundo poderia ser diferente, que poderíamos erguer um reino encantado onde tudo fosse tranquilo e mundano. Ó, Rei Cisne, o mundo precisa de castelos e cavaleiros, de montanhas assombradas por dragões e grutas místicas. Volte e nos traga novos sonhos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Imperatriz Teodora, você foi do nada a governante do que restou de Roma! Com sua inteligência e beleza, você cativou o povo de Constantinopla e tomou o poder em suas próprias mãos. Em tempos de discórdia e divisão, guie a todos com o seu conselho e estampe o seu selo resplandecente sobre as terras.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Sejong</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Louis II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Théodora</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Hangeul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Votre [ICON_SCIENCE] science par tour est doublée et transformée en [ICON_CULTURE] culture lorsque vous découvrez la première technologie d'une nouvelle ère.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Roi cygne</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_CULTURE] Culture +2 pour les merveilles, même non terminées, pour chaque quartier adjacent. Ce bonus de [ICON_CULTURE] culture apparaît dans les rendements de la ville. Tous les bonus de proximité de [ICON_CULTURE] culture génèrent du [ICON_TOURISM] tourisme une fois les châteaux découverts.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Métanoïa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les lieux saints fournissent une quantité de [ICON_CULTURE] culture égale à leurs bonus de proximité. Les fermes fournissent un bonus de proximité de [ICON_FAITH] foi aux hippodromes et aux lieux saints.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Sejong le Grand, souverain de la dynastie Joseon, c'est sous votre plume que des proclamations ayant façonné l'histoire du monde ont vu le jour. Une nouvelle société et une nouvelle façon d'être n'attendent que vous pour s'imposer. Puisse votre peuple apprendre à vivre en harmonie, guidé par votre exemple, et puissent votre sagesse et votre savoir aider la Corée à accomplir son destin.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Roi Louis, on vous surnomme "le Fou", mais votre folie est celle des rêves, de la poésie et des contes de fées. Vous avez imaginé un autre monde, un royaume enchanté que nous aurions pu construire là où tout semblait pénible et ordinaire. Ô Roi cygne, le monde a besoin de vos châteaux et de vos chevaliers, de vos montagnes hantées par des dragons et de vos grottes mystiques. Revenez, et offrez-nous de nouveaux rêves.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Impératrice Théodora, partie de rien, vous avez malgré tout fini par régner sur les vestiges de Rome ! Votre esprit et votre beauté captivaient les citoyens de Constantinople, et vous placèrent à la barre de ce grand navire qu'est votre empire. Dans une époque de conflits et de division, nous avons besoin de vos conseils pour nous guider et de votre sceau incandescent pour illuminer nos terres.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sejong</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ludwig II.</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Theodora</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Hangul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Nach Fertigstellung Eurer ersten Technologie eines neuen Zeitalters, erhaltet Ihr die doppelte Menge der [ICON_SCIENCE] Wissenschaft pro Runde als [ICON_CULTURE] Kultur.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Schwanenkönig</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wunder, selbst nicht fertiggestellte, erhalten +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Kultur für alle angrenzenden Bezirke. Diese [ICON_CULTURE] Kultur wird in den Stadterträgen angezeigt. Alle [ICON_CULTURE] Kulturnachbarschaften gewähren nach der Erforschung von Burgen [ICON_TOURISM] Tourismus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Metanoia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Heilige Stätten gewähren [ICON_CULTURE] Kultur in Höhe ihres Nachbarschaftsbonus. Bauernhöfe gewähren dem Hippodrom und Heiligen Stätten einen [ICON_FAITH] Glauben-Nachbarschaftsbonus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sejong Daewang, Sejong der Große, Herrscher von Joseon, aus Eurer Feder fließen Proklamationen, die den Lauf der Geschichte bestimmen. Eine neue Gesellschaft, eine neue Art des Seins soll von Euch gelenkt werden. Lasst Euer Volk harmonisch nach Eurem Vorbild leben, und führt Korea mit Eurer Weisheit und Eurem Wissen seiner Bestimmung zu. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>König Ludwig, man nennt Euch irre, doch Euer Irrsinn ist der Irrsinn der Träume, der Poesie und der Märchen. Ihr habt Euch vorgestellt, dass die Welt anders sein könnte, dass wir ein verzaubertes Königreich errichten könnten anstelle von allem, was mühsam und gewöhnlich scheint. Oh Schwanenkönig, die Welt braucht Eure Schlösser und Ritter, Eure von Drachen heimgesuchten Berge und mystischen Grotten. Kommt wieder und schenkt uns neue Träume.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kaiserin Theodora, Ihr kommt aus dem Nichts, um die Überreste Roms zu regieren! Mit Eurem Witz und Eurer Schönheit habt Ihr das Volk von Konstantinopel in Euren Bann gezogen und Eure Hand an das große Rad der Macht gelegt. Lasst alle in einer Zeit der Zwietracht und Spaltung durch Euren Rat geleitet sein und setzt Euer leuchtendes Siegel auf das Land.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sejong</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Ludovico II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Teodora</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Hangul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Quando ottieni la prima tecnologia di una nuova epoca ricevi una quantità di [ICON_CULTURE] Cultura pari al doppio della tua [ICON_SCIENCE] Scienza per turno.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Re Cigno</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Le Meraviglie, anche quelle non finite, ricevono +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Cultura per ogni distretto adiacente. Questa [ICON_CULTURE] Cultura è visualizzata nelle rese della città. Tutti i bonus per la posizione alla [ICON_CULTURE] Cultura forniscono anche [ICON_TOURISM] Turismo dopo la scoperta dei Castelli.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Metanoia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I Luoghi Santi forniscono [ICON_CULTURE] Cultura pari al loro bonus per la posizione. Le Fattorie forniscono un bonus alla [ICON_FAITH] Fede per la vicinanza agli Ippodromi e ai Luoghi Santi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sejong Daewang, Sejong il Grande, monarca di Joseon, dalla tua penna sono scaturiti editti che hanno dato forma al corso della storia. Sotto le tue direttive è sorta una nuova società, un nuovo modo di essere. Che il tuo popolo viva in armonia seguendo il tuo esempio, che la tua erudizione e saggezza conducano la Corea verso il suo destino.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Re Ludovico, ti chiamano pazzo, ma la tua è la pazzia dei sogni, della poesia e delle fiabe. Hai immaginato un mondo diverso, un regno incantato là dove tutto era normale e noioso. Oh, Re Cigno, il mondo ha bisogno dei tuoi castelli e dei tuoi cavalieri, delle tue montagne piene di draghi e di grotte magiche. Torna a portarci nuovi sogni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Imperatrice Teodora, sei assurta dal nulla fino a governare la discendenza di Roma! Con il tuo ingegno e la tua bellezza hai affascinato il popolo di Costantinopoli e hai posto la tua mano sulla grande ruota del potere. In un tempo di lotta e divisioni, mostra a tutti la via con il tuo saggio consiglio e imprimi il tuo sigillo splendente sulla terra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>世宗大王</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ルートヴィヒ2世</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>テオドラ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ハングル</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>新しい時代の最初の技術が完成すると、毎ターンの [ICON_SCIENCE] 科学力の2倍の [ICON_CULTURE] 文化力を受け取る。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>白鳥王</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>未完成のものも含めて、遺産が隣接するすべての区域に [ICON_CULTURE] 文化力+2をもたらす。この [ICON_CULTURE] 文化力は都市の産出量に表示される。「城」の発見後は、 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化力をもたらすすべての区域が [ICON_TOURISM] 観光力を産出する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>メタノイア</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>聖地が隣接ボーナスに等しい [ICON_CULTURE] 文化力をもたらす。農場がヒッポドロームと聖地に [ICON_FAITH] 信仰力の隣接ボーナスをもたらす。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>世宗大王、李氏朝鮮の支配者よ、貴方の筆が紡いだ布告は、歴史の流れを形作る。新たな社会、新たな生き方、すべては貴方の差配のとおり。範を示して民の暮らしに安寧をもたらし、叡智と知識によって韓国を栄光へと導きたまえ。 </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ルートヴィヒ2世、夢と詩とおとぎ話に情熱を傾け、狂王と呼ばれし者よ。世界の在り方を変えられると夢想した貴方は、退屈で平凡と思われていた世界に魔法の王国を造れると信じた。白鳥の王よ、世界は貴方の城と騎士、ドラゴンが住まう山と神秘の洞窟を必要としている。今一度その姿を現し、我らに新たな夢を与えたまえ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>テオドラ皇后、名も無き身から、半身を失いしローマ帝国の支配者となりし者よ！ 貴方はその機知と美貌によってコンスタンティノープルの民を魅了し、権力という巨大な車輪を御するまでになった。衝突と分断の時代、賢き言葉をもって万人を導き、この地に貴方の紋章を輝かせたまえ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세종대왕</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>루트비히 2세</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>테오도라</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>한글</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>새로운 시대에 첫 번째 기술을 완료하면 턴당 [ICON_SCIENCE] 과학의 2배에 해당하는 [ICON_CULTURE] 문화를 받습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>백조의 왕</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>불가사의가 인접 특수지구마다 [ICON_CULTURE] 문화 +2를 얻습니다(완성되지 않은 경우 포함). 이 [ICON_CULTURE] 문화는 도시 생산량에 표시됩니다. 모든 [ICON_CULTURE] 문화 인접 지역은 성을 발견한 후 [ICON_TOURISM] 관광을 제공합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>메타노이아</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>성지가 인접 보너스에 해당하는 [ICON_CULTURE] 문화를 제공합니다. 농장이 인접한 히포드롬과 성지에 [ICON_FAITH] 신앙을 제공합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위대한 조선의 지배자 세종대왕이시여, 당신의 붓끝에서 나온 반포문은 역사의 향방을 바꾸었습니다. 새로운 사회, 새로운 존재 방식을 지도할 이는 오직 당신뿐입니다. 타의 모범이 되어 백성이 화목하게 살게 하시고, 당신의 지혜와 지식으로 한국을 위대한 운명으로 이끄십시오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>루트비히 왕이시여, 사람들은 당신이 미쳤다고 하지만, 당신의 광기는 꿈의 광기이자 시와 동화의 광기입니다. 당신은 다른 세상, 우리가 모든 것이 지루하고 평범해 보이는 마법의 왕국을 건설할 수 있다고 상상했습니다. 백조의 왕이시여, 세상에는 당신의 성과 기사, 용이 도사리고 있는 산과 신비한 동굴이 필요했습니다. 다시 오셔서 저희에게 새 꿈을 주십시오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>테오도라 황후시여, 당신은 빈손으로 시작하여 동로마를 지배하는 인물이 되셨습니다! 당신은 재치와 아름다움으로 콘스탄티노플 사람들을 사로잡았고, 권력의 거대한 바퀴에 손을 얹었습니다. 갈등과 분열의 시기에 모두를 당신의 조언으로 인도하고 대지에 당신의 빛나는 인장을 찍으십시오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sejong|Sejonga|Sejongowi|Sejonga|Sejongiem|Sejongu</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Ludwik II|Ludwika II|Ludwikowi II|Ludwika II|Ludwikiem II|Ludwiku II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Teodora|Teodory|Teodorze|Teodorę|Teodorą|Teodorze</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Hangul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po opracowaniu pierwszej technologii z nowej epoki otrzymujesz [ICON_CULTURE] kulturę, której ilość równa się twojej podwojonej [ICON_SCIENCE] nauce na turę.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Bajkowy Król</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Cuda – nawet nieukończone – zapewniają każdej sąsiadującej dzielnicy +2 do [ICON_CULTURE] kultury. [ICON_CULTURE] Kultura ta jest widoczna w dochodach miasta. Wszystkie premie za sąsiedztwo do [ICON_CULTURE] kultury zapewniają [ICON_TOURISM] turystykę po odkryciu zamków.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Metanoia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dzielnice świątynne zapewniają [ICON_CULTURE] kulturę, której ilość odpowiada ich premii za sąsiedztwo. Farmy zapewniają [ICON_FAITH] wiarę za sąsiedztwo hipodromom i dzielnicom świątynnym.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sejongu Wielki, władco królestwa Joseon, twoje pióro kreśli proklamacje, które kształtują bieg historii. Nowe społeczeństwo, nowy sposób bycia jest twoim dziełem. Niech twój lud żyje harmonijnie, biorąc z ciebie przykład, a twoja mądrość i wiedza niech poprowadzą Koreę ku jej przeznaczeniu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Królu Ludwiku, zwą cię Szalonym, ale twoje szaleństwo to szaleństwo marzeń, poezji i baśni. Wyobrażałeś sobie, że świat może być inny, że możemy zbudować zaczarowane królestwo tam, gdzie wszystko wydaje się nudne i przyziemne. O Bajkowy Królu, świat potrzebuje twoich zamków i rycerzy, twoich gór ze smokami i mistycznych grot. Wróć i daj nam nowe marzenia.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Cesarzowo Teodoro, z nikogo stałaś się władczynią pozostałości Rzymu! Sprytem i pięknem oczarowałaś lud Konstantynopola i chwyciłaś stery władzy. W czasach naznaczonych sporami i podziałami niech wszyscy kierują się twoimi radami i zjednoczą się pod twą złotą pieczęcią.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Седжон|Седжона|Седжону|Седжона|Седжоном|Седжоне</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Людвиг II|Людвига II|Людвигу II|Людвига II|Людвигом II|Людвиге II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Феодора|Феодоры|Феодоре|Феодору|Феодорой|Феодоре</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Хангыль</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Дает [ICON_CULTURE] культуру в объеме 200% [ICON_SCIENCE] науки за ход после открытия вашей первой технологии в новой эпохе.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Король-лебедь</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Чудеса, даже не достроенные, получают +2 к [ICON_CULTURE] культуре за каждый район по соседству. Эта [ICON_CULTURE] культура отображается в доходах города. После открытия замков все бонусы [ICON_CULTURE] культуры за соседство также дают [ICON_TOURISM] туризм.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Метанойя</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Святыни дают [ICON_CULTURE] культуру, в количестве, равном бонусу за соседство. Фермы дают [ICON_FAITH] веру за соседство с ипподромами и святынями.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Великий Седжон-тэван, правитель Чосона! Твоим пером начертаны указы, которые определят ход истории. Ты создашь новое общество и навсегда изменишь страну. Пусть народ, как и ты, живет в гармонии, а твои знания и мудрость ведут Корею к предначертанной ей судьбе.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Король Людвиг! Тебя прозвали безумным лишь за то, что ты поверил в сказку и возжелал превратить мир скуки и обыденности в волшебное королевство. Людям нужны твои замки и рыцари, таинственные пещеры и горы, в которых живут драконы. Смело следуй за мечтами, Лебединый король!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Императрица Феодора, ты поднялась из низов и обрела власть над обломками Римской империи. Твои ум и красота покорили народ Константинополя, и они передали бразды правления в твои руки. Пусть же народ услышит твои мудрые слова, чтобы преодолеть эпоху войн и раздоров.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>世宗大王</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>路德维希二世</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>狄奥多拉</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>谚文</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>解锁新时代的首项科技时，获得两倍于每回合 [ICON_SCIENCE] 科技值收益的 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>童话国王</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>奇观（即使未建成）从每个相邻区域处获得+2 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。这个 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值显示在城市产出中。解锁“城堡”之后，所有文化 [ICON_CULTURE] 相邻加成将提供 [ICON_TOURISM] 旅游业绩。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>悔改</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>圣地提供等于其相邻加成的 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。农场可以为跑马场和圣地提供+1的信仰 [ICON_FAITH] 相邻加成。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>世宗大王，朝鲜最高统治者，你创造的训民正音塑造了历史进程。一个全新的社会、一种全新的生活方式，皆由你亲自指导。让人民以你为榜样和谐生活，让你的智慧和知识引领朝鲜踏上自己的命运旅程。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>路德维希国王，世人笑你太疯癫，而你的疯癫属于梦想、诗歌和童话。这世界显得乏味而无聊，你憧憬着它换上新颜，所以才要建立一个魔法王国。童话国王啊，世界需要你的城堡和骑士，巨龙盘踞的高山和神秘莫测的洞穴。再次君临吧，赋予我们新的梦想。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>狄奥多拉皇后，你来自社会底层，却一跃成为罗马残余势力的统治者。你用智慧和美貌征服了君士坦丁堡的人民，让自己的双手牢牢紧握权力巨轮。在纷争与分裂的时代中，愿天下人都听从你的旨意，在土地上印下你光辉的印记。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Sejong</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Luis II</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Teodora</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Hangul</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Al completar la primera Tecnología de una nueva época, recibe el doble de la Ciencia [ICON_SCIENCE] por turno como Cultura [ICON_CULTURE].</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Rey Cisne</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Las maravillas, incluso cuando no estén terminadas, reciben +2 a Cultura [ICON_CULTURE] por cada distrito adyacente. Esta Cultura [ICON_CULTURE] se muestra en el rendimiento de la ciudad. Todas las adyacencias de Cultura [ICON_CULTURE] otorgan Turismo [ICON_TOURISM] tras descubrir los Castillos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Metanoia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los Lugares sagrados otorgan Cultura [ICON_CULTURE] equivalente a su bonificación de adyacencia. Las Granjas otorgan una bonificación de Fe [ICON_FAITH] por adyacencia a los Hipódromos y Lugares sagrados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Sejong Daewang, Sejong el Grande, gobernante de Chosón, de tu pluma brotan proclamas que dan forma al curso de la historia. Una nueva sociedad, una nueva forma de ser son tuyas para que las dirijas. Deja que el pueblo viva en armonía con tu ejemplo y que tu sabiduría y conocimiento guíen a Corea hacia su destino.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Rey Luis: te llaman loco, pero tu locura es la locura de los sueños, de la poesía y de los cuentos de hadas. Tú imaginaste que el mundo podría ser de otra manera, que podríamos construir un reino encantado en un lugar donde todo parecía tedioso y mundano. Oh, Rey Cisne, el mundo necesita tus castillos y caballeros, tus montañas plagadas de dragones y tus grutas místicas. Ven otra vez y danos nuevos sueños.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Emperatriz Teodora, vienes de la nada para gobernar los restos de Roma! Con tu ingenio y belleza has cautivado al pueblo de Constantinopla y has puesto la mano sobre el gran timón del poder. En un tiempo de lucha y división, deja que tus consejos guíen a todos y pon tu sello resplandeciente sobre la tierra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>世宗</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>路德維希二世</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>狄奧多拉</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>諺文</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>當新時代的首個科技研發完成後，獲得兩倍于每回合 [ICON_SCIENCE] 科技值收益的 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>天鵝之王</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>無論完成與否，奇觀都能為相鄰的區域提供+2 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。此 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值會顯示於城市收益上。所有 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值相鄰加成，都會在發現「城堡」後提供 [ICON_TOURISM] 旅遊業績。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>悔改</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>聖地提供等同於其相鄰加成的 [ICON_CULTURE] 文化值。農場能對競馬場和聖地提供 [ICON_FAITH] 信仰值相鄰加成。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>世宗大王啊，朝鮮的統治者，你的妙筆寫下無數詔令，形塑出歷史的走向。如今有新的社會和新的生活方式等著你去指揮。讓你的人民以你為榜樣和諧地生活，並讓你的智慧與知識引導朝鮮走向它的宿命。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>路德維希二世，世人稱你為狂人，但你的狂熱來自對夢想之狂熱，對詩歌及童話故事之追求。你曾想像這世界可以是其他模樣，並且相信我們能在看似無聊乏味的世界中建造充滿魔幻的國度。喔，天鵝之王啊，這世界需要你的城堡與騎士，你那有巨龍盤據的高山與神祕的岩洞。再來一次，為我們帶來嶄新的夢想吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>狄奧多拉皇后，你出身平凡，最後登上大位，統治著殘餘的羅馬帝國！靠著你的機智與美貌，你俘虜了君士坦丁堡的人民，並將巨大的權力掌握在手中。在充滿衝突與分裂的時局之中，讓你的建言引導一切，為大地蓋上你閃亮的徽印吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>