<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- Lincoln-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_NAME">
			<Text>Abraham Lincoln</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LINCOLN_NAME">
			<Text>Emancipation Proclamation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LINCOLN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Industrial Zones give +2 [ICON_Amenities] Amenities. Receive a free Melee unit after constructing Industrial Zones and their buildings. The free unit does not require resources when created or to maintain and receives +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LINCOLN_EXPANSION_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Industrial Zones give +2 [ICON_Amenities] Amenities and +3 Loyalty per turn but your Plantations give -2 Loyalty per turn. Receive a free Melee unit after constructing Industrial Zones and their buildings. The free unit does not require resources when created or to maintain and receives +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN">
			<Text>Abraham Lincoln, you rose to the challenge as your country tore itself asunder. Seize the power of a new, younger world, one built on rail and steam, on progress and liberty, and break apart the chains of bondage. Great Emancipator, in this new time of strife and division, the time has come to unite your people once again. Lead your people to freedom and liberty, and end forever the shackles of the past.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Nzinga Mbande-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_NAME">
			<Text>Nzinga Mbande</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_NAME">
			<Text>Queen of Ndongo and Matamba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Cities receive +10% Yields if on the same continent as your [ICON_Capital] Capital (Including your  [ICON_Capital] Capital), -15% if on another continent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE">
			<Text>Nzinga Mbande, queen of Ndongo and Matamba, warlord of the Imbangala, you know too well that power is not granted, but must be made anew in each instant. Beware those who would seize your lands and your people for their own ends. Strike back against those who would conspire against you, and take what is yours, if not by right, then by grand vision.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Saladin Alt-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_SALADIN_ORIGINAL_NAME">
			<Text>Saladin (Vizier)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_NAME">
			<Text>Saladin (Sultan)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_NAME">
			<Text>The Victorious</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+100% Flanking and Support Bonus to all Combat and Religious units.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
