<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_TITLE">
			<Text>Abraham Lincoln</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_QUOTE">
			<Text>While man exists, it is his duty to improve not only his own condition, but to assist in ameliorating mankind; I am for those means which will give the greatest good to the greatest number.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>One of the most recognizable faces in US history, Abraham Lincoln was President for only four years, but during which time he abolished slavery (an act that was rather late in comparison with the USA’s European contemporaries), successfully waged the Civil War, and catapulted the United States into the industrial age.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Lincoln came from modest beginnings in the Midwest. His family were poor landowners who were caught between the two major struggles of the day: the push westward into indigenous territory, and the tension between enslaving farmers (where wealth tended to be consolidated into larger landownings) and those who worked their own fields. The Lincolns were pushed up and north into Indiana, where they engaged in woodworking and farming. Times were hard – Lincoln’s mother died when he was a small boy, and Lincoln became mostly self-taught. Upon his return from serving in the militia against the Sauk, Lincoln studied law and began pursuing politics in earnest.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Lincoln’s early political career was with the Whigs, a party that had coalesced – in America, at least – against executive power, an artifact of its original anti-monarchical status. In the US, this meant combating the potential for political figures such as Andrew Jackson to establish sweeping executive powers. The US was changing, however, and the dominant divisions were no longer between wealthy plantation owners in Virginia (e.g., Washington or Jefferson) against thrifty and philosophically-minded New Englanders (e.g., Franklin or Adams), but as an industrial capital in the North against a South moving towards industrial agriculture, powered by slave labor. As the Whigs transformed into the Republican party, aligning with Northern industrial interests against the South, Lincoln became a leading voice. Lincoln’s views called for moderation on the issue of slavery (as awful as that sounds today, it was progressive for the time), international economic protectionism, and support for domestic industry – all policies that favored free capital (within the country, at least, and amongst white men), industrialization and the wealth of industrialists.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>These white Southern landowners in the South depended upon slavery to keep pace with international industrial, agricultural production, and global trade. Still, it was an increasingly untenable (and had always been an abhorrent) practice. Lincoln made no disguise of his opposition to slavery, although he saw containment, and not eradication, as the path forward. But even this attempt at moderation was too far for Southern states, who interpreted his election as a sign that their power within the Union was irrevocably waning and that the institution of slavery, and thus their economic base, might be at an end. Thus, directly after his election, the Confederacy declared its separation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Lincoln was a debater and, as such, was criticized for underestimating the gravity of the situation and not taking early action, but his penchant for words and caution was to pay off later. In the Civil War, the South had the advantage of home territory and a well-educated elite to produce generals and strategists, but lagged behind the North in nearly every other factor. As much of the labor force in the South were enslaved and, as such, would be hard-pressed to make fight for their own continued enslavement, the South had to use propaganda campaigns to bring poor landless whites to fight. Further, Southern factories and industry lagged behind the North. And finally, the South lacked existing international support.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>But there was a path to victory, however unlikely this seemed. The politics of racial resentment remained, and Lincoln underestimated the pro-slavery sentiment even in states that did not secede (e.g., Maryland) – riots and saboteurs abounded there. More ominous, there were many international powers that would like to see the South remain a largely agricultural producer of raw materials to fuel their own industry, especially given Lincoln’s penchant for foreign tariffs and protecting American trade. Lincoln intercepted envoys from the Confederacy to England, but in a wise move, gave leniency, thus avoiding an international incident.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Things could have gone differently: a foreign power could have intervened. A mass slave uprising could have destroyed the Confederacy before it began. A mass pro-slavery uprising could have sabotaged the United States’ industry. But none of these things happened, and the industrial machine of the North inexorably destroyed the Confederacy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>This theme of industrialism is key here. At home, Lincoln was known for establishing a banking administration and a department of agriculture, both issues to bring the growing nation under centralized control. But when we think of Lincoln’s time, we think of growing factories, the rise of European immigration to the US, the growth of railroads. And also, the movement of these industrial forces against the lands to the west – Lincoln, especially given his background, had no soft spot in his heart for the indigenous people of the continent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>Lincoln’s victory and the reforms made to the South in the wake of the war were bound to cause resentment. He was assassinated in Washington DC by John Wilkes Booth in 1865, just after his re-election and only a few days after the end of the war. Booth believed such an assassination would lead to the war’s continuance, but this was not the case. Lincoln was succeeded by Andrew Johnson, a particularly inept leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Abraham Lincoln wants to utilize industrialization to prevent disharmony in his civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_ABRAHAM_LINCOLN_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>A choice of government is important for Abraham Lincoln with the Founding Fathers’ ability that provides additional Wildcard slots and Diplomatic Favor.  He also wants to research Apprenticeship and build Industrial Zones in all his cities to receive free melee units. Lincoln should avoid Irrigation and Plantations, so he doesn’t receive their malus. Late in the game the P-51 Mustang and Film Studio arrive for the final push towards victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_TITLE">
			<Text>Nzinga Mbande</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_QUOTE">
			<Text>Chance all, and see where destiny leads.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>An important figure in the Angolan independence movement and in the early history of colonialism in Africa, Nzinga Mbande struggled to establish a voice for herself (and a kingdom to rule), bouncing between various kingdoms and playing the European powers off of each other as she did so.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Portuguese reached Kongo in the 1480s. What they found there was the Kingdom of Kongo, an elective monarchy that had been in power since the 1300s. Missionaries had established schools and developed a syncretic religious practice in Kongo and, within a decade, had baptized the king. Slavery was a more complicated matter. The Kongolese had long practiced slavery, bringing subjects into the capital from wars and raids and forcing them to settle and work. When the Portuguese established their plantations on Sao Tome, Kongo made an exclusive trade agreement to supply the island with captives for enslaved labor. Over time, Kongo and Portugal forged an uneasy alliance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The problem was that the Portuguese did not respect Kongo’s monopoly on the slave trade, and Afonso – Mvemba a Nzinga - urged the deal’s end. It should be noted that Mvemba was not advocating an end to slavery or protesting imperial aggression but merely that the Portuguese did not adhere to the terms of their agreement. This issue leads Portugal to set up camps in neighboring kingdoms, both as trading camps as well as raiding camps.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>A generation later, areas on Kongo’s frontier that were once targeted by slavers were now potential partners. Ndongo was one of these. In 1590, it was in a state of war against the Portuguese and their Kongolese allies, as well as suffering attacks from a particularly fierce band of mercenaries known as the Imbangala. As this war started going poorly, a noble staged a coup d’etat, ousting many members of the royal court, including Nzinga, who flees to the nearby kingdom of Matamba. But the new leader of Ndongo found a need for her political acumen and connections, and drafted her to negotiate with the Portuguese.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Here is where Nzinga shone. She deliberately defied Portuguese norms. Refusing to take the allotted submissive role in negotiations, she dressed in local finery, presenting herself as a queen, not a subject. When the Portuguese sought to have her sit on the ground, she had her attendant become her chair. She held out on the subject of baptism, using it as an offer in negotiations. In the end, she arrived at a peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>But this peace didn’t last. The Imbangala desired more territory and acted in defiance of both the Portuguese and Ndongo, keeping up the war. As the crisis deepened at home, the king of Ndongo died, and Nzinga, with her wide-ranging net of political and strategic allies, sought control. The Portuguese, remembering her fire, balked at recognizing her and demanded that she pay obeisance to their own selection of a puppet-king. She refused and escaped to join the rebels – those same Imbangala. She married into that group and rebuilt her forces after the highly militaristic fashion of her new people. With this, she swept over the area, taking Matamba for her own, though not all of Ndongo. From this vantage point, she established independent relations with Dutch traders, with whom she exchanged slaves as a financial lifeline into resistance, and built an alliance with the Dutch and Kongolese against the Portuguese.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>War dragged on. The Dutch were forced out by the Portuguese, but at the same time, Portugal entered into a war with Spain. In 1656, after years of fighting, the two foes agreed on a peace treaty – Portugal gained a good deal of the coast, while Nzinga gained her monopoly over the slave trade. It was many years until the Europeans again sought to breach the interior.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>She is remembered now as a force against the Portuguese, especially in depictions of the Angolan Civil War.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Staying on her home continent is the key to success with Nzinga Mbande.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_NZINGA_MBANDE_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Nzinga Mbande’s Kongo wants to be the preeminent power on her home continent. Her additional yields on her home combined with the Nkisi ability set her up well for a Culture Victory. The Ngao Mbeba helps her conquer any civilization that enters her home continent. The Mbanza will help her cities grow large and prosperous.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SALADIN_TITLE">
			<Text>Saladin (Vizier)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_TITLE">
			<Text>Saladin (Sultan)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_QUOTE">
			<Text>When Allah decides a matter, it is done.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Defeating opponents with either military or Religion is at the heart of playing with Sultan Saladin.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SALADIN_ALT_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Being guaranteed a Great Prophet allows Sultan Saladin a chance to build up his military until his free Great Prophet arrives. After the Great Prophet is received, go forth spreading Arabia’s Religion and military across the map. The Mamluk will be an asset in conquering faraway civilizations with its ability to heal every turn. The Madrasa will help you unlock stronger military units while also allowing the purchase of more Apostles. Arabia under the Sultan Saladin’s leadership is great for either Domination or Religious Victories.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_ANA_NZINGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>In the late 1500s, the lord of Zazzau, a city-state in northern Nigeria, began to notice something about his daughter. She was preternaturally bold and assertive, and held her kitchen knife not like a tool, but like a weapon of war. This was Amina, of the Hausa, and when her father and brother both died, she took control of Zazzau and expanded it into a major force in the region. Zazzau was one of a series of states at the far western edge of Saharan trade routes, sending raw resources – and, at the time, enslaved people – across the desert into the Middle East, and as the region had seen the rise and fall of multiple related powers – Ghana, Mali, Songhai, among others, the area was constantly on the verge new wars and conquests. Amina, upon taking the throne, called upon her followers to ‘sharpen their weapons’ and moved from city to city, first sacking the place, and then erecting new fortifications to consolidate her rule. She was also unapologetic about being a female leader in a Muslim society. She allegedly took a lover in each town she captured for one night, and then had the (un?)fortunate man executed the next morning. This perhaps was not only a display of her capacity for military conquest, but also a way to ensure that patriarchal systems of dynastic succession would never threaten her right to rule. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_ANA_NZINGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Her rule was the height of women’s power in Hausaland, which in years afterward experienced a gradual decline. She remains a folk hero, though, and is fondly remembered by people in the region – at least, those who lived to tell the tale. </Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
