<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Júlio César</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Vim, vi, venci.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Modelo a ser seguido por todos os aspirantes a ditadores que viriam depois, Júlio César foi um militar que cultivava o apoio da população simples e das forças armadas como uma via para o poder contra a oligarquia estabelecida. Sua ascensão marcou o fim da República Romana e o início do Império.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A gente Júlia não era do nível das outras famílias patrícias, apesar de ter supostamente se originado da deusa Vênus. Eles haviam sido alçados à categoria de nobres (isto é, patrícios, em oposição à plebe) em um passado relativamente distante, mas eram de menor importância na república romana. A história de Júlio César começa quando ele se torna chefe da família em 85 a.C. e é quase que imediatamente alvejado pelo novo vencedor de uma sangrenta guerra civil entre o povo de César, Caio Mário e Lúcio Sula. César perdeu o pouco de herança que sua família ainda tinha e sua capacidade de servir como sacerdote de Júpiter. De relativamente poucas posses, César se alistou no exército, uma decisão que depois se provaria dramática.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Em certo episódio no início de sua carreira, César foi capturado por piratas no Mar Egeu. Ele fez amizade com os homens e os encorajou a exigir mais dinheiro do que ele valia, falando em tom de brincadeira que, quando livre, ele os rastrearia e os destruiria. Eles acataram seu conselho... E ao final, ele levou imediatamente a cabo a ameaça que havia feito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>No começo de sua carreira, César era visto como um opositor da corrupção no Senado e favorecido pelos militares. Conforme ele foi subindo nas fileiras, ganhando um consulado em 59 a.C. e se tornando membro do "triunvirato", uma aliança entre César e dois poderosos aliados, ele recebeu o apoio da população comum, promovendo a redistribuição forçada de terras e ameaçando a nobreza com seus soldados quando conflitos emergiam. Isso o fez criar inimigos, e assim ele buscou uma governadoria nas regiões fragmentadas da Gália para se proteger de qualquer retaliação. Essa jogada também seria determinante para seu futuro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A guerra gerava oportunidades. César afastou implacavelmente as forças gaulesas, incluindo Ambiórix, na Guerra Gálica. Mas, enquanto estava fora, os opositores de César enfraqueciam ativamente o apoio que tinha em sua terra, citando irregularidades nas eleições consulares. Pompeu, antes aliado de César, tomou todo o controle para si, com os senadores clamando para que ambos largassem as armas e assim restabelecessem a ordem jurídica. Mas nenhum deles cedeu. E pior, César começou a marchar suas legiões vitoriosas na Gália na direção de Roma.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>E nesse trajeto existia o rio Rubicão. Exércitos mobilizados eram proibidos de entrar em Roma, de forma que cruzar o grande rio representava um sinal de hostilidade. César parou por um instante antes de declarar que "alea icata est": a sorte foi lançada. Depois cruzou o rio e alterou os rumos da história. Apesar da eclosão de uma guerra civil, o planejamento militar de César foi tal que ele superou as estratégias de seu opositor Pompeu e o perseguiu para além da Itália e depois pela Espanha e Grécia. Ao voltar para Roma, César foi nomeado ditador. Uma medida que mais tarde outros ditadores iriam reproduzir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Consolidar seu poder foi sua próxima ação. Com um misto de astúcia e coação, César intimidou o Senado e intercedeu, como todos sabem, por Cleópatra no Egito (que por sua vez se tornou sua amante). Embora sua personalidade pública favorecesse os plebeus, ele restringiu o poder dos não nobres, tanto na forma das guildas de artesãos quanto nas reformas jurídicas. Em respeito à expansão romana, César permitiu algum grau de descentralização, estendendo direitos jurídicos para além da Itália e permitindo que as cidades locais tivessem mais liberdade para governar de acordo com seus desígnios. Sua ditadura dependia tanto da intimidação informal (ele simplesmente rejeitou várias medidas feitas pelo Senado) quanto dos novos poderes jurídicos a ele concedidos pelo próprio Senado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nesse ponto, o poder do Senado pareceu estar gravemente abalado. Não era à toa que seus inimigos conspiravam contra ele. E assim o fizeram. Em uma assembleia do Senado em que César deveria discursar, ele foi esfaqueado 23 vezes, e mais notoriamente pelo seu suposto amigo, Brutus. Embora conheçamos a frase "et tu, brute" por causa de Shakespeare, suas últimas palavras foram "kai su, teknon" (você também, filho?) em grego.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Depois disso, o pais caiu em desordem. As massas ainda apoiavam César, e agora seu general, Antônio, enquanto que os futuros líderes, Brutus e Cássio, foram forçados a fugir. Ao mesmo tempo, o filho adotivo de César, Otaviano, reivindicou o direito de governar começando uma guerra que parecia ser de todos contra todos. Os assassinos foram caçados e mortos, assim como Antônio, que havia buscado refúgio com Cleópatra. Otaviano, então, se tornou Augusto César.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O legado de César reforçou o poder do populismo combinado com as forças militares e a audácia da ambição. Pretensos imperadores, como Napoleão e Bolívar, inspiraram-se em César, e monarquias que se autoproclamavam "Kaiser, "Czar" ou "Qaisar" pegaram a ideia de seus nomes do ditador Romano.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Júlio César deseja conquistar todos os hexágonos do mapa, eliminando tanto os bárbaros quanto as civilizações que se opuserem a ele.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Desbloquear as Legiões no Trabalho em Ferro é fundamental para se obter a vitória, tendo em vista sua [ICON_Strength] força de combate aumentada. Então use as Legiões para dispersar os Acampamentos Bárbaros e conquistar as cidades adversárias. O [ICON_Gold] ouro adicional de Júlio César nessas conquistas ajudará a impulsioná-lo a obter um império e exército maiores. O [ICON_Gold] ouro adicional é gerado pela sua habilidade "Todos os Caminhos Levam a Roma", de forma que você também poderá apaziguar as massas com seus Banhos que concedem [Icon_amenities] serviços adicionais. Seu poderio militar é ideal para uma Vitória por Dominação.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Guerra Gálica</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Odeia bárbaros. Gosta de civilizações que eliminam postos avançados bárbaros. Não gosta de civilizações que ignoram postos avançados bárbaros.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Meu nome é César, destruidor de conspirações tanto nas florestas alpinas quanto no Senado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quanta ambição. Você quer conquistar minhas terras antes que eu ataque as suas. Eu aprovo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A sorte foi lançada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Um exército vitorioso é aquele liderado por um vencedor.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O perigo está à sua porta, e você não faz nada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Tu quoque? Então caia, César.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Já tenho Otaviano, Antônio e meu caro Brutus como amigos. E agora, você!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Eu sempre sei identificar uma amizade traiçoeira. Sempre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Roma também tem seus charmes. Faça amizade conosco.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Serei um amigo tão fiel para você quanto meu caro Brutus é para mim.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Você tem uma aparência esguia e voraz. Esse tipo de gente não é confiável.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nós mostraremos Roma a eles como fizemos com Vercingetórix!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Não existem presentes grátis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os presentes de Roma: pão, azeitonas, queijos, garo. Todos eles, sem falar no meu favor, ajudam a garantir uma longa vida.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Espero que suas palavras não sejam vazias. Eu lhe garanto que minhas ameaças não são.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sua aparência é pálida e voraz. Não vejo isso com bons olhos. (Denuncia você)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Todas as estradas levam a Roma, para o bem ou para o mal. Deseja conhecê-la?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Isto há de passar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Saudações de Roma! Estamos ávidos por conhecer outros faróis de civilização na imensidão deste mundo. Por que não me conta sobre a sua?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Dê ouvidos a mim.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nossos interesses se alinham como uma formação tartaruga. O que acha de formalizar essa aliança?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Até espadas se cansam de golpear.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Só haverá paz quando eu tiver o que é meu por direito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Esta guerra drena forças que seriam melhor empregadas contra outros.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nosso império abriga milhares de povos diferentes. O seu povo se sentirá em casa passando por nosso território.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Acha que deixaremos guerreiros bárbaros andarem livremente em nossas terras? Não, não deixaremos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Podemos fazer um acordo, como pessoas civilizadas, para deixar nossas tropas marcharem em paz a caminho de outras terras?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Fale abertamente. Suas tropas estão se dirigindo a Roma? Você ordenará o recuo e a paz, ou o avanço e o massacre?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Que assim seja.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Jules César</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Veni, vidi, vici.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Véritable modèle pour tous les dictateurs en herbe, Jules César était avant tout un homme d'armée, qui cultiva aussi bien le soutien du peuple que celui des forces militaires pour prendre le pouvoir face à l'oligarchie en place. Son essor marqua la fin de la République romaine et le commencement de l'Empire.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Pour une famille patricienne, les Iulii n'étaient guère influents, bien que descendants selon la légende de la déesse Vénus. Ils quittèrent la plèbe pour être élevés au rang de nobles à une époque relativement éloignée, mais jouèrent un rôle très limité dans la République romaine. L'histoire de Jules César commence lorsqu'il prend la tête de cette famille en l'an 85 av. J.-C., avant d'être presque immédiatement pris pour cible par le vainqueur d'une violente guerre civile entre ses proches, Caius Marius et Sylla. César perdit le maigre héritage de sa famille et la possibilité de servir en tant que prêtre de Jupiter. N'ayant presque aucune possession, il s'engagea donc dans l'armée, une décision qui devait bien vite entrer dans l'histoire.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Dans l'un des premiers épisodes marquants de sa carrière militaire, César fut fait prisonnier par des pirates sur la mer Égée. Il se lia d'amitié avec les hommes et les encouragea à réclamer plus d'argent pour sa libération qu'il n'en valait vraiment, en plaisantant qu'une fois libre, il les retrouverait et les détruirait. Les pirates suivirent son conseil... et César mit sa menace à exécution.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Dans les premiers temps de sa carrière, César se fit remarquer en s'opposant à la corruption des membres du Sénat et en gagnant les faveurs de l'armée. À mesure qu'il s'élevait dans la hiérarchie, jusqu'à devenir consul en 59 av. J.-C. et membre du triumvirat, un accord le liant à deux puissants alliés, César s'attira les bonnes grâces du peuple, poussant pour la redistribution des terres et menaçant la noblesse de ses soldats lorsque des conflits pointaient. Il se créa ainsi bien des inimitiés, et se fit nommer gouverneur des régions indisciplinées de la Gaule dans le simple but de se mettre à l'abri des représailles. Cette décision, elle aussi, allait façonner son avenir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Avec les hostilités vinrent les opportunités. Tout au long de la guerre des Gaules, César fut sans pitié contre les forces gauloises, et notamment celles d'Ambiorix. Mais pendant son absence de Rome, ses adversaires redoublèrent d'efforts pour saper son soutien, citant des irrégularités dans son élection au poste de consul. Pompée, ancien allié de César, prit le pouvoir, et les sénateurs supplièrent les deux hommes de déposer les armes afin de rétablir l'ordre. Aucun n'accepta, et pire encore, César fit prendre le chemin du retour à ses légions victorieuses.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>César et ses troupes finirent par arriver au Rubicon, fleuve séparant la Gaule du grand territoire romain, et qu'il était formellement interdit de franchir aux armées actives sous peine de terribles représailles du Sénat. César fit une courte pause, avant de déclarer : "Alea jacta est" – "Le sort en est jeté". Il franchit alors le fleuve symbolique et transforma ainsi le cours de l'histoire. Une guerre civile s'en suivit, mais César était si bien préparé qu'il déjoua tous les plans de son adversaire, Pompée, jusqu'à le chasser hors d'Italie, en Espagne et en Grèce. À son retour à Rome, César fut nommé dictateur, un geste qui devait inspirer tous les autocrates pour les siècles à venir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>César dut ensuite cimenter son pouvoir. Entre ruse et menace, il fit plier le Sénat et intervint en Égypte pour le compte de Cléopâtre, dont il devint l'amant. Si dans ses déclarations publiques, il semblait favoriser le petit peuple, il fit en sorte d'empêcher les non nobles d'accéder au pouvoir, aussi bien dans les corporations d'artisanat que par des réformes juridiques. Pour tenir compte de l'expansion de Rome, César autorisa un certain degré de décentralisation, élargissant les droits juridiques au-delà des frontières de l'Italie et offrant plus de libertés aux villes pour gouverner selon leur bon vouloir. Sa dictature s'appuyait à la fois sur des intimidations officieuses – il rejeta purement et simplement plusieurs décisions du Sénat – et sur l'acquisition d'un certain nombre de nouveaux pouvoirs.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le pouvoir du Sénat semblait particulièrement secoué, ce qui explique pourquoi ses adversaires cherchèrent à conspirer contre lui. C'est ainsi qu'à une rencontre politique lors de laquelle il devait s'exprimer, César fut poignardé 23 fois, notamment par celui qu'il pensait être son ami proche, Brutus. Si nous devons à Shakespeare l'expression "Et tu, Brute ?", en grec, ses derniers mots auraient été "Kaì sý, téknon" : "Toi aussi, mon fils ?".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Suite à sa mort, l'Empire sombra dans le chaos. La majorité populaire soutenait toujours César, et par extension son général, Marc Antoine, ce qui força Brutus et Cassius à prendre la fuite alors qu'ils se voyaient déjà à la tête de Rome. Dans le même temps, Auguste, fils adoptif de César, affirma que le pouvoir lui revenait de droit, ce qui déclencha une guerre de succession ouverte sans commune mesure. Les assassins furent traqués et exécutés, tout comme Marc Antoine, qui s'était réfugié auprès de Cléopâtre. Auguste, quant à lui, fut nommé empereur.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'héritage de César renforça le pouvoir du populisme associé à la force militaire, ainsi que l'audace de l'ambition. D'autres empereurs ou aspirants dictateurs, comme Napoléon et Bolivar, s'inspirèrent de sa vie, et les souverains se faisant appeler "Kaiser", "Tsar" ou "Qaisar" tirent d'ailleurs directement leur titre du nom de l'empereur romain.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Jules César veut conquérir toutes les cases de la carte, jusqu'à la dernière, en écrasant aussi bien les barbares que les civilisations adverses.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Débloquez les légions avec le travail du fer pour vous assurer la victoire grâce à leur [ICON_Strength] puissance de combat renforcée, et envoyez-les ensuite liquider les campements barbares et conquérir les villes adverses. Le bonus en [ICON_Gold] or reçu par Jules César pour ces prises l'aidera à développer plus rapidement son empire et son armée. Il pourra également obtenir de l'[ICON_GOLD] or supplémentaire grâce à sa compétence "Tous les chemins mènent à Rome", et apaiser les foules avec ses thermes, sources d'[Icon_amenities] activités additionnelles. La puissance de ses armées est idéale pour une victoire militaire.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Guerre des Gaules</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>A horreur des barbares. Apprécie les civilisations qui rasent leurs avant-postes. N'apprécie pas celles qui les laissent en paix.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Je suis César, destructeur de complots, aussi bien dans les forêts alpines qu'au Sénat.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Quelle ambition. Vous cherchez à conquérir mon empire avant que je ne m'attaque à vous. Je salue votre geste.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le sort en est jeté.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une armée victorieuse a toujours à sa tête un vainqueur.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le danger patiente, tapi devant votre porte, et vous, vous ne faites rien.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Tu quoque ? Tombe donc, César.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Parmi mes amis, je peux compter Auguste, Marc Antoine, mon si cher Brutus... et vous !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Je reconnais toujours la traîtrise quand je la vois. Toujours.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Rome sait aussi se montrer généreuse. Liez-vous donc d'amitié avec nous.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Mon amitié pour vous sera aussi indéfectible que celle que me porte mon cher Brutus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Vous avez l'air d'avoir l'estomac dans les talons. C'est la marque de quelqu'un de dangereux.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Nous devrions les faire défiler dans les rues de Rome, comme avec Vercingétorix !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un cadeau n'est jamais gratuit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les dons de Rome : du pain, des olives, du fromage et du garum. On dit qu'ils sont source de vitalité, tout comme mes bonnes grâces.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>J'espère que ce n'était pas des paroles en l'air, car pour ma part, mes menaces sont toujours sérieuses.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Je vous trouve la mine bien pâle et affamée. Je n'aime pas ça du tout. (Dénonciation)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Tous les chemins mènent à Rome, pour le meilleur ou pour le pire. Souhaitez-vous nous rendre visite ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Ça passera.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Salutations de Rome ! Nous sommes toujours heureux de découvrir d'autres lueurs civilisées. Et si vous nous parliez de vous ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Écoutez-moi, vous voulez bien ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Nos intérêts sont liés. Et si nous l'annoncions officiellement ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Même une épée se lasse de frapper.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Je n'accepterai la paix que lorsque j'aurai obtenu ce qui me revient de droit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Cette guerre sape une force qui serait plus utile ailleurs.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Notre empire regroupe des milliers de peuples différents. Le vôtre se sentira comme chez lui en traversant nos frontières.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Faut-il tolérer que des guerriers barbares piétinent ouvertement nos terres ? Non. Nous le tolérerons pas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Et si nous acceptions pacifiquement de laisser nos troupes traverser d'autres territoires ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Exprimez-vous clairement. Ces troupes sont-elles en route pour Rome ? Allez-vous leur ordonner de rentrer en paix, ou d'attaquer ?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Eh bien soit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Julius Cäsar</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ich kam, sah und siegte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Julius Cäsar, der Prototyp aller Diktatoren, war ein Feldherr, der die Unterstützung des Volkes und seiner Soldaten nutzte, um sich gegen eine etablierte Oligarchie den Weg an die Macht zu bahnen. Sein Aufstieg läutete das Ende der Römischen Republik und den Beginn des Prinzipats ein.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Obwohl ihre Ahnenlinie angeblich bis auf die Göttin Venus zurückging, waren die Julier ein sehr gewöhnliches Patriziergeschlecht. Sie waren schon vor einiger Zeit von den Plebs ins Patriziat aufgestiegen, besaßen jedoch keine große Macht in der Römischen Republik. Die Geschichte von Julius Cäsar begann, als er im Jahr 85 v. Chr. zum Familienoberhaupt und daraufhin zur Zielscheibe des frischen Siegers eines blutigen Bürgerkriegs zwischen Cäsars Verwandtem Gaius Marius und Lucius Sulla wurde. Cäsar verlor dabei den ohnehin schon geringen Besitz seiner Familie und das Recht, als Priester des Jupiter zu dienen. Da ihm so gut wie kein Besitz mehr blieb, ging Cäsar zum Militär – eine schicksalhafte Entscheidung.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>In einer Episode aus seiner frühen Militärlaufbahn wurde Cäsar in der Ägäis von Piraten gefangen genommen. Er schloss Freundschaft mit den Männern und ermutigte sie, deutlich mehr Geld für ihn zu verlangen als geplant. Er scherzte, wenn er wieder frei sei, würde er sie dann aufspüren und niederstrecken. Sie folgten seinem Rat... und er machte seinerseits ohne zu zögern seine Drohung wahr.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>In seiner frühen Karriere machte Cäsar sich einen Namen als Gegner senatorischer Korruption und Freund des Militärs. Als er im Rang aufstieg und im Jahr 59 v. Chr. als Konsul zusammen mit zwei mächtigen Verbündeten das erste "Triumvirat" bildete, sammelte er weitere Pluspunkte beim Volk, indem er Land umverteilen ließ und dem Adel bei aufkommenden Konflikten mit seinen Soldaten drohte. So machte er sich allerdings auch Feinde, weswegen er sich die Regentschaft über die kämpferischen Regionen Galliens sicherte, um sich vor Vergeltungsschlägen zu schützen. Auch dies sollte seine Zukunft prägen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Krieg eröffnet Möglichkeiten. Cäsar rückte im Gallischen Krieg unablässig gegen die Streitkräfte der gallischen Stämme vor – auch gegen König Ambiorix. Doch in seiner Abwesenheit untergruben Cäsars Gegner seine Unterstützung in der Heimat und wiesen auf Unregelmäßigkeiten bei seiner Wahl zum Konsul hin. Cäsars einstiger Verbündeter Pompeius übernahm die Macht und die Senatoren drängten beide Männer, die Waffen niederzulegen und wieder eine rechtliche Ordnung herzustellen. Keiner von beiden folgte ihrem Rat. Im Gegenteil, Cäsar ließ seine siegreichen Legionen aus Gallien abziehen und Richtung Rom marschieren.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sie erreichten den Fluss Rubikon. Einsatzbereite Heere waren in Rom verboten und den Fluss zu überqueren würde als Kriegserklärung betrachtet werden. Cäsar pausierte und erklärte dann: alea iacta est – der Würfel wurde geworfen (geläufiger: die Würfel sind gefallen). Er überquerte den Fluss und veränderte den Lauf der Geschichte. Es entbrannte ein Bürgerkrieg, aber dank seiner Militärstrategie gelang es Cäsar, seinen Gegner Pompeius auszumanövrieren und ihn aus Italien bis nach Spanien und Griechenland fortzujagen. Bei seiner Rückkehr nach Rom wurde Cäsar zum Diktator ernannt. Dies wurde zu einer Strategie, die von späteren Diktatoren nachgeahmt wurde.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sein nächster Schritt war die Konsolidierung der Macht. Mit einer Mischung aus Arglist und offenen Drohungen schüchterte Cäsar den Senat ein und intervenierte mit großem Aufsehen im Namen Kleopatras (die seine Geliebte wurde) in Ägypten. Nach außen hin gab sich Cäsar zwar als Mann des Volkes, doch schränkte er die Macht der Nichtadligen ein, sowohl in den Handwerksgilden als auch bei rechtlichen Reformen. Mit Rücksicht auf die Expansion Roms ließ er einen gewissen Grad an Dezentralisierung zu. Er dehnte Rechte über die Grenzen Italiens hinweg aus und gewährte Städten mehr Freiheit bei ihrer Verwaltung. Seine Diktatur beruhte auf informeller Einschüchterung (er setzte sich über mehrere Beschlüsse des Senats hinweg) ebenso wie auf neuen Rechten, die ihm vom Senat zugebilligt wurden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Macht des Senats war bedenklich ins Wanken geraten. Daher ist es nicht verwunderlich, dass viele seiner Gegner sich gegen ihn verschworen. Bei einer Senatssitzung, auf der auch Cäsar sprechen sollte, stach sein enger Vertrauter Brutus gleich 23 Mal auf ihn ein. Zwar heißt es bei Shakespeare "Auch du, Brutus?", doch Cäsars letzte überlieferte Worte waren griechisch: "kaì sý, téknon" (Auch du, mein Sohn?).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Danach verfiel das Reich in Tumult. Die Mehrheit des Volkes hielt zu Cäsars General Antonius, deshalb mussten die potenziellen Nachfolger Brutus und Cassius fliehen, anstatt die Macht zu übernehmen. Gleichzeitig pochte Cäsars Adoptivsohn Octavian auf sein Recht zu regieren, und so schien jeder gegen jeden Krieg zu führen. Die Attentäter wurden gejagt und zur Strecke gebracht und auch Antonius, der bei Kleopatra Zuflucht gesucht hatte, kam ums Leben. Aus Octavian wurde später Kaiser Augustus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Cäsars Vermächtnis stärkte den Einfluss von Populismus, verbunden mit militärischer Waffengewalt, ebenso wie die Macht von unbändigem Ehrgeiz. Herrscher wie Napoleon und Bolivar übernahmen inspiriert von Cäsar die Macht und Monarchen, die sich selbst "Kaiser", "Zar" oder "Qaisar" nannten, leiteten ihren Titel vom römischen Imperator ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Julius Cäsar will jedes Geländefeld auf der Karte erobern und sowohl die Barbaren als auch die gegnerischen Zivilisationen vernichten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Legionen bei der Eisenverarbeitung freizuschalten ist durch ihre erhöhte [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke der Schlüssel zum Sieg. Führt die Legionen dann weiter, um Barbarenlager aufzulösen und gegnerische Städte einzunehmen. Julius Cäsars zusätzliches [ICON_Gold] Gold für diese Eroberungen wird ihm ein großes Reich und eine große Armee verschaffen. Das zusätzliche [ICON_GOLD] Gold wird durch seine "Alle Wege führen nach Rom"-Fähigkeit generiert. Ihr könnt außerdem die Massen mit euren Bädern bei Laune halten, die weitere [Icon_amenities] Annehmlichkeiten bieten. Seine Militärmacht eignet sich am besten für einen Herrschaftssieg.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Gallischer Krieg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Hasst Barbaren. Mag Zivilisationen, die Barbaren-Außenposten ausräumen. Mag keine Zivilisationen, die Barbaren-Außenposten ignorieren.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ich bin Cäsar, Ersticker von Verschwörungen – ob in den Alpenwäldern oder im Senat.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ehrgeizig. Ihr wollt mich erobern, bevor ich gegen Euch ausrücke. Das gefällt mir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Würfel sind gefallen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine siegreiche Armee wird von einem Sieger angeführt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Gefahr steht direkt vor Eurer Tür und Ihr unternehmt nichts.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Tu quoque? So falle, Cäsar!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zu meinen Freunden zähle ich Octavian, Antonius und meinen guten Brutus. Und nun auch Euch!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ich kann einen verräterischen Freund immer erkennen. Immer.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Rom hat einiges zu bieten. Schließt Freundschaft mit uns.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ich werde Euch ein wahrer Freund sein, so wie mir mein guter Brutus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ihr seht mager und hungrig aus. Solche Leute sind gefährlich.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wir führen sie durch Rom wie schon Vercingetorix!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Geschenke sind niemals umsonst.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Gaben Roms – Brot, Oliven, Käse, Garum. So wie meine Gunst gewähren sie ein langes Leben.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ihr steht besser zu Eurem Wort. Ich für meinen Teil mache meine Drohungen wahr.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ihr seht blass und hungrig aus. Ich mag diesen Anblick nicht. (Denunziert Euch)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Alle Wege führen nach Rom, ob man will oder nicht. Seht Ihr es Euch an?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ich bin einverstanden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Grüße aus Rom! Wir hören immer gerne von anderen Lichtern der Zivilisation in der Wildnis. Erzählt Ihr mir von Eurem?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Hört mir zu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wie bei der Schildkrötenformation haben wir gemeinsame Interessen. Sollen wir sie besiegeln?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Selbst ein Schwert wird der Schläge müde.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Es wird erst dann Frieden geben, wenn ich habe, was mir zusteht.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Dieser Krieg erschöpft Kräfte, die wir besser gegen andere einsetzen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>In unserem Reich leben vielerlei Volksstämme. Euer Volk wird sich auf der Durchreise heimisch fühlen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Lassen wir kriegerische Barbaren frei durch unsere Lande ziehen? Nein. Nein, das tun wir nicht.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sollen wir wie vernünftige Menschen vereinbaren, dass unsere Truppen in Frieden zu anderen Ländern marschieren können?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sprecht aufrichtig. Sind diese Truppen für Rom gedacht? Schickt Ihr sie zurück in den Frieden oder vorwärts ins Gemetzel?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>So soll es sein.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Giulio Cesare</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Veni, vidi, vici.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Giulio Cesare, il modello di tutti i successivi dittatori, era un condottiero militare che si guadagnò il supporto della gente comune e dell'esercito per scalare il potere e rovesciare un'oligarchia costituita. La sua ascesa segnò la fine della repubblica di Roma e l'inizio dell'impero.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La gens Iulia, nonostante la presunta discendenza dalla dea Venere, non era particolarmente rinomata in quanto famiglia patrizia. Pur facendo risalire la propria nobiltà a tempi remoti, nella repubblica di Roma occupava un posto alquanto marginale. La storia di Giulio Cesare ebbe inizio quando divenne capo della famiglia nell'85 a.C. e fu immediatamente preso di mira dal vincitore di una sanguinosa guerra civile tra Gaio Mario, parente di Cesare, e Lucio Silla. Cesare perse i pochi possedimenti di cui la sua famiglia poteva disporre e anche la facoltà di servire come sacerdote di Giove. In ristrettezze, decise di intraprendere la carriera militare. Questa scelta avrebbe avuto conseguenze di portata storica.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>All'inizio della sua carriera nell'esercito, Cesare fu catturato dai pirati nel mar Egeo. Dopo aver fatto amicizia coi marinai, li incoraggiò a chiedere più soldi di quanto valesse, scherzando sul fatto che, una volta liberato, li avrebbe rintracciati e distrutti. I pirati seguirono il suo consiglio... e da parte sua, Cesare diede immediatamente seguito alla sua minaccia.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Cesare divenne famoso per la sua opposizione alla corruzione nel Senato e per la stima di cui godeva tra i militari. Dopo aver scalato rapidamente le posizioni, vinse un consolato nel 59 a.C. e diventò membro di un triumvirato insieme a due potenti alleati. Nel frattempo si guadagnò la benevolenza del popolo, promuovendo la ridistribuzione di terre e usando i suoi soldati per minacciare i nobili e sedare eventuali conflitti. Così facendo Cesare si guadagnò parecchi nemici: per proteggersi dalle rappresaglie si assicurò il posto di governatore delle diverse regioni di una Gallia divisa. Anche questa mossa avrebbe segnato il suo futuro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Guerra significava opportunità. Cesare continuò a respingere le forze dei galli, incluse quelle di Ambiorix, nelle guerre galliche. Ma durante la sua assenza i suoi oppositori si diedero da fare per minare il suo sostegno in patria, prendendo come pretesto le presunte irregolarità nella sua elezione a console. L'ex alleato di Cesare, Pompeo, prese il potere per sé; i senatori invitarono entrambi i contendenti a deporre le armi per ripristinare l'equilibrio dello Stato. Nessuno dei due lo fece, anzi, Cesare dalla Gallia si mise in marcia alla testa delle sue vittoriose legioni, alla volta di Roma.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Così raggiunse il fiume Rubicone. Agli eserciti attivi era proibito entrare nell'area vicino a Roma: varcare quel fiume sarebbe equivalso a un atto ostile. Cesare fece una pausa prima di dichiarare "alea iacta est", il dado è tratto. Così varcò il fiume e cambiò il corso della storia. Scoppiò una guerra civile, ma l'abilità militare di Cesare gli permise di ricacciare l'avversario Pompeo fuori dall'Italia, verso Spagna e Grecia. Tornato a Roma, Cesare fu nominato dittatore, una mossa che nel corso della storia altri dittatori avrebbero emulato.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La mossa successiva fu il consolidamento del potere. Mescolando astuzia e minacce, Cesare soggiogò il Senato e, con un'atto divenuto celebre, intervenne in Egitto in favore di Cleopatra (che poi divenne la sua amante). Seppure pubblicamente favoriva i cittadini comuni, in effetti limitò il potere dei ceti non nobiliari, sia nelle gilde degli artigiani che attraverso le riforme dei codici. In seguito all'espansione di Roma, Cesare permise un certo grado di decentralizzazione, estendendo i diritti legali oltre l'Italia e dando alle città estere una maggior libertà di governarsi come meglio ritenevano. La sua dittatura si basava sui nuovi poteri che il Senato gli aveva conferito legalmente, ma anche su atteggiamenti intimidatori informali (per esempio, si oppose a diverse azioni raccomandate dallo stesso Senato).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Come si vede, il potere del Senato risultò severamente limitato. Non stupisce, quindi, che i suoi nemici volessero cospirare contro Cesare. E lo fecero. Durante un incontro nel Senato in cui avrebbe dovuto prendere la parola, il dittatore fu accoltellato 23 volte. Tra i cospiratori, in particolare, c'era il suo presunto amico Bruto. Anche se Shakespeare ha fatto passare alla storia la frase "et tu, Brute", le sue ultime parole furono in effetti in greco: "kai su, teknon?", che significa "anche tu, figlio?".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>In seguito, Roma precipitò nel caos. Il popolo, che amava ancora Cesare, trasferì il suo sostegno al suo generale Antonio, che obbligò alla fuga gli aspiranti leader Bruto e Cassio. Allo stesso tempo Ottaviano, il figlio adottivo di Cesare, rivendicò per sé il diritto a governare. Ne scaturì una guerra "tutti contro tutti" in seguito alla quale gli assassini furono perseguitati e uccisi, così come Antonio, che aveva cercato rifugio presso Cleopatra. Ottaviano divenne il nuovo Cesare col nome di Augusto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>L'esperienza di Cesare mise in mostra il potere del populismo abbinato alla forza militare e all'ambizione sfrenata. Aspiranti imperatori come Napoleone e Simón Bolívar presero ispirazione proprio da esso e in effetti, monarchie che hanno adottato termini quali "Kaiser," "Zar" o, in arabo, "Qaisar", stabilirono il titolo dei propri monarchi proprio seguendo l'esempio del grande dittatore.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Giulio Cesare vuole conquistare ogni esagono della mappa, annientando sia i barbari sia le civiltà che si oppongono.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Grazie alla loro grande [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento, sbloccare le Legioni con la Lavorazione del Ferro è la chiave della vittoria. In seguito si possono usare le Legioni per disperdere gli Avamposti barbarici e conquistare le città nemiche. L' [ICON_Gold] Oro aggiuntivo che queste conquiste frutteranno a Giulio Cesare lo aiuterà a proiettarsi verso la costruzione di un grande impero e di un esercito potente. L'abilità "Tutte le strade portano a Roma" porterà ulteriore [ICON_GOLD] Oro, mentre le masse potranno essere placate grazie all' [Icon_amenities] Attrattiva delle Terme. La forza militare di Roma è l'ideale per puntare a una Vittoria per dominio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Guerre galliche</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Odia i barbari. Apprezza le civiltà che distruggono gli Avamposti barbarici. Non ama le civiltà che ignorano gli Avamposti barbarici.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sono Cesare, distruttore di cospirazioni, nei boschi delle Alpi, così come nel Senato.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Quanta ambizione. Cerchi di conquistarmi prima che io muova contro di te. Mi piace.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il dado è tratto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un'esercito vittorioso è quello guidato da un vincente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il pericolo è alle porte e tu non fai nulla.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>"Tu quoque?" Dunque soccombi, Cesare.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Tra i miei amici posso annoverare Ottaviano, Antonio e il mio caro Bruto. E adesso anche te!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Riesco sempre a capire quando un amico è pronto a tradire. Sempre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Roma non è priva di attrattive. Diveniamo amici.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sarò un tuo buon amico, quanto il mio caro Bruto lo è per me.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Hai un aspetto emaciato, affamato. Persone del genere sono pericolose.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Li accompagneremo per tutta Roma, come abbiamo fatto con Vercingetorige!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I doni non sono mai gratuiti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I doni di Roma: pane, olive, formaggi, garum. Dicono che garantiscano una lunga vita, proprio come il mio favore.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Spero che tu stia parlando sul serio. Per quanto mi riguarda, le mie minacce non sono mai pronunciate a sproposito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Hai un aspetto pallido e affamato. Non mi piace. (Ti denuncia)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Nel bene o nel male, tutte le strade portano a Roma. Ti piacerebbe vederla?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Passerà.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Saluti da Roma! Siamo ansiosi di conoscere gli altri fari di civiltà nel buio del deserto. Vuoi parlarmi del vostro?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Prestami attenzione.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I nostri interessi sono intrecciati come una testuggine. Vogliamo formalizzare l'accordo?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Anche una spada si stanca di colpire.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Ci sarà pace solo quando avrò avuto ciò che mi spetta.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Questa guerra impegna delle forze che faremmo meglio a usare contro altri.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Le nostre terre sono abitate da migliaia di popoli diversi. Il tuo si sentirà a casa mentre passa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Permettiamo forse ai guerrieri barbari di aggirarsi liberamente per le nostre terre? Assolutamente no.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Siamo d'accordo che, come persone civilizzate, permetteremo alle nostre truppe di marciare in pace verso altre terre?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Parla chiaramente. Quelle truppe sono destinate a Roma? Le richiamerai in pace o le manderai al macello?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>E sia.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ユリウス・カエサル</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>来た。見た。勝った。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>独裁者を志す者全員の手本、それがユリウス・カエサルだ。軍人だった彼は、確立されていた寡頭制に対抗する手段として民衆と軍を味方につけた。彼の台頭によって共和制ローマは終焉を迎え、帝政ローマがはじまったのだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ユリウス氏族は、女神ウェヌスに連なる血筋とうたわれていた一方で、名門中の名門かといえば、そこまでではなかった。比較的遠い時代に貴族 (平民を意味するプレブスに対してパトリキと呼ばれた) の地位を得たが、ユリウス氏族は共和制ローマでは傍流の存在でしかなかった。ユリウス・カエサルの物語は、彼が紀元前85年に一家の長となった時からはじまる。家督を継ぐやいなや、カエサルは親族であるガイウス・マリウスとの血なまぐさい内戦の新たな勝者となったルキウス・スッラに命を狙われることになった。この結果カエサルは、一家に残されたわずかな遺産とユピテルの神官になる資格を失ってしまう。どん底のカエサルは軍に入った。歴史を変える大きな選択だった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>カエサルの軍隊生活初期のエピソードに、エーゲ海で海賊に捕まったときの話がある。彼は海賊たちと打ち解け、自分の価値以上の身代金を要求するよう言い聞かせた後、自由になったら彼らを追い詰めて破滅させてやると軽口をたたいた。海賊たちは言われたとおりにし、自由になるとカエサルもすぐさま宣言どおりにした。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>名を知られるようになって間もない頃のカエサルは、元老院の腐敗を毛嫌いし、軍から支持されている人物として知られていた。順調に出世して紀元前59年に執政官の座を勝ち取り、有力者である2人の味方と自身からなる三頭政治の一角となったカエサルは、民衆の支持を得るべく土地の再分配を強行し、諍いが起きると兵士を差し向けて貴族を脅しつけた。この結果、敵を増やしてしまったカエサルは、報復から身を守ることも兼ねて、紛争地であるガリアの総督の地位を得た。この判断もまた、彼の未来を形作るものとなった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>戦争はチャンスに他ならなかった。カエサルはガリアの軍勢と激しく戦った。ちなみにアンビオリクスは、このガリア戦争におけるガリア側の指導者の1人である。ところがカエサルが不在の間に、本国では執政官選挙における不正を理由に反カエサル派が躍起になって彼の支持基盤を弱めていた。かつてはカエサルの盟友だったポンペイウスが単独執政官の座につくと、元老院は両者に武装解除と法による秩序の回復を求めたが、どちらも従わず、それどころかカエサルはガリアで勝利を収めた軍団を引き連れ、ローマに向けて進軍をはじめた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>有名なルビコン川の逸話はこの時のものだ。軍をともなってローマ本国に入ることは禁止されており、ここを渡河することは明確な反逆を意味していた。カエサルは川のほとりで足を止め、「賽は投げられた」と大音声で告げると、川を渡って歴史の流れを変えたのである。こうして内戦が勃発したが、カエサルの軍略は敵対するポンペイウスのそれを上回り、彼はイタリアから追い出されてスペインとギリシャへ落ちのびた。ローマに戻ったカエサルは独裁官となった。後世の独裁者たちの手本になりそうな見事な手際である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>次なる動きは権力の一本化だった。カエサルは奸智に脅しを織り交ぜて元老院を服従させた。クレオパトラ (後に恋人となる) に味方してエジプトの政争に介入したのは有名な話だ。公人としてのカエサルは民衆を厚遇していたが、職人の組合においても、法の改正においても、非貴族の力を制限した。その一方で、ローマの拡大を尊重し、ある程度の地方分権化を認め、イタリアの外にも法的権利を広げ、適切とみなした範囲で地方都市のさらなる自治を認めた。カエサルの独裁政治は、非公式の脅し (元老院の決議を何度かあっさり拒否した) と、元老院から与えられた新たな法的権限の両方に依存していた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>事ここに至って、元老院の権力は大きく揺らいでいるように見えた。彼の政敵が陰謀を企てたのも無理はない。その企ては実行に移された。カエサルは演説することになっていた元老院の議場で23箇所を刺されて死んだ。手を下した者の中には、カエサルが可愛がっていたブルトゥス (ブルータスは英語式の発音だ) もいた。シェイクスピア劇の「ブルータス、お前もか」という台詞が有名だが、「息子よ、お前もか？」とギリシャ語で言ったとの説もある。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>その後、国は混乱に陥った。大衆はまだカエサルを支持しており、今度はその腹心だった将軍アントニウスを支持した。指導者になるつもりだったブルータスとカッシウスは逃亡を余儀なくされた。同時に、カエサルの養子であるオクタウィアヌスも後継者として名乗りを上げ、事態は万人の万人に対する闘争めいた様相を呈した。暗殺犯たちは追われ、殺された。クレオパトラのもとに逃れたアントニウスも同じ運命をたどった。敵をすべて片付けたオクタウィアヌスは、初代ローマ皇帝アウグストゥス・カエサルとなった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>カエサルの遺産は、軍事力や大胆な野心と結びつき、ポピュリズムの力を強めた。ナポレオンやシモン・ボリバルなど、皇帝を夢見た後世の人々はカエサルを手本とした。皇帝を意味するヨーロッパ諸語の称号、カイザー、ツァーリ、カイサルは、いずれもユリウス・カエサルに由来している。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ユリウス・カエサルは、敵対する文明と蛮族のいずれも滅ぼし、マップのタイルをすべて征服することを目指す野心的な指導者です。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>まずは「鉄器」を研究してレギオンを解除しましょう。高い [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力を持つこのユニットが勝利の鍵を握ります。レギオンを前進させて蛮族の野営地を滅ぼし、さらには敵対する都市を征服しましょう。こうした征服によって得られる追加の [ICON_Gold] ゴールドは、ユリウス・カエサルの帝国と軍をより大きなものへと発展させる原動力です。「すべての道はローマへ通じる」能力もさらなる [ICON_GOLD] ゴールドをもたらします。浴場から得られる [Icon_amenities] 快適性は、大衆の不満のはけ口となるでしょう。強大な軍事力を持つユリウス・カエサルは、制覇による勝利に適した指導者です。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ガリア戦争</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>蛮族を憎む。蛮族の前哨地を排除する文明を好み、放置する文明を嫌う。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>私はカエサル。森に覆われた山と元老院、いずれの策謀も打ち砕く者だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野心的だな。やる前にやれというわけだ。よかろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>賽は投げられた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>勝利する軍とは、勝者が率いる軍だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>目の前に危険が迫っているのに何もしないとはな。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>お前もか？ ならばカエサルもここまでだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>私にはオクタウィアヌス、アントニウス、そしてブルータスという仲間たちがいるが、そこに君も加わったわけだ！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>不誠実な友を見分けることにかけては自信がある。見誤るものか。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ローマは礼節を知る国だ。友好関係を結ぼう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>私が可愛がっているブルータスと同じような真の友になろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>痩せて腹が減っているようだな。危険な臭いがするぞ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ウェルキンゲトリクスにしたのと同様にローマを案内してやるとしよう！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>無償の贈り物などあるものか。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>パンにオリーブ、チーズにガルム。いずれも長寿を約束すると言われている。ローマの、そして私個人からの贈り物だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>何を言っているかわかっているのか？ 私ならこけおどしはせん。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>顔色が悪い。腹も空いているようだな。嘆かわしいことだ。(非難)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>すべての道はローマに通じる。良くも、悪くも。わかるかね？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>思ったとおり立派な御仁だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ローマから挨拶申し上げる！ 我々は荒野にある異なる文明についても学びたいと思っているのだ。教えてくれまいか？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>耳を貸してくれ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>我々の利益は軍団兵が構える盾の壁のように繋がっている。正式に手を組まないか？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>剣でさえ血を吸ってばかりでは飽きてしまう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>平和が訪れるのは、私が手にすべきものを手にしたときだけだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>この戦争のせいで、他で使うべき力が奪われている。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>この国は多様な民族の集まりだ。君も気兼ねなく通るといい。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>我らの土地を蛮族の戦士が荒らすことを許すと？ まさか。許可できんな。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>冷静な者同士、他国へ向かう兵の通行を認めないかね？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>はっきり言え。この兵たちはローマに向かっているのか？ 撤収させて平和を保てばよし。進軍すれば血の海と化すぞ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>拒否権を発動する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>よかろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>율리우스 카이사르</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>왔노라, 보았노라, 이겼노라.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이후 나타날 모든 독재자 후보의 본보기인 율리우스 카이사르는 기존의 과두제에 대항할 권력을 쟁취할 수단으로 시민과 군대의 지지를 일궈낸 군인이었습니다. 카이사르의 부상은 로마 공화국의 종말이자 제국의 시작을 의미했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>율리아 씨족은 대개의 귀족 가문이 그렇듯 비너스 여신에게서 나왔다고 주장하지만, 그리 대단한 가문은 아니었습니다. 비교적 오래전에 귀족, 즉 평민의 반대 의미로서 귀족 계급에 올라갔지만, 로마 공화국에 있어서는 사소한 일이었습니다. 율리우스 카이사르의 이야기는 기원전 85년에 그가 가장이 되면서 시작됩니다. 카이사르는 가장이 되자마자 그의 친척 가이우스 마리우스와 루키우스 술라의 피비린내 나는 내전에서 승리한 술라의 표적이 되었습니다. 카이사르는 얼마 안 되는 유산과 유피테르의 사제직을 모두 잃었습니다. 거의 빈털터리가 된 카이사르는 군대에 입대했습니다. 그 선택은 극적인 결과를 낳게 될 터였습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>카이사르는 군 경력 초기에 에게해의 해적에게 붙잡힌 일이 있었습니다. 카이사르는 해적들과 친구가 되어 더 많은 몸값을 부르라고 부추겼고, 풀려나면 그들을 추적하여 깡그리 없애버리겠다고 농담처럼 얘기했습니다. 해적들은 카이사르의 조언을 받아들였고... 카이사르는 농담으로 한 위협을 즉시 실행에 옮겼습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>초기에 카이사르는 원로원의 부패에 반대하고 군대를 좋아하는 인물로 유명했습니다. 기원전 59년, 집정관에 당선되고 '삼두정'의 일원이 된 카이사르는 계급이 오르면서 일반 시민에게 호의를 베풀어 토지 재분배를 밀어붙이며 갈등이 벌어지면 자기 병사들과 함께 귀족을 위협했습니다. 그 덕분에 카이사르에게는 적들이 생겼고, 그는 보복을 피하고자 정세가 어수선한 갈리아 지역의 총독직을 확보했습니다. 이 행위 또한 그의 미래를 결정하는 요소가 되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>전쟁은 곧 기회입니다. 카이사르는 갈리아 전쟁에서 암비오릭스를 포함한 갈리아 군대를 가차 없이 밀어붙였습니다. 그러나 카이사르가 로마를 떠나 있는 동안 그의 정적들은 집정관 선거에서의 부정을 빌미로 삼아 카이사르의 지지 세력을 적극적으로 공략했습니다. 한때 동맹이었던 폼페이우스는 단독 집정관이 되었고, 원로원에서는 두 사람에게 무장을 해제하고 법질서를 재건할 것을 촉구했습니다. 둘 다 그 말을 따르지 않았고, 설상가상으로 카이사르는 갈리아 전쟁에서 승전한 군단병을 돌려 로마로 진군하기 시작했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>그리고 거기 루비콘강이 있었습니다. 로마 본토에서는 군대 활동이 금지됐으며 루비콘강을 건너는 것은 적대적 행동의 신호였습니다. 카이사르는 루비콘강 앞에 잠시 멈춰 'alea icata est(알리아 이악타 에스트)', 즉 주사위는 던져졌다고 선언했습니다. 카이사르는 강을 건넜으며, 역사의 흐름을 바꾸었습니다. 내전이 발발했지만, 카이사르의 군사 기획은 적인 폼페이우스를 압도하였습니다. 카이사르는 그를 이탈리아에서 스페인을 거쳐 그리스까지 추격했습니다. 로마로 돌아온 카이사르는 독재관에 임명되었습니다. 후대의 독재자들이 모방하게 될 행동이었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>권력을 통합하는 것이 다음 조치였습니다. 카이사르는 속임수와 위협을 교묘하게 섞어서 원로원을 겁먹게 했고, 이집트에서는 그의 연인이 된 클레오파트라를 대신하여 개입한 것으로 유명합니다. 카이사르는 공적으로는 서민을 우대하는 모습을 보였지만, 장인 길드와 법률 개혁 양쪽 면에서 귀족이 아닌 사람들의 권력을 제한했습니다. 로마의 확장에 경의를 표하는 의미에서 카이사르는 어느 정도의 분권을 허용하여 이탈리아 너머까지 법적 권리를 확장했으며, 지방 도시에 그들이 적절하다고 생각하는 방식으로 통치하도록 더 많은 자유를 허용했습니다. 카이사르의 독재 정권은 원로원에서 부여한 새로운 법적인 권한은 물론, 비공식적인 협박(카이사르는 간단히 원로원의 움직임을 여러 개 거부했습니다)에도 의존했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이렇게 보면 원로원의 권력이 심각하게 흔들린 것처럼 보입니다. 적들이 카이사르를 상대로 음모를 꾸며도 놀랄 일은 아니었고, 실제로 그렇게 했습니다. 카이사르가 연설하기로 한 원로원 회의에서 카이사르는 23번 칼에 찔렸는데, 그중에는 그가 친구라고 생각했던 브루투스도 있었습니다. 흔히들 셰익스피어의 'et tu, brute(에 투, 브루트. 브루투스 너마저)'로 알고 있지만, 카이사르의 마지막 유언은 그리스어로 'kai su, teknon(카이 수, 테크논)', 즉 '아이야, 너도냐?'로 기록되어 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이후 로마는 혼란에 빠졌습니다. 카이사르는 여전히 대중의 지지를 받고 있었고, 이제 그 책임을 질 자는 카이사르의 장군 안토니우스가 되었습니다. 그리고 지도자를 꿈꾸던 브루투스와 카시우스는 도망쳐야만 했습니다. 동시에 카이사르의 양자 옥타비아누스가 통치권을 주장했고, 그에 따라 만인의 만인에 대한 전쟁이 발발했습니다. 카이사르의 암살자는 물론, 클레오파트라에게로 도망쳤던 안토니우스까지 쫓기다 죽었습니다. 옥타비아누스가 아우구스투스 카이사르가 되려고 할 때였습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>카이사르의 유산은 대담한 야망뿐 아니라 군사력과 결합된 민중주의의 힘도 강화했습니다. 나폴레옹, 볼리바르와 같은 황제 지망생은 카이사르에게서 영감을 얻었고 자신을 '카이저'나 '차르', '카이사르'라고 칭하는 군주들은 카이사르의 이름을 원하는 만큼 마음대로 차용했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>율리우스 카이사르는 지도의 모든 타일을 정복하여 야만인과 적대하는 문명을 모두 무찌르는 게 좋습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>철제 기술에서 군단병을 잠금 해제하여 더욱 강력한 군단병의 [ICON_Strength] 전투력을 활용하는 것이 승리의 열쇠입니다. 군단병을 잠금 해제한 다음에는 군단병으로 야만인 주둔지를 해산하고 적 도시를 정복하십시오. 이런 정복을 통해 율리우스 카이사르가 받는 추가 [ICON_Gold] 금은 거대한 제국과 군대를 구축하는 데 도움이 될 것입니다. 추가 [ICON_GOLD] 금은 '모든 길은 로마로 통한다' 능력에서 나오며, 추가 [Icon_amenities] 쾌적도를 제공하는 목욕탕으로 대중을 달랠 수 있습니다. 카이사르의 군사력은 지배 승리에 가장 적합합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>갈리아 전쟁</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야만인을 증오합니다. 야만인 전초기지를 처리하는 문명을 좋아합니다. 야만인 전초기지를 무시하는 문명을 싫어합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>나는 카이사르, 고산지역의 숲과 원로원 양쪽의 음모를 파괴한 사람이오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야심이 넘치는구려. 내가 그러기 전에 날 정복하려 하는구려. 인정하오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>주사위는 던져졌소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>영광스러운 군대는 승자가 이끄는 군대라오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위험이 코앞에 닥쳤는데 당신은 아무것도 하지 않고 있구려.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>그렇게 응수하는가? 이렇게 카이사르가 쓰러지는군.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>난 옥타비아누스와 안토니우스, 그리고 친애하는 브루투스를 친구로 두었소. 그리고 이제 당신 또한 그렇소!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>난 언제나 위험한 친구는 알아볼 수 있지. 언제나.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>로마에 은총이 없는 것은 아닙니다. 우리와 친구가 되시오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>친애하는 브루투스가 그랬던 것처럼, 나도 그대에게 있어 진정한 친구가 될 것이오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>여위고 배고픈 모습을 했구려. 그런 사람은 위험한 법이오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>베르킨게토릭스에게 그랬듯 저들을 로마로 인도할 것이오!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세상에 공짜 선물은 없는 법이지.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>로마의 선물이오. 빵, 올리브, 치즈, 가룸을 드리지요. 이들은 제 선의와 마찬가지로 장수를 가져다준다고 하오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>그 말이 진심이어야 할 거요. 무엇보다 나는 헛된 위협은 하지 않소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>창백하고 굶주린 모습이구려. 마음에 들지 않소. (공개 비난)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좋든 나쁘든 모든 길은 로마로 통하오. 한번 보시겠소?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>허가하겠소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>로마에서 인사드리오! 우리는 야생에서 다른 문명의 빛을 배우고자 하오. 당신의 문명에 대해 이야기해주시겠소?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>귀를 잠깐 빌려주시오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>우리 관심사는 귀갑진처럼 연결되어 있소. 이 관계를 공표하는 건 어떻겠소?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>검조차 지칠 때가 있소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>평화는 내가 차지해야 할 것을 얻었을 때만 찾아올 것이오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이 전쟁은 다른 곳에 필요한 힘을 약화시키고 있소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>우리 조국에는 수천 명의 다른 민족이 있소. 여러분의 시민들이 지나갈 때 집처럼 느낄 것이오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야만인 전사들이 우리 땅을 마음대로 짓밟게 하라고? 어림도 없소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>규율 잡힌 사람들답게 우리 부대가 다른 땅을 향해 평화롭게 행진하는 것에 동의하는 건 어떻겠소?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>솔직히 말씀하시오. 이 부대는 로마를 칠 병력이오? 평화를 위해 부대를 물리겠소, 아니면 학살을 위해 전진시키겠소?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>거부하오.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좋소.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Juliusz Cezar</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Przybyłem, zobaczyłem, zwyciężyłem.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Juliusz Cezar, który stał się wzorem dla wszystkich przyszłych dyktatorów, był wojskowym wykorzystującym poparcie zwykłych ludzi i wojska, aby zdobyć władzę wbrew oporowi ustabilizowanej oligarchii. Jego rządy wyznaczyły koniec republiki rzymskiej i początek cesarstwa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Ród Juliuszów nie był zbyt potężny w porównaniu z innymi patrycjuszowskimi rodzinami, pomimo że wywodził swój rodowód od bogini miłości, Wenus. Juliuszowie zostali wyniesieni do rangi patrycjuszy (znajdującej się w strukturze społecznej ponad warstwą plebejuszy) w stosunkowo odległych czasach, ale w republice rzymskiej byli mało znaczącym rodem. Historia Juliusza Cezara zaczęła się, gdy został głową rodziny w 85 r. p.n.e. i niemal natychmiast stał się celem ataku nowego zwycięzcy krwawej wojny domowej między swoimi krewnymi, Gajuszem Mariuszem i Lucjuszem Sullą. Cezar stracił resztę rodzinnego majątku oraz prawo sprawowania posługi jako kapłan Jowisza. Mając stosunkowo niewiele, postanowił skupić się na karierze wojskowej. Wybór ten przyniósł dramatyczne konsekwencje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Na początku swojej kariery wojskowej Cezar został schwytany przez piratów na Morzu Egejskim. Zaprzyjaźnił się z nimi i zachęcił, by zażądali większego okupu, niż był wart. Żartował, że gdy odzyska wolność, wytropi ich i zniszczy. Posłuchali jego rady... a on spełnił swoją groźbę.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Początkowo Cezar był przeciwnikiem korupcji w Senacie i ulubieńcem wojskowych. W miarę jak piął się po szczeblach kariery, zdobywając urząd konsula w 59 r. p.n.e. i stając się członkiem „triumwiratu”, czyli porozumienia Cezara i dwóch potężnych sojuszników, zaczął zabiegać o względy zwykłych ludzi, wymuszając podział ziemi i w razie konfliktów grożąc szlachcie swoimi żołnierzami. Zyskał w ten sposób wielu wrogów. Aby uchronić się przed ich odwetem, zapewnił sobie pozycję namiestnika podzielonego na frakcje regionu Galów. To posunięcie również miało wpłynąć na jego przyszłość.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wojna oznaczała szansę. W wojnach galijskich Cezar nieustannie napierał na siły galijskie, w tym Ambioryksa. Jednak podczas nieobecności Cezara jego przeciwnicy aktywnie podkopywali jego poparcie w kraju, wskazując na nieprawidłowości dotyczące wyborów, w których uzyskał stanowisko konsula. Niegdysiejszy sojusznik Cezara, Pompejusz, skupił w swoich rękach wielką władzę, a senatorowie nalegali, żeby obaj się rozbroili i w ten sposób przywrócili porządek prawny. Żaden z nich tego nie zrobił. Co gorsza, Cezar rozpoczął powrotny marsz swych zwycięskich legionów z Galii na Rzym.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Na drodze stanęła mu rzeka Rubikon. Aktywne wojska miały zakaz wstępu do samego Rzymu, a przekroczenie tej rzeki oznaczało akt wrogości. Cezar zatrzymał się na jej brzegu i oznajmił „Alea iacta est” – kości zostały rzucone – po czym przekroczył rzekę i zmienił bieg historii. Wybuchła wojna domowa, ale dzięki trafnej taktyce Cezar przechytrzył swojego przeciwnika, Pompejusza, i przepędził go z Italii do Hiszpanii i Grecji. Po powrocie do Rzymu został ogłoszony dyktatorem. Ruch ten mieli naśladować również późniejsi dyktatorzy.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Następnym krokiem była konsolidacja władzy. Podstępem i groźbą Cezar podporządkował sobie Senat i przeprowadził w imieniu Kleopatry (która została jego kochanką) słynną interwencję w Egipcie. Choć publicznie znany był ze sprzyjania zwykłym ludziom, to ograniczał wpływy osób spoza arystokracji zarówno w gildiach rzemieślniczych, jak i poprzez reformy prawne. Ze względu na ekspansję Rzymu Cezar pozwolił na pewien stopień decentralizacji, nadając prawa mieszkańcom ziem poza granicami Italii i dając lokalnym miastom więcej swobody. Jego dyktatura opierała się zarówno na nieformalnym zastraszaniu (po prostu odrzucił kilka uchwał senackich), jak też na nowych uprawnieniach oficjalnie nadanych mu przez Senat.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Władza Senatu wydawała się poważnie zachwiana. Nie dziwi więc, że wrogowie Cezara spiskowali przeciwko niemu. Na posiedzeniu senatu, na którym Cezar miał przemawiać, został zasztyletowany 23 pchnięciami – wśród zamachowców był też jego rzekomy przyjaciel, Brutus. Ostatnimi słowami umierającego Cezara miało być zdanie „Et tu, Brute?” („I ty, Brutusie?”), znane ze sztuki Szekspira, lub „Kai su, teknon?” („I ty, mój synu?”), które podaje Swetoniusz w „Żywotach cezarów”. W rzeczywistości jednak Cezar najprawdopodobniej zginął w milczeniu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po tym wydarzeniu w imperium zapanował chaos. Masy wciąż popierające Cezara udzieliły wsparcia jego generałowi, Antoniuszowi, a niedoszłych uzurpatorów – Brutusa i Kasjusza – zmuszono do ucieczki. W tym samym czasie prawa do rządzenia rościł sobie adoptowany syn Cezara, Oktawian. Tak doszło do – wydawało się – wojny każdego z każdym. Zabójcy Cezara zostali wytropieni i zabici. Zginął również Antoniusz, który szukał schronienia u Kleopatry. Kolejnym cezarem miał zostać Oktawian August.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dziedzictwo Cezara wzmocniło siłę populizmu połączonego z siłą wojskową, a także zuchwałość ambicji. Władcy pragnący rządzić imperiami, jak Napoleon i Bolivar, inspirowali się Cezarem. Monarchowie, którzy określali się jako „kaiser”, „car” czy „qaisar”, wywodzili te nazwy bezpośrednio od imienia rzymskiego dyktatora.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Juliusz Cezar chce podbić każde pole na mapie, eliminując zarówno barbarzyńców, jak i przeciwstawiające się mu cywilizacje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Odblokowanie legionów wraz z opracowaniem technologii obróbki żelaza jest kluczowe dla osiągnięcia zwycięstwa dzięki ich zwiększonej [ICON_Strength] sile bojowej. Wykorzystaj legiony do zniszczenia obozów barbarzyńców i podbicia przeciwstawiających ci się miast. Dodatkowe [ICON_Gold] złoto otrzymywane przez Juliusza Cezara za te podboje pomoże mu powiększyć imperium i armię. Dodatkowe [ICON_GOLD] złoto będzie napływało dzięki jego umiejętności „Wszystkie drogi prowadzą do Rzymu”, a łaźnie zapewnią dodatkowe [Icon_amenities] udogodnienia, dzięki którym udobruchasz masy. Militarna potęga Cezara sprawia, że najłatwiej mu osiągnąć zwycięstwo przez dominację.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wojny galijskie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nienawidzi barbarzyńców. Lubi cywilizacje, które niszczą obozy barbarzyńców. Nie lubi cywilizacji, które ignorują obozy barbarzyńców.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jestem Cezar, niszczyciel spisków zarówno w alpejskich lasach, jak i senackich salach.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Co za ambicja. Chcesz podbić mnie, zanim ja podbiję ciebie. Pochwalam.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Kości zostały rzucone.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zwycięska armia to ta, na której czele stoi zwycięzca.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zagrożenie stoi u twego progu, a ty nic z tym nie robisz.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Tu quoque? Więc konaj, Cezarze.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wśród mych przyjaciół jest Oktawian, Antoniusz i mój drogi Brutus. A teraz także ty!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zawsze rozpoznam zdradzieckiego przyjaciela. Zawsze.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Rzym nie jest pozbawiony dobroci. Zostańmy przyjaciółmi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Będę ci prawdziwym przyjacielem, tak jak mnie przyjacielem jest mój drogi Brutus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wyglądacie na szczupłych i głodnych. Tacy ludzie są niebezpieczni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Może oprowadzimy ich po Rzymie jak niegdyś Wercyngetoryksa!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dary nigdy nie są darmowe.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Oto dary Rzymu: chleb, oliwa, sery i garum. Mówi się, że zapewniają – podobnie jak moje względy – długie życie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Lepiej nie rzucaj słów na wiatr. Moje groźby nigdy nie są czcze.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nie podoba mi się twój blady, wygłodniały wygląd. (Potępia cię).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wszystkie drogi prowadzą do Rzymu. Odwiedzisz go?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W porządku.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Pozdrowienia z Rzymu! Chętnie poznamy inne cywilizacje rozwijające się w dziczy. Opowiecie nam o swojej?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wysłuchaj mnie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nasze interesy są powiązane ze sobą jak tarcze testudo. Czy sformalizujemy nasz sojusz?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nawet miecz się w końcu męczy.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Pokój nastąpi dopiero wtedy, gdy zdobędę to, co moje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Ta wojna angażuje siły, które lepiej wykorzystać przeciwko innym.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nasze imperium obejmuje tysiące różnych ludów. Twoi ludzie poczują się jak u siebie, przemierzając nasze terytorium.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Czy pozwolimy barbarzyńskim wojownikom deptać naszą ziemię? Nie. Nie pozwolimy.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Czy zgodzimy się – jak przystało na ludzi ceniących ład – by nasze wojska mogły spokojnie maszerować w kierunku innych ziem?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Powiedz wprost. Czy te wojska mają pomaszerować na Rzym? Wycofasz je, aby zapanował pokój, czy poślesz naprzód, by nastąpiła rzeź?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niech się tak stanie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Юлий Цезарь</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Пришел, увидел, победил.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Образец для всех будущих диктаторов, Юлий Цезарь был военным человеком, который опирался на поддержку простого народа и легионов в борьбе против влиятельной аристократии. Его приход к власти ознаменовал собой переход Рима от республики к империи.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Род Юлиев не считался среди патрициев особо знатным даже несмотря на то, что якобы происходил от самой богини Венеры. Юлии получили титул патрициев довольно давно, но роль в Римской республике играли незначительную. История Юлия Цезаря начинается в 85 г. до н. э., когда он стал главой семьи и тут же попал под прицел нового победителя в кровавой гражданской войне между своим родственником Гаем Марием и Луцием Суллой. В последовавших за этим гонениях Цезарь потерял немногое оставшееся ему наследство и право служить жрецом Юпитера. Оставшись ни с чем, Цезарь выбрал военную службу. И это решение определило его будущую жизнь.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Однажды, еще в начале своей военной карьеры, Цезарь попал в плен к пиратам на Эгейском море. Он сдружился со своими пленителями и даже посоветовал им требовать за него больший выкуп, чем они изначально собирались. При этом Цезарь в шутку грозил своим новым друзьям, что как только освободится, обязательно разгромит флот пиратов и предаст их казни. Пираты послушались совета Цезаря… и тот немедленно исполнил свою угрозу.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В начале своей карьеры Цезарь был известным противником продажного Сената и пользовался уважением среди военных. Став консулом в 59 г. до н. э. и заключив триумвират — союз с двумя влиятельными политиками, он начал завоевывать доверие плебеев: перераспределял землю в их пользу, а когда по этому поводу возникали конфликты, запугивал патрициев войсками. Так он нажил много врагов и, спасаясь от них, отправился наводить порядок в земли разрозненных племен Галлии. Этот его шаг тоже стал судьбоносным.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Расценив Галльскую войну как возможность упрочить свое положение, Цезарь решительно ударил по силам галлов — в том числе разгромил племя вождя Амбиорикса. Но пока Цезарь воевал на севере, его враги активно подрывали его поддержку в Риме, апеллируя к нарушениям при избрании его консулом. Власть единолично захватил бывший союзник Цезаря Помпей. Сенаторы призывали обоих добровольно сложить с себя полномочия и восстановить законный порядок в государстве — но их увещеваниям никто не внял. Напротив, Цезарь выступил из Галлии и повел свои победоносные войска на Рим.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>По закону римским легионам было запрещено находиться на территории собственно Римской республики, и границей запретных земель служила река Рубикон. Пересечь ее означало объявить войну Риму. Подойдя к берегу, Цезарь ненадолго замешкался, но затем со словами «Alea iacta est» — «жребий брошен» форсировал реку и изменил этим ход истории. Началась гражданская война, в ходе которой Цезарю удалось умелым планированием и ловкими маневрами изгнать Помпея из Италии в земли Испании и Греции. Вернувшись в Рим, он принял титул диктатора. Последующие диктаторы не раз повторяли подобный ход.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Следующим шагом для Цезаря было сосредоточить власть в своих руках. Коварством и угрозами он подчинил себе сенат и даже вмешался в династический спор в Египте на стороне Клеопатры (которая стала его любовницей). Хотя Цезарь публично поддерживал плебеев, на деле он ограничивал власть непатрициев как в коллегиях, так и в законодательстве. В ответ на продолжающееся расширение Рима Цезарь разрешил частичную децентрализацию государства: он распространил права граждан за пределы Италии и предоставил городам больше возможностей самоуправления. Власть Цезаря держалась как на неявном запугивании (он просто отказывался давать ход ряду инициатив сената), так и на официальных полномочиях, которыми наделил его сенат.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Сам же сенат оказался власти практически лишен. Неудивительно, что в таких условиях против диктатора начал зреть заговор. Когда однажды Цезарь пришел в здание сената с речью, заговорщики напали на него и нанесли ему 23 ножевых ранения. В числе убийц был и друг Цезаря Брут. Нам известна фраза «И ты, Брут!» из пьесы Шекспира, но согласно некоторым источникам, последними словами Цезаря стала греческая фраза «Και συ τέκνον!» — «И ты, дитя мое!»</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>После убийства диктатора в империи воцарился хаос. Массы все еще поддерживали Цезаря, чьим преемником стал генерал Антоний, и несостоявшимся правителям Бруту и Кассию пришлось бежать. В то же время права на правление предъявил приемный сын Цезаря Октавиан, и разразилась война всех против всех. Убийц Юлия нашли и казнили. Был убит и Антоний, который бежал за спасением к Клеопатре. В итоге власть взял в свои руки Октавиан, принявший имя Августа Цезаря.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Опыт Цезаря продемонстрировал политическую силу популизма, подкрепленного военной мощью и дерзкими амбициями. Его примером вдохновлялись императоры последующих эпох, такие как Наполеон и Симон Боливар, а многие монаршие титулы — кайзеры, цари и кесари — восходят к его имени.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Юлий Цезарь стремится завоевать все клетки на карте, победить варваров и враждебные цивилизации.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ключ к победе для Цезаря — технология обработки железа, которая дает возможность обучать легионы с высокой [ICON_Strength] боевой мощью. Эти легионы будут разорять лагеря варваров и завоевывать вражеские города. Юлий Цезарь получает за такие завоевания больше [ICON_Gold] золота, которое позволяет ему расширять империю и нанимать больше войск. Еще больше [ICON_GOLD] золота дает его способность «Все дороги ведут в Рим». Возведя римские бани, вы обеспечите дополнительное [Icon_amenities] довольство, которое поможет вам заручиться народной поддержкой. Военная мощь Цезаря делает его идеальным кандидатом на военную победу.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Галльские войны</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ненавидит варваров. Любит цивилизации, которые уничтожают аванпосты варваров. Не любит цивилизации, которые оставляют аванпосты варваров.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Я Цезарь. Я пресек заговоры, что замышляли против меня в альпийских лесах и в сенате.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Смело. Хотите расправиться со мной прежде, чем я покорю ваши земли. Одобряю.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Жребий брошен.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Во главе успешной армии должен стоять победитель.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Опасность уже у вас на пороге, а вы сидите сложа руки.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ты тоже? Так пади же, Цезарь.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Мои друзья — это Октавий, Антоний и дорогой Брут. А теперь и вы тоже!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вероломного предателя я чую издалека.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>У Рима есть добродетели. Предлагаем вам нашу дружбу.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Я буду вам таким же верным другом, каким стал мне Брут.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ваши люди исхудали. Такие союзники нам не нужны.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Мы показали Рим Верцингеторигу — покажем и им!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>У всякого дара своя цена.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вот дары Рима — хлеб, оливы, сыр и гарум. Все они, равно как и моя благосклонность, даруют долгую жизнь.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Надеюсь, вы сдержите слово. Лично я не разбрасываюсь пустыми угрозами.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Мне не нравится ваша бледность и голодный взгляд. (Осуждает вас)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>К добру или к худу, все дороги ведут в Рим. Приведут ли они к нам и вас?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Это пройдет.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Рим приветствует вас! Мы жаждем знакомства с другими светочами цивилизации в этих варварских землях. Расскажите о себе.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Меня своим вниманьем удостойте!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Наши судьбы тесно переплетены между собой. Предлагаю скрепить союз.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Даже меч порой устает от битв.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Мир настанет, когда я обрету все мне предназначенное.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Эта война лишает нас сил, которые нужны нам в других битвах.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В нашу империю входят тысячи разных народов. Ваши послы будут чувствовать себя как дома.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Позволим ли мы вооруженным варварам безнаказанно топтать наши земли? Ни за что.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Предлагаю поступить цивилизованно и отправить наши войска в другие земли.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Говорите прямо. Ваши войска намерены напасть на Рим? Если они повернут назад, то уцелеют. Пойдут вперед — будут истреблены.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вето.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Да будет так.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>尤里乌斯·凯撒</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我来，我见，我征服。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>尤里乌斯·凯撒是后继独裁者们的典范，身为一个军人，他赢得了普通民众和军队的支持，并利用他们的力量反抗当时的寡头政治。他的崛起标志着罗马共和国的结束和罗马帝国的开始。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>和很多贵族家庭一样，''尤利亚''这个姓氏并不多见，而他们声称这起源于女神维纳斯。他们在很久以前被册封为贵族（相对于平民），但在罗马共和国中名不见经传。尤里乌斯·凯撒的故事开始于公元前85年，他成为家族之主的那一刻起，他几乎立即成为了血腥内战胜利者们的目标——这场内战在凯撒的亲戚盖乌斯·马里乌斯和卢修斯·苏拉之间展开。凯撒失去了家族仅有的一点遗产，也失去了担任朱庇特祭司的资格。几乎孑然一身的凯撒只得被迫从军。而事实证明，这是一个充满戏剧性的选择。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>他早期军旅生涯有过一段插曲。凯撒曾在爱琴海被海盗俘虏。结果他和海盗成为了朋友，还鼓励他们索要更高的赎金，并且开玩笑说，一旦自己获得自由，就会找到并消灭他们。海盗采纳了他的建议……而他也马上兑现了自己说过的话。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在从军生涯早期，凯撒以反对元老院腐败而为人所熟知，在军队中颇受爱戴。他平步青云，在公元前59年荣升罗马领事，成为了“三巨头联盟”中的一员，“三巨头联盟”是凯撒和两个强大盟友的联盟。为了拉拢平民百姓，凯撒常在平民和贵族暴发冲突时强制重新分配土地，并以武力威胁贵族。为此他树敌众多。为了保护自己的安全，他在高卢的冲突地区谋了总督一职。而这一举动也为他的未来奠定了基础。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战争意味着机会。在高卢战争中，凯撒毫不留情地打击高卢的势力——包括安比奥里克斯。但当他出征在外时，反对者却在积极破坏他在国内的支持度，称他在领事选举中存在违规行为。凯撒曾经的盟友庞培独揽大权，参议员们敦促两人解除武装，重新建立法律秩序，但两人都并未理睬。更糟的是，凯撒正率领他的胜利军团从高卢返回罗马。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>这支军队来到了卢比孔河边。根据法典，现役军队不能进入罗马城，越过卢比孔河会被视为敌对行动。凯撒来到河边，宣布战争已经在所难免。他渡过卢比孔河，改变了历史进程。内战就此爆发，凯撒发起了一系列军事行动，他智胜对手庞培，将其赶出意大利，后者流亡西班牙和希腊。回到罗马后，凯撒被任命为独裁者。此举也被后世独裁者们争相效仿。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>接下来便是巩固权力。凯撒软硬兼施，让元老院彻底屈服于他。他代表克利欧佩特拉（后来成为了他的情人）干预了埃及的事务。凯撒为自己树立的公众形象是爱民如子，但在工匠公会和法律改革的时候，他却限制了平民的权力。为了扩张罗马帝国，凯撒允许一定程度的权力下放，将法律权利赋予意大利以外的城市，并允许地方城市按照他们认为合适的方式进行更大程度的自治。他的独裁统治既依靠非正式的恐吓（他只是拒绝了元老院的几项举措），也依靠元老院赋予他新的法律权力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在如此情况下，元老院的权力受到了严重动摇。于是，一场针对凯撒的密谋悄然进行。在一次元老院会议上，正要发表讲话的凯撒被连刺23刀，其中下手最狠的正是他所谓的朋友布鲁图斯。在莎士比亚的作品中，凯撒临终前最后一句话是“也有你吗？布鲁图斯？”，但希腊语中的记录为“也有你吗？孩子？”</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>之后整个帝国陷入了动荡。民众中仍然有凯撒的支持者，他们转而支持凯撒的将军安东尼，而妄想篡位的布鲁图斯和卡修斯被迫逃亡。与此同时，凯撒的养子屋大维宣称拥有统治权，于是一场全民战争就这样爆发了。暗杀者反被追杀，投靠克利欧佩特拉的安东尼也遭到追杀。屋大维则以奥古斯都·凯撒之名登基。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>凯撒的统治将民粹主义、军事武装和称霸野心完美结合，形成一股强大的力量。后来的拿破仑、玻利瓦尔等统治者均以他为榜样。“凯撒”、“沙皇”或“盖萨尔”等统治者尊号皆是来源于这位罗马皇帝。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>尤里乌斯·凯撒想征服地图上的每一个格位，将蛮族和敌对文明消灭殆尽。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>罗马拥有更强的 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力，拥有“炼铁术”后解锁军团是取得胜利的关键。带领军团继续肃清蛮族营地，征服对手的城市。尤里乌斯·凯撒在征服中获得的额外金币将有助于他建立起庞大的帝国和军队。他的特色能力“条条大道通罗马”将提供额外 [ICON_GOLD] 金币，还可以用浴场来抚慰民众，提供额外的 [Icon_amenities] 宜居度。他的军事实力最适合统治胜利。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>高卢战争</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>讨厌蛮族。喜欢清除蛮族哨站的文明。讨厌对蛮族哨站视而不见的文明。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我是凯撒，无论在高山森林，还是元老院中，阴谋都会被我戳破。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>野心不小。还想在我攻击你之前先征服我。我就恩准你先下手。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>事已至此，即决生死吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>王者之师战无不胜。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>危险就在家门口，而你却熟视无睹。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>亦有汝焉？凯撒之命休矣。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>屋大维、安东尼、还有亲爱的布鲁图斯都是我的朋友。现在你也成了我的朋友！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我总是能识别奸诈的朋友。从未出错。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>罗马自然有它的魅力。和我们缔结友谊吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我要做你忠实的朋友，就像亲爱的布鲁图斯对我那样。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>你看上去瘦弱且饥渴。这样的人十分危险。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>要带他们去罗马，就像我们对维钦托利做的那样！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>天下没有白吃的午餐。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>来自罗马的礼物——面包、橄榄、奶酪、鱼露。以及我的恩惠，据说它可以使人延年益寿。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>你最好说到做到。就我自己来说，绝不会做出毫无意义的威胁。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>你看上去苍白而饥渴，让我厌恶。（谴责你）</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>罗马位于所有道路的尽头，不管是好是坏。你是否有缘见到？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>那么协议就此通过了。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>来自罗马的问候！我们渴望了解这片荒野中其他的文明之光。能说说你的情况吗？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>请听我说。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我们的利益紧密相连。能不能让关系更正式一点？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>连刀剑也厌倦了挥舞。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我只有得到属于自己的东西之后这里才能安宁。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>这场战争消耗了本该用来对付别人的力量。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我们的帝国拥有成千上万不同族群。当你的人民经过时，他们将拥有家一样的感觉。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>能让蛮族战士在我们的土地上自由穿行吗？不，不，我们不能。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>我们能否像君子一样同意双方军队在各自的国土中和平行军？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>直说了吧。这些军队是开往罗马的吗？你打算让他们回归和平，还是进入杀戮战场？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>反对。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>就这样吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Julio César</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Vine, vi, vencí.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Julio César, inspiración para todos los aspirantes a dictadores del futuro, fue un militar que cultivó el apoyo de la gente corriente y de los militares como camino hacia el poder, contra una oligarquía establecida. Su ascenso marcó el final de la república romana y el comienzo del imperio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La "gens" Julia no era gran cosa, como ocurría con muchas familias, a pesar de remontar sus supuestos orígenes a la diosa Venus. Habían ascendido al rango de nobles (es decir, patricios, en contraposición a los plebeyos) en un tiempo relativamente lejano, pero eran una nota al margen en la República romana. La historia de Julio César comienza cuando se convierte en cabeza de familia en el año 85 a. C. y casi de inmediato se convierte en el objetivo del nuevo ganador de una sangrienta guerra civil entre Cayo Mario, Lucio Sila y sus propios parientes. Como resultado, César perdió la poca herencia que le viniera de su familia y su capacidad para servir como sacerdote de Júpiter. Con este escaso patrimonio, César entró en el ejército. La elección resultaría muy acertada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En un episodio de los inicios de su carrera militar, César se vio capturado por los piratas en el mar Egeo. Se hizo amigo de los hombres y los alentó a pedir más dinero del que en verdad valía, bromeando y diciendo que, cuando estuviera libre, los perseguiría y destruiría. Ellos siguieron su consejo... y él, por su parte, cumplió de inmediato su amenaza.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Al principio de su carrera, César destacó como detractor de la corrupción senatorial y favorito de los militares. Al medrar, hacerse con el consulado en el 59 a. C. y convertirse en miembro del "triunvirato" (una alianza entre César y dos poderosos homólogos), César se ganó el favor de la plebe, impuso la redistribución de tierras y amenazó a la nobleza con sus soldados cuando aparecieron conflictos. Esto le granjeó enemigos, y se aseguró la gobernación de las regiones conflictivas de la Galia para protegerse de las represalias. Este movimiento también conformaría su futuro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La guerra presentaba una oportunidad. César presionó de manera implacable a las fuerzas galas –incluido Ambiórix– en la Guerra de las Galias. Pero, mientras estuvo fuera, los opositores de César no pararon de socavar su apoyo en casa, alegando irregularidades en su elección como cónsul. Pompeyo, otrora aliado de César, se hizo con todo el poder, y los senadores instaron a ambos hombres a abandonar las armas y restablecer el orden legal. Ninguno lo hizo. Peor aún, de regreso de la Galia, César comenzó a marchar sobre Roma con sus legiones victoriosas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Y ahí estaba el río Rubicón. Los ejércitos activos estaban prohibidos en la Roma propiamente dicha, y cruzar el gran río sería señal de una acción hostil. César hizo una pausa aquí antes de sentenciar su famoso "alea iacta est" ("la suerte está echada"). Cruzó el río y alteró el curso de la historia. Estalló una guerra civil, pero la planificación militar de César fue tal que superó a su oponente Pompeyo y lo persiguió en su huida de Italia hasta España y Grecia. Al regresar a Roma, nombraron a César dictador. Esta es una estrategia que imitarían dictadores posteriores.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Consolidar el poder fue el siguiente paso. Con una mezcla de astucia y amenazas, César intimidó al Senado y, como es bien sabido, intervino en favor de Cleopatra en Egipto (que se convirtió en su amante). Si bien de cara al público favorecía a los plebeyos, restringió el poder de los que no eran nobles, tanto en los gremios de artesanos como en las reformas legales. En aras de la expansión de Roma, César permitió cierto grado de descentralización y extendió los derechos que confería la ley más allá de Italia y dio a las ciudades locales más libertad para gobernar como mejor les pareciera. Su dictadura se basó tanto en la intimidación informal (simplemente, rechazó varias maniobras del Senado) como en los nuevos poderes legales que le otorgó esta cámara.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Por ello, el poder del Senado parecía gravemente perturbado y no era de extrañar que los enemigos conspiraran contra él. Y así lo hicieron. En una asamblea del Senado en la que César iba a hablar, lo apuñalaron 23 veces, y quien más su supuesto amigo Bruto. Si bien, según Shakespeare, sus últimas palabras fueron el famoso "et tu, Brute?", los historiadores se inclinan a pensar que fueron "kai su, teknon?" (¿tú también, hijo?, en griego).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tras ello, el país se sumió en el caos. César todavía tenía el apoyo de las masas, que recaía ahora sobre los hombros de su general Marco Antonio, y los conspiradores Bruto y Casio se vieron obligados a huir. Al mismo tiempo, el hijo adoptivo de César, Octavio, reclamó para sí el derecho a gobernar, y así comenzó una guerra al parecer de todos contra todos. Se persiguió y mató a los asesinos, así como a Marco Antonio, que había buscado refugio con Cleopatra. Octavio se convertiría en César Augusto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El legado de César reforzó el poder del populismo combinado con el brazo militar, así como la audacia de la ambición. Los aspirantes a emperadores como Napoleón y Bolívar se inspiraron en César, y los monarcas que se hicieron llamar káiser, zar o "qaisar" cogieron el título de su nombre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Julio César quiere conquistar todas las casillas del mapa y someter tanto a los bárbaros como a las civilizaciones rivales.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Desbloquear legiones en la Forja del hierro es esencial para la victoria, con su Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] superior. Luego haz que las legiones avancen para dispersar los Campamentos bárbaros y conquistar las ciudades enemigas. El Oro [ICON_Gold] adicional que recibe Julio César por estas conquistas lo ayudará a convertirse en un gran imperio y con un ejército enorme. Gana más Oro [ICON_GOLD] todavía por su habilidad Todos los caminos llevan a Roma, y puedes apaciguar a las masas con los Baños al proporcionarles más Servicios [Icon_amenities]. Su poderío militar va mejor para una lograr una victoria por Dominación.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Guerra de las Galias</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Odia a los Bárbaros. Le gustan las civilizaciones que eliminan Puestos bárbaros. No le gustan las civilizaciones que ignoran los Puestos bárbaros.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Soy César, destructor de conspiraciones en los bosques alpinos y en el Senado por igual.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Cuánta ambición. Pretendes conquistarme antes de que marche contra ti. Lo admiro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La suerte está echada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un ejército vence cuando está liderado por un vencedor.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El peligro está en tu puerta y no haces nada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>"Tu quoque?" Entonces cae, César.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Cuento a Octavio, a Antonio y a mi querido Bruto entre mis amigos. ¡Y ahora también a ti!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Siempre distingo a los amigos traicioneros. Siempre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Roma no está exenta de gracias. Ven con nosotros en amistad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Seré un amigo tan leal como lo es mi querido Bruto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tienes un aspecto demacrado y famélico. Tales personas son peligrosas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Los guiaremos por Roma como hicimos con Vercingétorix!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los regalos nunca son gratis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Se dice que los dones de Roma —pan, aceitunas, quesos y garo—, así como mi favor, conceden una vida longeva.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Espero que lo digas en serio. Yo, por mi parte, no amenazo en vano.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tienes un aspecto pálido y famélico. No me gusta. (Te denuncia).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Todos los caminos conducen a Roma, para bien o para mal. ¿Te gustaría verla?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Debe pasar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Saludos de Roma! Estamos deseando conocer otros faros de civilización en la oscuridad de la barbarie. Háblanos de tu tierra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Presta atención.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Nuestros intereses están unidos como una formación en tortuga. ¿Lo formalizamos?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Incluso una espada se cansa de golpear.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Solo habrá paz cuando tenga lo que es mío por derecho.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Esta guerra socava una fuerza que sería mejor usar contra otros.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Nuestro país abarca miles de pueblos diferentes. El vuestro se sentirá como en casa al cruzarlo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¿Dejamos que los guerreros bárbaros campen a sus anchas por nuestras tierras? No, en absoluto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¿Podemos permitir a nuestras tropas marchar en paz hacia otras tierras como gente civilizada?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Habla con franqueza. ¿Esas tropas se dirigen hacia Roma? ¿Las conducirás hacia la paz o hacia la matanza?</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Veto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Que así sea.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>尤里烏斯‧凱撒</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我來，我見，我征服。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>作為後世獨裁者的範本，尤里烏斯‧凱撒作為一名軍人，他培養起平民和軍隊的支持，並以此作為對抗當時寡頭政治的權力途徑。他的崛起象徵著羅馬共和的結束和帝國的開端。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>和當時很多貴族家庭一樣，儘管他們聲稱自己姓名的起源是女神維納斯，「Julia」這個姓氏其實並不常見。他們很久以前就有了顯貴的地位（相對於平民而言），但在羅馬共和國內卻始終沒沒無聞。尤利烏斯·凱撒的故事要於西元前85年說起，也就是他成為一家之主的那一刻。當時，凱撒的親戚蓋烏斯·馬略和盧基烏斯·蘇拉之間爆發了血腥內戰，而勝利者幾乎立刻便想將他除之後快。凱撒失去了家族僅有的一點遺產，也頓時失去了擔任朱庇特神祭司的資格。幾乎一無所有的凱撒只好投身軍旅。後來的事實證明，這是個充滿戲劇性的選擇。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在他早期的軍旅生涯中，有過一段插曲。凱撒在愛琴海遭到海盜俘虜。結果他和這些海盜成了朋友，還鼓勵他們索取高於他當時身價的贖金，還開玩笑地說，一旦重獲自由，他就會找到他們並消滅他們。海盜採納了索取更高贖金的建議……而他，也在重獲自由後立即消滅了這群海盜。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在其生涯早期，凱撒因反對元老院的貪污與腐敗而為人所熟知，成為了軍隊裡很受歡迎的人。隨著他平步青雲，在西元前59年獲選為羅馬執政官，成為了「三頭同盟」的一員，也就是凱撒和兩個強大盟友之間的聯盟。為了拉攏平民百姓，凱撒強制重新分配土地，並在發生衝突時用他的士兵來威脅貴族。為此他樹敵無數，為了保護自己的安全，他在衝突不斷的高盧地區謀求了總督一職。而這一舉動，也為他的未來奠定了基礎。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰爭代表著機遇。在高盧戰爭中，凱撒毫不留情地擊退高盧人的軍隊——也包括安比奧里克斯的部隊。但當他出征在外時，他的反對者便以他在執政官選舉中存在違法行為的理由積極地破壞其在國內的支持。這讓凱撒曾經的盟友龐培獨攬國內的大權，元老院的議員們呼籲兩人解除武裝，重新建立法律秩序。但雙方都不予理會。更糟的是，凱撒正率領他的凱旋之師從高盧向著羅馬進軍。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>這隻軍隊行進至盧比孔河。根據法規，現役軍隊不得進入羅馬城，越過盧比孔河會被視為敵對行為。凱撒來到河邊，宣佈「Alea icata est」（木已成舟，即決生死）。他強渡盧比孔河，改變了歷史的進程。內戰因此爆發了，凱撒以軍事方面的雄才大略，完勝了其對手龐培，並將其趕出了義大利，迫使他逃往西班牙和希臘。回到羅馬後，凱撒被任命為獨裁官。這樣的軍事政變被後來的獨裁者們爭相效仿。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>凱撒的下一步是鞏固權力。凱撒軟硬兼施，讓元老院徹底屈服於他。他代表克麗奧佩脫拉（後來成為他的情人）干預了埃及的事務。儘管凱撒為自己確立了偏袒平民的公眾形象，但在工匠公會和法律改革的時候，他卻限制了平民的權力。為了擴張羅馬帝國，凱撒允許一定程度的權力下放，將法律權利賦予到義大利以外的城市，並允許地方城市按照自己認為適合方式進行更多自治。他的獨裁統治既仰賴非正式的恐嚇手段（他只是拒絕了元老院的幾項舉措），也仰賴著元老院賦予他的新的法律權力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在這種情況下，元老院的權力受到嚴重的動搖。於是，一場針對凱撒的密謀悄然展開。在某次元老院會議上，正要發表演說的凱撒身中23刀，當中最著名的行兇者便是他所謂的朋友布魯特斯。在莎士比亞的作品中，凱撒臨終前最後一句話是「布魯特斯，亦有汝焉？」，但希臘語中的記錄為「孩子，亦有汝焉？」</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>之後，整個帝國陷入了動盪。民眾中仍然有凱撒的支持者，他們轉而支持凱撒的將軍安東尼，而妄想篡位的布魯特斯和卡西烏斯被迫逃亡。與此同時，凱撒的養子屋大維宣稱自己擁有統治權，於是一場全面戰爭就此爆發。暗殺者被追殺伏誅，而投靠克麗奧佩脫拉的安東尼也死了。屋大維則正式以奧古斯都·凱撒登上王位。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>凱撒的統治過程確立了一件事情，那就是當民粹主義的力量，加上軍權和稱雄野心時，能成就多厲害的霸業。後來的拿破崙、玻利瓦等人稱王時均視他為榜樣。無論是「凱撒」、「沙皇」或「蓋薩爾」等皇帝的稱呼，皆是取自這位羅馬皇帝。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>尤里烏斯‧凱撒想要征服地圖上的每個格位，擊敗所有蠻族和敵對的文明。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>用「煉鐵術」解鎖「軍團」，他們較高的 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力將是勝利的關鍵。然後帶領軍團踏上掃平蠻族營地和征服敵對城市的道路吧。尤里烏斯‧凱撒從這些征途中獲得的額外 [ICON_Gold] 金幣能協助他建立更大的帝國與軍隊。他的「條條大路通羅馬」能力也將帶來更多額外 [ICON_GOLD] 金幣，而你可以用浴場來提供額外 [Icon_amenities] 滿意度，藉此取悅群眾。他的軍事實力最適合爭取統治勝利。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>高盧戰爭</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GALLIC_WARS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>討厭蠻族。喜歡清除蠻族哨站所的文明。討厭對蠻族哨站所視而不見的文明。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我是凱撒，不管是高山森林深處還是元老院的陰謀，我都將竭盡粉碎。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>嗬，狼子野心。臆想在我的征服之道面前征服我。準奏了。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>木已成舟，即決生死吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>由勝利者帶領的大軍才會戰無不勝。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>危險就待在你家的門口，而你卻無所作為。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>亦有汝焉？凱撒之命休矣。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我有屋大維、安東尼和我親愛的布魯特斯當我的朋友。現在還多了你一個！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我總能看出哪些朋友兩面三刀。從沒看錯過。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>羅馬可是相當有風度的國家。和我們締結友誼吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我會成為你的真心好友，一如我親愛的布魯特斯待我那樣。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>你看起來又瘦又餓。這樣的人最危險了。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們會帶他們遊遍羅馬，就像我們當初對待維欽托利那樣！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>天下就沒有免費的贈禮。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>羅馬的餽贈：麵包、橄欖、起司、魚醬。除了這些，還有我的友好態度，據說都能保你長命百歲。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>你最好說到做到。像我這樣的人，可是不會空口威脅人的。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>你看起來既蒼白又飢餓。我不喜歡。（譴責你）</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>無論是好是壞，條條大路依舊通羅馬。你能看得出來吧？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>準了。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>來自羅馬的問候！我們迫不及待想瞭解荒野之中的其他文明之光了。何不向我說說你們的文明呢？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>聽我說來。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們的利益就像是龜甲陣一樣緊密相連。我們是否該正式締結關係了呢？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>就算是寶劍也有砍累的一天。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>等我拿了屬於我的東西後，才會迎來和平。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>這場戰爭勞心勞力，我不如將這些心力用來對付他人。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們的帝國內囊括成千上百種不同的民族。你的人在通過時肯定會覺得賓至如歸。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們要讓蠻族的勇士來去自如地踏進我們的土地嗎？不行。當然不可以。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們是否能像有紀律的人一樣，讓我們的軍隊平安地通過彼此的土地呢？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>你就直說吧。這些軍隊是衝著羅馬來的嗎？你打算和平地召回他們，還是派他們進軍接受殘殺呢？</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>不許。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_ANY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>那就這樣吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>