<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- Sejong-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME">
			<Text>Sejong</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_NAME">
			<Text>Hangul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SEJONG_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>When you complete your first Technology from a new Era, receive double your [ICON_SCIENCE] Science per turn as [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Ludwig II-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME">
			<Text>Ludwig II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_NAME">
			<Text>Swan King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LUDWIG_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Wonders, even if not finished, receive +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for every adjacent District. This [ICON_CULTURE]Culture is displayed in the City Yields. All  [ICON_CULTURE] Culture adjacencies provide [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism after discovering Castles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Theodora-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME">
			<Text>Theodora</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_NAME">
			<Text>Metanoia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THEODORA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Holy Sites provide [ICON_CULTURE] Culture equal to their adjacency bonus. Farms provide a [ICON_FAITH] Faith adjacency to Hippodromes and Holy Sites.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_SEJONG">
			<Text>Sejong Dewang, Sejong the Great, ruler of Joseon, from your pen proclamations flow that shape the course of history. A new society, a new way of being is yours to direct. Let your people live harmoniously by your example, and let your wisdom and knowledge guide Korea towards its destiny.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_LUDWIG">
			<Text>King Ludwig, they call you mad, but your madness is the madness of dreams, of poetry and fairy stories. You imagined that the world could be otherwise, that we could build an enchanted kingdom where all seemed tedious and mundane. Oh Swan King, the world has need of your castles and knights, your dragon-haunted mountains and mystical grottoes. Come again, and give us new dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_THEODORA">
			<Text>Empress Theodora, you come from nothing to rule the remnants of Rome! With your wit and beauty you captivated the people of Constantinople, and placed your hand upon the great wheel of power. In a time of strife and division, let all be guided by your counsel and set your shining seal upon the land.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
