<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_TITLE">
			<Text>Ramses II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_QUOTE">
			<Text>I have been granted sheaves of wheat like sand, buildings that approach heaven, and grain heaps like mountains.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Iconic for the New Kingdom of Egypt, Ramses’s reign is marked not by anything distinctive but by a series of exemplary moments – military conquests, monumental architecture, etc. Here is the arrogance and might of the pharaoh made flesh.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Many of our leaders come from obscurity to greatness. Pachacuti was the second son of a royal dynasty and was never intended to lead the Inca. Cleopatra was the subject of a foreign kingdom that rose into rebellion. Not so with Ramses, the son of Seti.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>While Seti’s family was not originally royal, they emerged in the wake of the social and religious upheaval of Akhenaten, who sought to create a new religious order and under whose rule (and subsequent rule of Tutankhamun), Egypt’s foreign borders declined. Seti sought to correct this – expanding Egyptian power to conquer the Anatolian Hittites and re-establishing Egypt as a far-flung empire whose borders extended far beyond the Nile. Ramses showed promise early, and his father appointed him as regent at the age of ten. Seti’s reconsolidation of Egyptian power was outward-looking in other ways, incorporating Syrian deities into the thought-to-be monolithic and conservative Egyptian state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>In his early years, Ramses sent warriors to subdue Syria, Libya, and the Hittites and, in a brilliant strategical maneuver against Sardinian pirates, captured the entirety of the rebel fleet by allowing them certain victories that lulled them into complacency. Another significant point in his expansion was the Battle of Kadesh (in Syria), where an overextended Egyptian force, personally led by the pharaoh, captured a Hittite city but then was forced to retreat. What might have been a demoralizing defeat turned into victory, as the Egyptians used the time to rethink their strategies and push the war to a draw. The resultant peace treaty became the balance of power in the region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>At home, Ramses embarked on a construction spree, most notably the temples at Ramesseum and Abu Simbel, ensuring that his name – often under its Greek version, Ozymandias – lived through the ages.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Ramses died well into his nineties, giving Egypt nearly seven decades with him on the throne. His name is now synonymous with Egyptian power, arrogance, and might (rightly or wrongly).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Who says that wonders are their own reward? So it is with Ramses, who gets large amounts of [Icon_Culture] Culture for completing wonders and a small amount for finishing buildings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_RAMSES_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>With a nice river start, Egypt gains bonuses towards wonders and districts. Wonders are a great source of [Icon_Culture] Culture with Ramses’ Abu Simbel ability that gives 30% of the construction cost as [Icon_Culture] Culture. The Sphinx then gives even more [Icon_Culture] Culture if placed adjacent to these Wonders. The Maryannu Chariot Archer will protect Egypt while they focus on construction, leading to a Culture Victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_TITLE">
			<Text>Sundiata Keita</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_QUOTE">
			<Text>But never try to pierce the mystery which Mali hides from you. Do not go into the dead cities to question the past, for the spirits never forgive. Do not seek to know what is not to be known.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Malian Empire arose from the ashes of Ghana (Wagadou). Mali existed as a small state on the edges of the Sahel, that arid region at the southern fringe of the Sahara. But as Wagadou collapsed, these smaller powers saw their chance. And, for Mali, around 1230, it was Sundiata Keita, the Lion of Mali, on whose shoulders this burden fell.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>According to the Epic of Sundiata, the Lion’s origins were not auspicious. His mother, Sogolon, was a commoner unflatteringly called “the buffalo woman.” But this was part of the point; according to prophecy, if the Mande king Nare Maghann Konate married such a person, she would bear a great king.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Sundiata was, in this way, born to Konate and Sogolon. He was not well-liked – he acquired his looks from his mother, and, further, his physical condition was such that he was unable to walk throughout much of his childhood. Sundiata struggled as a young man against his condition as well as against the resentment of his half-brother, born of a fully noble line. He struggled to walk, breaking the iron rods that blacksmiths had forged for him, and only through the steady command of his mother (or, in some tellings, the strength of a baobab tree) he forced himself to move.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>But family struggles proved worse – upon the death of his father, Sundiata and Sogolon were exiled and wandered the Sahel seeking shelter. All tribes cast them out, except for one, the Mema kingdom. With shelter there, Sundiata learned to hunt and fight, and proved his worth.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>In his absence, things were developing in the region. Soumaoro Kante, a sorcerer-king, had arisen and began conquering the remnants of Wagadou. In fear, the Malian people sought for their exiled, prophesied king, and found him – it should be noted that the young king was only 18 at the time! Sundiata returned to Mali, united the scattered kingdoms, and defeated the sorcerer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>This story, recorded in the “Epic of Sundiata”, has its biases. Later writings and tellings come mostly from Muslim sources and would be eager to cast any ruler following indigenous religions as a cruel and wicked sorcerer. Sundiata, in these stories, is a righteous Muslim king who founds a Muslim dynasty. But most Malians at Sundiata’s time were not Muslim, and his own religion was likely not Islam, though in just a generation or two, most of Mali’s elites were. Indeed, the explorer Ibn Battuta complains about the unorthodox practices at the Malian court nearly a hundred years later, though he notes that the nobles are all of the faith.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Mali under Mansa [king] Sundiata was not of the extent and richness it would become under Musa, his great-nephew. Nonetheless, Sundiata created a federated monarchy in West Africa, where various vassal kingdoms would send representatives to speak for their people. It was the beginnings of the successors to Wagadou, successors that would include Mali itself, Songhai, and others.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Mansa Sundiata died young, likely during a failed river crossing. His tomb is hidden, as are all tombs of the Malian kings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Sundiata Keita’s wealth is not as great as his descendant, but it is still large enough to compete with Russia’s quest for Great Writers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SUNDIATA_KEITA_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>The two things Sundiata Keita is best at are [ICON_Gold] Gold and [ICON_GreatWork_Writing] Great Works of Writing. Mali’s Songs of the Jeli hurts his [ICON_Production] Production, but gives back in [ICON_Gold] Gold generation. He receives even more [ICON_Gold] Gold from the Suguba’s adjacency bonuses and Mandekalu Cavalry’s [ICON_Gold] Gold from kills. Sundiata Keita’s epic ability to purchase Great People cheaper is best focused on purchasing Great Writers who can create even more powerful [ICON_GreatWork_Writing] Great Works of Writing. Culture Victory is the best purchase Sundiata Keita can make.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_CLEOPATRA_TITLE">
			<Text>Cleopatra (Egyptian)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_CLEOPATRA_ALT_TITLE">
			<Text>Cleopatra (Ptolemaic)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_CLEOPATRA_ALT_QUOTE">
			<Text>All strange and terrible events are welcome, but comforts we despise.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_CLEOPATRA_ALT_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>[ICON_FOOD] Food and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture flow down the great Nile River while playing as Ptolemaic Cleopatra.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_CLEOPATRA_ALT_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Make sure you settle cities with lots of Rivers and Floodplains when playing as Ptolemaic Cleopatra. Settling next to rivers with her leading Egypt provide everything a civilization that stands the test of time needs: [ICON_Production] Production, [ICON_Culture] Culture, [ICON_Food] Food, and Appeal. The Iteru ability gives [ICON_Production] Production and protection from Floods on these river-adjacent cities as well. Her leader ability gives [ICON_Culture] Culture, Appeal, and [ICON_FOOD] Food for river cities. Even more [ICON_Culture] Culture for river cities is found if you can solve the riddle of the Sphinx (that is to say, by constructing them). Culture Victory is Cleopatra’s main focus with [ICON_Culture] Culture coming from the Sphinx and her leader ability.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
