<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Apocalipse</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Boas-vindas</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Na configuração de partida, os jogadores podem ativar o modo de jogo Apocalipse, alterando a gravidade dos desastres, introduzindo uma nova Competição Pontuada e unidade, e testemunhando o fim do mundo, com os planetas e civilizações atingidos por cometas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Vidente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O modo de jogo Apocalipse introduz uma nova unidade, o Vidente. Essa unidade tem a habilidade exclusiva de causar desastres naturais: leve-o para um local adequado e use a ação Causar Desastre para iniciar uma inundação, tempestade, incêndio ou erupção vulcânica nos painéis próximos. Isso gera uma pequena quantia de CO2 que acelera as mudanças climáticas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Videntes só podem ser comprados com [ICON_Faith] fé e podem ser escoltados. A cada promoção, eles ganham mais cargas para causar desastres. Videntes não ganham experiência; em vez disso, eles desbloqueiam novas promoções por meio de uma nova Competição Pontuada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Acalmando os Deuses</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Para ganhar promoções para seus Videntes, você terá de participar da competição pontuada Acalmar os Deuses. Ela aparecerá durante o jogo, dando-lhe a capacidade de usar seus Videntes para sacrificar suas unidades de combate perto de vulcões e ganhar pontos. Jogadores com altas pontuações ganham promoções para todos os seus Videntes atuais e futuros. Sacrificar as unidades gera uma pequena quantia de CO2 que acelera as mudanças climáticas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Novos Desastres</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Dois novos desastres são exclusivos do modo de jogo Apocalipse: [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Erupções Solares: ao redor do mundo, a radiação solar bombardeia o planeta, causando dano a edificações e melhorias de energia, pilhando certos distritos e causando dano a unidades de final de jogo [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Colisões de Cometa: um cometa cai no planeta destruindo tudo em seu caminho, até mesmo cidades</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Fim do Mundo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Desastres terríveis e de alto dano, especialmente Colisões de Cometa, ficam mais frequentes depois que a Mudança Climática atinge seu nível máximo. Nesse momento, os jogadores terão que vencer rapidamente, ou o fim do mundo decidirá o vencedor por eles.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Erupções Solares</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Erupções Solares afetam o mapa inteiro. No momento em que são iniciadas, elas destroem edificações de usina de [ICON_POWER] energia, e podem causar danos a melhorias e unidades avançadas, edificações de [ICON_POWER] energia e distritos de Campus, Zona Industrial e Espaçoporto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Colisões de Cometa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Colisões de Cometa afetam quatro painéis adjacentes ou Centros da Cidade, eliminando tudo em seu caminho e tornando os painéis intransponíveis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Em épocas de crise, as pessoas costumam recorrer a quem promete alguma forma de libertação. Quando há um rompimento da ordem natural, política ou econômica, surgem videntes que podem fornecer às pessoas uma forma de afastar o desastre, sobreviver ou infligir um em seus inimigos. Embora a unidade Vidente não seja feita para refletir alguma cultura ou fato histórico em particular, podemos encontrar momentos semelhantes de protagonismo dessas figuras em diversas épocas e lugares, desde a reação dos mesoamericanos à chegada dos espanhóis, até as seitas milenaristas europeias e grupos atuais como o Heaven's Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Por exemplo, na virada do século XX, em regiões de língua laosiana do Sudeste Asiático, surgiram novos profetas, os "homens sagrados". Eles declararam ao povo laosiano (que havia visto seu território ser dividido entre forças francesas e siamesas, novos sistemas de tributação e a destruição da cidade de Vientiane) que ocorreriam coisas piores. Vacas e porcos se transformariam em demônios. O dinheiro perderia todo o seu valor, enquanto o cascalho se transformaria em ouro. Um grande vento varreria a terra e levaria consigo todos que não conseguissem se agarrar a uma moita de capim-limão. Muitos acreditavam nesses videntes, coletando cascalho e matando seus próprios animais, todos aguardando a grande mudança que estava por vir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Videntes raramente acabam bem. O movimento laosiano foi reprimido pelas tropas do Sião, as orações astecas não detiveram a conquista espanhola, e o fim dos tempos aparentemente nunca chega.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os videntes muitas vezes diziam ter comunicação direta com o mundo divino. Alguns eram inspirados por sonhos sagrados, como os "homens sagrados" dos laosianos; alguns diziam ter textos divinos dados pelos deuses, como o ocultista do século XX Aleister Crowley; já outros diziam até mesmo serem parentes de figuras divinas, como Hong Xiuquan, líder da Rebelião Taiping, que afirmava ser irmão de Jesus Cristo. Mas todos tinham alguma mensagem do além que diziam ser compelidos a entregar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Um inquisidor é simplesmente quem faz uma pergunta. Porém, desde a Inquisição Espanhola, o termo ficou associado aos que buscam descobrir crenças heréticas e eliminá-las. Se alguém possui uma mensagem sagrada, consequentemente é preciso eliminar as mensagens discordantes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Uma semelhança entre esses diversos movimentos apocalípticos é seu fanatismo. Para realizar as ações que esses grupos exigem, e para fazer os sacrifícios costumeiros, os devotos dos grupos apocalípticos são unidos em sua fé. Essa é uma das características que os torna tão convincentes... e assustadores.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Grupos apocalípticos costumavam ter uma oração secreta, e os videntes prometiam que entoá-la traria proteção. Podiam ser nomes secretos de Deus, o chamado repetitivo de uma "terra pura", ou algo em um idioma tão secreto que nem o vidente compreendia.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Grupos que esperam pelo fim dos tempos às vezes tomam medidas para precipitar esse fim. A praga foi usada como arma biológica na Idade Média, notavelmente durante o cerco a Caffa, em que as tropas invasoras lançaram corpos infectados na cidade, causando um surto. Mas não precisamos voltar tanto: em 1995, a seita apocalíptica Aum Shinrikyo buscou trazer uma nova era quando atacou o metrô de Tóquio com gás sarin. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Em 1908, S. Semenov estava no entreposto comercial de Vanavara quando, segundo ele, "o céu se dividiu em dois e um fogo surgiu alto e amplo sobre a floresta". O calor do verão ficou insuportável, e então "o céu se fechou... depois se ouviu um ruído, como queda de pedras ou disparo de canhões... um vento quente bateu nas casas, como de canhões, e deixou rastros no chão como estradas". O que Semenov viu foi o evento de Tunguska, uma explosão com milhares de vezes o poder de uma bomba atômica, causado pelo impacto de um fragmento de cometa, uma bola de gelo de aproximadamente 65 metros de diâmetro, na taiga siberiana. Embora impactos como o evento de Tunguska possam ser tão devastadores quanto uma bomba nuclear, impactos de cometas maiores (de quilômetros, não metros) teriam um efeito catastrófico e exponencial, afetando não só a região, mas o mundo inteiro. Os seres próximos ao impacto queimariam, e o cometa lançaria poeira na atmosfera, bloqueando a luz do sol, resfriando o clima e matando a vegetação (criando combustível para imensos incêndios florestais) no mundo inteiro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Acalmar os deuses</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nosso mundo se virou contra nós! Com o Modo Apocalipse ativado, secas, tempestades, enchentes e erupções vulcânicas ficam mais frequentes e mais perigosas. Por sorte, você pode treinar um Vidente, que pode virar essas calamidades contra seus inimigos. Fique de olho no clima; com um último aumento de temperatura, o mundo entrará no Apocalipse, e desastres ocorrerão a cada turno!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Um raio ou um erro humano causou um incêndio florestal! As chamas vão se disseminar para qualquer Floresta ou Selva adjacente. Embora a fumaça cause problemas, as cinzas são um bom fertilizante... depois que as chamas se apagarem, claro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Caíram meteoros do céu! Vamos ver o que trouxeram consigo. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Um cometa atingiu a Terra! Colisões de Cometa destroem tudo que atingem.[NEWLINE]'Desde o começo, nada durou.'</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O mundo está sendo atingido por uma Erupção Solar, causando danos a todos os nossos equipamentos elétricos. Foram danificadas nossas edificações e melhorias de geração de Energia, e até mesmo nossas unidades que usam eletricidade!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Videntes agora estão disponíveis para nós por meio de fé. Videntes podem atrair desastres para seus inimigos. Competindo com outras civilizações, você pode aumentar o poder deles sacrificando suas unidades de combate para vulcões.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O mundo está acabando! Desastres estão ocorrendo numa escala jamais vista! Consiga logo a vitória antes que você seja destruído!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>"Os deuses nos avisaram: o fim do mundo está próximo. Eles concederão bênçãos aos seus seguidores, mas antes devemos provar nossa devoção. Somente os mais zelosos serão recompensados."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os deuses nos avisaram que o fim está próximo. Eles concederão bênçãos aos seus seguidores, mas antes devemos provar nossa devoção. Somente os mais zelosos serão recompensados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os deuses nos avisaram que o fim está próximo. Eles concederão bênçãos aos seus seguidores, mas antes devemos provar nossa devoção. Somente os mais zelosos serão recompensados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Usando a ação "Sacrificar unidade adjacente" com sua unidade Vidente, recebe uma pontuação igual à [ICON_Strength] força de combate da unidade sacrificada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Unidades Videntes dos membros podem usar a ação "Sacrificar unidade adjacente" em unidades amigáveis adjacentes a vulcões ativos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>1 unidade Vidente gratuita</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>1 promoção aleatória gratuita para todas as unidades Videntes presentes e futuras</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+2 de [ICON_Faith] fé por turno.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Deve estar adjacente a uma unidade de combate aliada adjacente a um vulcão ativo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Deve estar em um painel que possa ser afetado por um desastre natural.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>É preciso estar em guerra com o jogador proprietário para causar um desastre em território estrangeiro</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Causar Desastre</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sacrificar Unidade Adjacente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+1 carga, +2 de [ICON_Movement] movimento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+1 carga, ganha furtividade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+2 cargas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+1 carga. As unidades adjacentes recebem +5 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+1 carga. As cidades inimigas adjacentes são automaticamente cercadas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>As cidades inimigas adjacentes são automaticamente cercadas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+5 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate de Vidente adjacente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+5 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate de Vidente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Vidente</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Mensageiro</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Inquisidor</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Fanático</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Encantamento</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Portador da Praga</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Apocalypse</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Bienvenue</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Lors de la configuration de la partie, vous pouvez activer le mode Apocalypse, ce qui modifie la gravité des catastrophes naturelles, ajoute un nouveau type de compétition et une unité, et finit par déclencher la fin du monde, en martelant la planète et ses civilisations de comètes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Devin</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le mode Apocalypse ajoute une nouvelle unité, le devin, qui possède une capacité unique : provoquer des catastrophes naturelles. Placez-le à l'endroit souhaité, puis utilisez l'action "Provoquer une catastrophe" pour déclencher une inondation, une tempête, un incendie ou une éruption volcanique dans les cases adjacentes. Ceci génère une petite quantité de CO2 qui contribue au changement climatique.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les devins peuvent uniquement être achetés avec de la [ICON_Faith] foi, peuvent être escortés. À chaque nouvelle promotion, ils obtiennent plus de charges lorsqu'ils provoquent des catastrophes naturelles. Les devins ne gagnent pas d'expérience, mais obtiennent des promotions via une nouvelle compétition.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Apaiser les dieux</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Pour promouvoir vos devins, vous devrez participer à la compétition Apaiser les dieux. Celle-ci apparaîtra tout au long de la partie, et sera l'occasion d'utiliser vos devins pour sacrifier vos autres unités militaires près d'un volcan, et marquer des points. Les joueurs au score élevé obtiendront des promotions pour tous leurs devins actuels et futurs. Le sacrifice d'unités génère une petite quantité de CO2 qui contribue au changement climatique.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Nouvelles catastrophes naturelles</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Deux nouvelles catastrophes naturelles surviennent uniquement en mode Apocalypse : [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Éruptions solaires : des radiations solaires bombardent la planète, endommageant les bâtiments et aménagements fournissant de l'énergie, pillant certains quartiers et endommageant les unités avancées.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Chutes de comètes : une comète s'écrase sur la planète, détruisant tout sur son passage, y compris les villes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Fin du monde</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les catastrophes naturelles dévastatrices (surtout les chutes de comètes) deviennent plus fréquentes lorsque le changement climatique atteint son niveau maximum. Dès lors, les joueurs devront l'emporter rapidement, ou la fin du monde décidera du vainqueur à leur place.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Éruptions solaires</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les éruptions solaires affectent la totalité de la carte. Au tour où elles surviennent, elles détruisent les [ICON_POWER] centrales électriques et peuvent endommager les unités avancées, les aménagements (y compris ceux produisant de l'[ICON_Power] électricité), les campus, les zones industrielles et les spatioports.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Chutes de comètes</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les chutes de comètes affectent 4 cases adjacentes, ou ciblent des centres-villes, et les rendent infranchissables en anéantissant tout ce qui s'y trouve.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Par temps de crise, les gens se tournent vers ceux qui leur promettent une forme de délivrance. Lorsque l'ordre naturel, politique ou économique s'effondre, les devins émergent, promettant au peuple des moyens de repousser la catastrophe, d'y survivre, ou de la faire s'abattre sur ses ennemis. Bien qu'ici, l'unité de devins ne reflète pas de culture ou d'événement historique en particulier, on peut trouver un intérêt pour de telles figures à travers le monde et l'Histoire, qu'il s'agisse par exemple de la réaction des Mésoaméricains à l'arrivée des Espagnols, des sectes millénaristes européennes, ou encore du culte actuel de Heaven's Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Par exemple, au tournant du XXe siècle, au sein des contrées parlant le lao dans l'Asie du Sud-est, de nouveaux prophètes apparurent, les "hommes saints". Ils promirent aux Lao, dont le territoire avait été divisé entre les forces françaises et siamoises et qui avaient été témoins de l'apparition de nouvelles taxes et de la destruction de Vientiane, que le pire était encore à venir. Les vaches et les porcs se transformeraient en démons, l'argent perdrait sa valeur tandis que les gravats deviendraient de l'or. Un vent terrible soufflerait à travers le pays et emporterait quiconque ne s'agripperait pas à une touffe de citronnelle. Nombreux furent ceux qui crurent ces devins et se mirent à collecter du gravier et abattre leurs propres animaux dans l'attente du grand changement à venir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les présages des devins sont rarement de bon augure. Le mouvement Lao fut éradiqué par les troupes siamoises, les prières des Aztèques n'arrêtèrent pas les Conquistadors, et apparemment, la fin des temps n'arriva jamais.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les devins prétendent souvent être en communication directe avec les dieux. Certains puisent l'inspiration dans des rêves sacrés, comme les hommes saints des Lao, d'autres assurent posséder des textes donnés par les divinités, comme l'occultiste Aleister Crowley au début du XXe siècle. Certains ont même déclaré avoir une ascendance divine, comme Hong Xiuquan, le meneur de la révolte des Taiping, qui prétendait être le frère de Jésus-Christ. Tous, cependant, portent un message venu d'ailleurs qu'ils se croient en devoir de répandre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>À l'origine, un inquisiteur est simplement une personne qui pose une question. Mais avec l'Inquisition espagnole, le terme a été associé à ceux qui traquaient les croyances hérétiques pour les éradiquer. Lorsque l'on porte un message sacré, on doit par conséquent éliminer les messages rivaux.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les sectes apocalyptiques, bien que disparates, partagent un point commun : le fanatisme. Afin de commettre les actes demandés par ces groupes et effectuer les sacrifices inhérents, les disciples de ces cultes s'unissent autour de leur foi. C'est l'un des aspects qui les rend si convaincants… et si terrifiants.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les sectes apocalyptiques disposent souvent d'une prière secrète qui, selon les devins, protège celui qui la psalmodie. Il peut s'agir des noms secrets de Dieu, de l'incantation d'une "terre pure", ou d'un langage si mystérieux que même les devins sont incapables de le comprendre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les sectes anticipant la fin des temps prennent parfois des mesures pour la précipiter. Ainsi, la peste fut utilisée comme arme biologique à l'époque médiévale, particulièrement lors du siège de Caffa, durant lequel les assaillants jetèrent des cadavres infectés dans la ville, provoquant une épidémie. Mais nul besoin de remonter aussi loin : plus récemment, en 1995, la secte apocalyptique d'Aum Shinrikyo prétendit ouvrir une nouvelle ère lorsqu'elle lança une attaque au gaz sarin dans le métro de Tokyo. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>En 1908, S. Semenov était assis devant le poste de commerce de Vanavara lorsque, comme il le décrivit plus tard, il vit "le ciel se fendre en deux", puis "s'embraser très haut au-dessus de la forêt". La chaleur de cette journée d'été devint brusquement intolérable, puis "le ciel se referma et un terrible fracas retentit, semblable à un éboulement ou au tir de canons… un vent brûlant courut entre les maisons, comme le souffle des canons, et traça des sillons sur le sol". Ce que S. Semenov venait de vivre fut plus tard nommé "l'événement de la Toungouska", une explosion d'une puissance d'un millier de bombes atomiques, causée par l'impact d'un fragment de comète. Cette boule de glace de près de 65 mètres de diamètre venait de heurter la taïga sibérienne. Si des incidents comme celui de la Toungouska peuvent s'avérer aussi dévastateurs qu'une arme nucléaire, les chutes de débris plus larges (aux diamètres de plusieurs kilomètres) pourraient avoir des effets catastrophiques exponentiels susceptibles d'affecter le monde entier. Toute vie à proximité de l'impact serait balayée, puis la comète projetterait un nuage de poussière dans l'atmosphère suffisamment important pour bloquer la lumière du soleil, refroidir le climat et tuer la végétation (ce qui entraînerait, entre autres, d'immenses feux de forêt).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Apaiser les dieux</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La planète se retourne contre vous ! Quand le mode Apocalypse est activé, sécheresses, tempêtes, inondations et éruptions volcaniques sont plus fréquentes et plus dévastatrices. Heureusement, vous pouvez former un devin capable de diriger ces calamités contre vos adversaires. Gardez un œil sur le climat, car une fois un certain palier de température atteint, l'Apocalypse débutera, et des catastrophes naturelles frapperont à chaque tour !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un feu de forêt s'est déclaré, par la faute de la foudre ou de la négligence humaine ! Les flammes se propageront à toute case de forêt ou jungle adjacente. Si la fumée risque de poser des soucis, les cendres feront un excellent engrais. Une fois l'incendie éteint, bien sûr.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Des météores sont tombés du ciel ! Voyons ce qu'ils recèlent.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une comète a percuté la Terre ! Les chutes de comètes détruisent tout ce qu'elles touchent.[NEWLINE]‘Dès le commencement, rien n'était éternel.’</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le monde subit les effets d'une éruption solaire, qui endommage tous les équipements électriques. Nos bâtiments et aménagements produisant de l'énergie en ont fait les frais, et même nos unités faisant usage d'électricité !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Vous pouvez désormais former des devins grâce à votre foi. Les devins sont capables de déclencher des catastrophes naturelles ciblant vos ennemis. Vous pourrez augmenter leur puissance en vous livrant à une compétition avec les autres civilisations. Pour cela, il vous faudra sacrifier vos unités militaires dans des volcans.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La fin du monde est proche ! Les catastrophes se succèdent à un rythme implacable ! Dépêchez-vous de gagner avant d'être anéanti !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>"Les dieux nous ont prévenus : la fin du monde est proche. Leurs fidèles recevront leur bénédiction, mais nous devons leur montrer notre ferveur. Seuls les plus zélés seront récompensés."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les dieux nous ont prévenus que la fin était proche. Leurs fidèles recevront leur bénédiction, mais nous devons leur montrer notre ferveur. Seuls les plus zélés seront récompensés.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les dieux nous ont prévenus que la fin était proche. Leurs fidèles recevront leur bénédiction, mais nous devons leur montrer notre ferveur. Seuls les plus zélés seront récompensés.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'action "Sacrifier l'unité adjacente" des unités de devins fait gagner un score égal à la [ICON_Strength] puissance de combat de l'unité sacrifiée.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les unités de devins des membres peuvent utiliser l'action "Sacrifier l'unité adjacente" sur les unités alliées adjacentes à un volcan en activité.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>1 unité de devins gratuite</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>1 promotion gratuite aléatoire pour les unités de devins actuelles et futures.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Faith] Foi +2 par tour.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Doit être adjacent à une unité militaire alliée adjacente à un volcan actif.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Doit se trouver sur une case pouvant être affectée par une catastrophe naturelle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Doit être en guerre avec le joueur propriétaire pour provoquer une catastrophe sur un territoire étranger.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Provoquer une catastrophe</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Sacrifier l'unité adjacente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Charge +1, [ICON_Movement] PM +2.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Charge +1, obtient la Furtivité.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Charges +2.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Charge +1. [ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +5 pour les unités adjacentes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Charge +1. Les villes ennemies adjacentes sont assiégées.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les villes ennemies adjacentes sont automatiquement assiégées.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +5 pour un devin adjacent.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +5 pour un devin.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Devin|Devins</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Messager|Messagers</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Inquisiteur|Inquisiteurs</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Zélote|Zélotes</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Incantation</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Porteur de Peste|Porteurs de Peste</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Apokalypse</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Willkommen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Beim Spiel-Setup können Spieler den Apokalypse-Spielmodus aktivieren und damit den Schweregrad von Katastrophen verändern, einen neuen punkteorientierten Wettkampf und eine neue Einheit erhalten und letztendlich den Weltuntergang erleben, wenn der Planet und seine Zivilisationen von Kometen ausgelöscht werden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Der Apokalypse-Spielmodus führt eine neue Einheit ein, den Seher. Diese Einheit hat die einzigartige Fähigkeit, Naturkatastrophen auszulösen: Bringt sie an einen passenden Ort und benutzt die Aktion "Katastrophe auslösen", um auf Geländefeldern in der Nähe eine Flut, einen Sturm, Brand oder Vulkanausbruch zu starten. Dadurch wird eine kleine Menge CO2 erzeugt, die den Klimawandel beschleunigt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher können nur mit [ICON_Faith] Glauben gekauft werden und können eskortiert werden. Sie erhalten mit jeder Beförderung weitere Ladungen für das Auslösen von Katastrophen. Seher erhalten keine Erfahrung; stattdessen schalten sie neue Beförderungen durch einen neuen punkteorientierten Wettkampf frei.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Besänftigung der Götter</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Für Beförderungen für Eure Seher müsst Ihr am punkteorientierten Wettkampf "Besänftigung der Götter" teilnehmen. Dieser erscheint im Verlauf des Spiels und verleiht Euch die Fähigkeit, Eure Seher dazu zu benutzen, Kampfeinheiten in der Nähe von Vulkanen für Punkte zu opfern. Spieler mit vielen Punkten erhalten Beförderungen für alle ihre aktuellen und zukünftigen Seher. Durch das Opfern von Einheiten wird eine kleine Menge CO2 erzeugt, die den Klimawandel beschleunigt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Neue Katastrophen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zwei neue Katastrophen gibt es nur im Apokalypse-Spielmodus: [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Sonneneruptionen: Die ganze Welt wird von Sonnenstrahlung bombardiert, die energiebezogene Gebäude und Modernisierungen beschädigt, bestimmte Bezirke plündert und Einheiten im späten Spiel Schaden zufügt. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Kometeneinschläge: Ein Komet stürzt auf den Planeten und zerstört alles in seiner Bahn, selbst Städte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Weltuntergang</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Schreckliche Katastrophen mit hohem Schaden, insbesondere Kometeneinschläge, treten häufiger auf, nachdem der Klimawandel die höchste Stufe erreicht hat. Ab diesem Zeitpunkt müssen Spieler schnell gewinnen oder der Weltuntergang entscheidet den Sieger für sie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sonneneruptionen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sonneneruptionen betreffen die gesamte Karte. In der Runde, in der sie ausgelöst werden, zerstören sie [ICON_POWER] Kraftwerke und können fortschrittlichen Einheiten und Modernisierungen, [ICON_POWER] energiebezogenen Gebäuden sowie Campus-, Industriegebiet- und Raumhafen-Bezirken Schaden zufügen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kometeneinschläge</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kometeneinschläge wirken sich auf vier angrenzende Geländefelder aus oder treffen Stadtzentren. Sie vernichten alles und machen das Geländefeld unpassierbar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>In Krisenzeiten haben sich Menschen schon immer an jene gewandt, die irgendeine Form von Erlösung versprachen. Immer, wenn die natürliche, politische oder wirtschaftliche Ordnung zusammenbricht, treten Seher auf den Plan, die den Menschen eine Möglichkeit verheißen, Katastrophen abzuwenden, sie zu überleben oder sie über die eigenen Feinde zu bringen. Die Seher-Einheit im Spiel ist mit keinem bestimmten kulturellen oder historischen Moment verknüpft, dennoch lässt sich überall auf der Welt und in der gesamten Geschichte eine vergleichbare Zuwendung in Richtung solcher Figuren erkennen, von der mesoamerikanischen Reaktion auf die Ankunft der Spanier über europäische Jahrtausendkulte bis hin zu heutigen Gruppierungen wie Heaven's Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>So erhoben sich an der Schwelle des 20. Jahrhunderts in den laotischsprachigen Teilen Südostasiens zum Beispiel neue Propheten, die "Heiligen Männer". Sie prophezeiten den Lao, die die Aufteilung ihres Lands zwischen französischen und siamesischen Streitkräften, neue Steuersysteme und die Zerstörung der Stadt Vientiane miterlebt hatten, dass ihnen noch schlimmere Dinge bevorstanden. Kühe und Schweine sollten sich zu Dämonen wandeln, Geld seinen Wert verlieren und wertloser Kiesel zu Gold werden. Ein starker Sturm sollte durch das Land fegen und alle mit sich reißen, die sich nicht an einem Büschel Zitronengras festhalten konnten. Viele glaubten diesen Sehern, sammelten Kiesel und töteten ihre Tiere, während sie auf die bevorstehende große Veränderung warteten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher finden selten ein gutes Ende. Die Lao-Bewegung wurde von der siamesischen Armee unterdrückt, die Prediger der Azteken konnten den spanischen Eroberern keinen Einhalt gebieten und das Ende der Welt scheint nie zu kommen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher taten oft so, als stünden sie in direktem Kontakt mit den Göttern. Manche wurden von heiligen Träumen inspiriert, wie die "Heiligen Männer" der Lao; andere behaupteten, göttliche Schriften von den Göttern selbst erhalten zu haben, wie der Okkultist Aleister Crowley zu Beginn des 20. Jahrhunderts; und manche behaupteten sogar, mit göttlichen Figuren verwandt zu sein, wie zum Beispiel Hong Xiuquan, der Anführer des Taiping-Aufstands, der sich als Bruder von Jesus Christus ausgab. Allen gemein ist, dass sie eine Botschaft von einem überirdischen Ort hatten, die sie verbreiten wollten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Inquisitor ist per Definition jemand, der eine Frage stellt. Seit der Spanischen Inquisition ist der Begriff jedoch mit jenen verbunden, die Häretiker jagten und hinrichteten. Wer meint, eine heilige Botschaft zu kennen, muss alle gegenteiligen Botschaften bekämpfen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine Sache, die selbst unvereinbare apokalyptische Bewegungen miteinander gemein haben, ist ihr Glaubensfanatismus. Um die von ihnen verlangten Opfer und Taten zu erbringen, werden die Anhänger solcher apokalyptischen Gruppierungen in ihrem Glauben vereint. Genau das macht sie so überzeugend ... und furchteinflößend.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Apokalyptische Gruppen hatten meist ein geheimes Gebet und Seher versprachen Schutz, wenn man es aufsagte. Dies konnten geheime Namen für Gott sein, die wiederholte Anrufung eines "reinen Lands" oder etwas in einer Sprache, die so geheim war, dass nicht mal die Seher sie verstanden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Gruppen, die die Endzeit vorhersehen, unternehmen manchmal Handlungen, um sie herbeizuführen. So wurde die Pest im Mittelalter als biologische Waffe benutzt, allen voran bei der Belagerung von Kaffa, als die Belagerungstruppen infizierte Leichen in die Stadt schleuderten und einen Ausbruch verursachten. Wir müssen jedoch gar nicht so weit zurückgehen; erst 1995 wollte die Endzeitsekte Ōmu Shinrikyō mit einem Saringas-Anschlag auf die Tokioter U-Bahn ein neues Zeitalter herbeiführen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Im Jahr 1908 saß S. Semenov in der Handelsstation Wanawara, als laut seiner Aussage "der Himmel entzwei brach und hoch über den Wäldern in Flammen zu stehen schien". Der Sommertag wurde unerträglich heiß, dann "schloss sich der Himmel ... und es gab ein Geräusch, das so klang, als würden Steine herabfallen oder Kanonen abgefeuert ... Heißer Wind wie von Kanonen fegte zwischen den Häusern hindurch und hinterließ Spuren am Boden". Semenov war Zeuge des Tunguska-Ereignisses - einer Explosion, die mehrere tausendmal so stark war wie die einer Atombombe, verursacht durch den Einschlag eines Kometenfragments aus Eis mit einem Durchmesser von etwa 65 Metern in der sibirischen Taiga. Ereignisse wie das von Tunguska können zwar so verheerend sein wie eine nukleare Explosion, Einschläge größerer Kometen - in der Größenordnung mehrerer Kilometer - könnten jedoch nicht nur für die Region, sondern für den ganzen Planeten katastrophale Folgen haben. In der Nähe des Einschlags käme es zum Brand, doch der Komet würde auch Staub in die Atmosphäre schleudern, der das Sonnenlicht blockieren, das Klima abkühlen und die Vegetation weltweit töten würde (wodurch sich das Feuer weiter ausbreiten könnte).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Besänftigung der Götter|Besänftigung der Götter|Besänftigung der Götter|Besänftigung der Götter|Besänftigung der Götter</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Unsere Welt hat sich gegen uns gewandt! Im Apokalypse-Modus treten Dürren, Stürme, Überflutungen und Vulkanausbrüche häufiger und heftiger auf. Zum Glück könnt Ihr einen Seher ausbilden, der diese Unglücksfälle möglicherweise auf Eure Feinde lenken kann. Behaltet das Klima im Auge, denn wenn die Temperatur weiter steigt, beginnt die Apokalypse mit ihren nie enden wollenden Katastrophen!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Blitzschlag oder menschliches Fehlverhalten hat einen Waldbrand ausgelöst! Die Flammen werden sich auf angrenzende Wald- und Regenwald-Geländefelder ausbreiten. Der Rauch wird uns zwar beeinträchtigen, aber die Asche düngt den Boden, nachdem der Brand erloschen ist.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Meteore sind vom Himmel gefallen! Lasst uns nachsehen, ob sie uns Interessantes gebracht haben.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Komet hat die Erde getroffen! Im Einschlaggebiet wurde alles zerstört. [NEWLINE]'Und so ist von Anfang an alles vergangen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Welt ist von einer Sonneneruption betroffen, die jegliche Elektrik stört. Unsere Energiegebäude und -Modernisierungen und selbst unsere elektrizitätsnutzenden Einheiten wurden beschädigt!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wir können nun durch Glauben Seher erhalten. Seher können Naturkatastrophen gegen Eure Feinde entfesseln. Im Wettkampf mit anderen Zivilisationen könnt Ihr sie noch stärker machen, indem Ihr eigene Kampfeinheiten in Vulkanen opfert.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Das Ende der Welt ist nah! Katastrophen von ungeahntem Ausmaß brechen über uns herein! Erringt den Sieg, bevor Ihr vernichtet werdet!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>"Die Götter haben uns vor dem nahenden Ende der Welt gewarnt. Sie werden ihren Anhängern Segen spenden, doch zuerst müssen wir unseren Eifer beweisen. Nur die Eifrigsten werden belohnt."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Götter haben uns vor dem nahenden Ende gewarnt. Sie werden ihren Anhängern Segen spenden, doch zuerst müssen wir unseren Eifer beweisen. Nur die Eifrigsten werden belohnt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Götter haben uns vor dem nahenden Ende gewarnt. Sie werden ihren Anhängern Segen spenden, doch zuerst müssen wir unseren Eifer beweisen. Nur die Eifrigsten werden belohnt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Verwendung der Aktion "Angrenzende Einheit opfern" mit ihrer Seher-Einheit bringt Punkte in Höhe der [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke der geopferten Einheit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher-Einheiten von Mitgliedern können die Aktion "Angrenzende Einheit opfern" auf verbündete Einheiten anwenden, die an aktive Vulkane angrenzen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>1 kostenlose Seher-Einheit</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>1 zufällige Gratis-Beförderung für alle aktuellen und zukünftigen Seher-Einheiten</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+2 [ICON_Faith] Glauben pro Runde</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Muss an eine freundlich gesinnte Kampfeinheit angrenzen, die wiederum an einen aktiven Vulkan angrenzt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Muss auf einem Geländefeld sein, das von einer Naturkatastrophe betroffen sein kann.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Muss im Krieg bei dem Besitzer sein, um eine Katastrophe in fremdem Gebiet auszulösen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Katastrophe auslösen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Angrenzende Einheit opfern</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+1 Ladung, +2 [ICON_Movement] Fortbewegung.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+1 Ladung, erhält Tarnung.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+2 Ladungen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+1 Ladung. Angrenzende Einheiten erhalten +5 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+1 Ladung. Angrenzende feindliche Städte werden automatisch belagert.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Angrenzende feindliche Städte werden automatisch belagert.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+5 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke durch angrenzenden Seher.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+5 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke durch Seher.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seher</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Bote</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Inquisitor</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eiferer</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Beschwörung</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seuchenbringer</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Apocalisse</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Benvenuti</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>In fase di impostazione della partita i giocatori possono attivare la modalità di gioco Apocalisse che aumenta la gravità dei disastri e introduce una nuova competizione a punti e una nuova unità. Inoltre la fine del mondo si presenta anticipatamente, sotto forma di una pioggia di comete che si abbatte sulla superficie spazzando via le varie civiltà.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Veggente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La modalità di gioco Apocalisse introduce una nuova unità, il Veggente. Quest'unità ha la capacità esclusiva di causare disastri naturali: se si trova in posizione corretta, l'azione Causa disastro può dare il via a un'inondazione, una tempesta, un incendio o un'eruzione vulcanica nelle caselle vicine. Questo produce una piccola quantità di CO2 che accelera il cambiamento climatico.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I Veggenti si possono solo acquistare in cambio di [ICON_Faith] Fede e possono essere scortati da altre unità. Con ogni promozione ottengono nuove Cariche che possono utilizzare per scatenare disastri. I Veggenti non accumulano esperienza, ma ottengono promozioni unicamente attraverso un nuovo tipo di competizione a punti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Placare gli Dei</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Per guadagnare promozioni per i tuoi Veggenti devi partecipare a una competizione a punti Placare gli Dei. Queste competizioni si terranno a intervalli regolari nel corso della partita, dandoti la possibilità di usare i Veggenti per sacrificare unità militari in prossimità dei vulcani in cambio di punti. I giocatori che ottengono il punteggio più alto guadagnano promozioni per tutti i loro Veggenti presenti e futuri. Sacrificare unità produce una piccola quantità di CO2 che accelera il cambiamento climatico.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Nuovi disastri</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La modalità Apocalisse introduce due nuovi disastri esclusivi: [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Eruzioni solari: le radiazioni del sole bombardano l'intero globo, danneggiando edifici e miglioramenti legati all'Energia, saccheggiando alcuni distretti e infliggendo danni alle unità più avanzate [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Impatti di comete: una cometa si schianta sul pianeta distruggendo tutto ciò che incontra, comprese le città</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La fine del mondo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Terribili disastri che infliggono danni devastanti, in particolare gli impatti di comete, diventano più frequenti dopo che il cambiamento climatico ha raggiunto il suo livello massimo. A questo punto i giocatori devono vincere rapidamente, o sarà la fine del mondo a decretare il vincitore della partita.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Eruzioni solari</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli effetti delle eruzioni solari si applicano all'intera mappa. Nel turno in cui si verificano, gli edifici [ICON_POWER] Centrale elettrica sono distrutti. Inoltre è possibile che restino danneggiati gli edifici relativi all'[ICON_POWER] Energia, i distretti Zona industriale, Campus e Spazioporto, le unità avanzate e i miglioramenti avanzati.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Impatti di comete</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli impatti delle comete coinvolgono quattro caselle adiacenti o colpiscono i Centri cittadini, spazzando via tutto e rendendo le caselle invalicabili.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Da sempre, in tempi di crisi, la gente si è rivolta a chi promette una qualche forma di liberazione. Quando l'ordine naturale, economico o politico è rovesciato, i veggenti possono fornire alle persone un modo di evitare il disastro, sopravvivergli o rivolgerlo contro i propri nemici. La nostra unità Veggente non intende riflettere una particolare cultura o momento storico, tanto più che figure simili si possono ritrovare in tutto il mondo e in tutti i secoli, dalla reazione mesoamericana dopo l'arrivo degli spagnoli ai culti millenaristi europei, fino a sette moderne come la famosa Heaven's Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>All'inizio del XX secolo, per esempio, nelle regioni del sud-est asiatico che parlavano il linguaggio Lao comparve un nuovo tipo di profeti, gli "uomini santi". Costoro profetizzarono al popolo Lao, che aveva visto il proprio territorio suddiviso tra Francia e Siam, l'introduzione di nuove tasse e la distruzione della città di Vientiane, che presto le cose sarebbero andate ancora peggio. Vacche e maiali si sarebbero trasformati in demoni. Il denaro avrebbe perso tutto il suo valore, mentre la ghiaia si sarebbe trasformata in oro. Un grande vento si sarebbe levato sulla terra e avrebbe portato via chiunque non si fosse tenuto stretto a un ciuffo di citronella. Molti ascoltarono le parole di questi veggenti, raccogliendo ghiaia e uccidendo i propri animali, nell'attesa del grande cambiamento imminente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>È raro che i veggenti facciano una bella fine. Il movimento dei Lao fu represso dalle truppe del Siam, le preghiere azteche non fermarono la conquista spagnola e la fine del mondo, a quanto pare, non arriva mai.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Spesso i veggenti sostenevano di essere in comunicazione diretta con la divinità. Alcuni sarebbero stati ispirati da sogni rivelatori, come gli "uomini santi" Lao; altri sostenevano di possedere testi sacri concessi direttamente dagli dèi, come l'occultista del primo novecento Aleister Crowley; altri ancora dichiaravano di essere loro stessi parenti di qualche figura divina, come Hong Xiuquan, leader della rivolta dei Taiping, che affermava di essere il fratello di Gesù Cristo. Tutti, comunque, erano in possesso di un messaggio soprannaturale che si sentivano in dovere di trasmettere.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un inquisitore, tecnicamente, è semplicemente una persona che fa una domanda. A partire dall'Inquisizione cattolica, però, il termine ha cominciato a fare riferimento a coloro che si dedicano a scoprire ed estirpare credenze definite eretiche. Se una persona ha un messaggio sacro, ne consegue che è suo dovere eliminare i messaggi che si pongono in contrapposizione.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Se c'è una cosa che unisce i più disparati movimenti apocalittici, è il fanatismo: per svolgere le azioni e compiere i sacrifici che questi gruppi richiedono, i loro seguaci devono essere dotati di una fede incrollabile. È questo che li rende tanto convincenti... e terrificanti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Spesso i gruppi che seguono un credo apocalittico hanno una preghiera segreta che, secondo i veggenti, dovrebbe tenere al sicuro i loro membri. La preghiera può contenere una lista di nomi di Dio o un'invocazione ripetuta alla "terra pura", o magari essere scritta in un linguaggio così segreto che neppure i veggenti stessi possono comprendere.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I gruppi che si preparano alla fine del mondo spesso intraprendono azioni volte a provocarla. Nel medioevo la peste era un'arma biologica molto diffusa: resta famoso il caso dell'assedio di Caffa, durante il quale le truppe lanciarono dei corpi infetti dentro la città per causare un'epidemia. Ma non c'è bisogno di andare tanto indietro nel tempo: nel 1995, la setta giapponese di Aum Shinrikyo cercò di provocare l'avvento di una nuova era spargendo gas sarin nella metropolitana di Tokyo. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Nel 1908 S. Semenov era seduto all'esterno della sua casa a Vanavara quando, nelle sue parole, "il cielo si aprì in due e sopra la foresta apparve un'alta, larga colonna di fuoco". Il giorno estivo si fece insopportabilmente caldo, dopodiché "il cielo si richiuse... in seguito arrivò un suono come di macigni caduti, o come se dei cannoni facessero fuoco... un vento caldo spazzò le case, come quello che esce dai cannoni, e lasciò tracce come sentieri sul terreno". Quello a cui Semenov aveva assistito era l'evento di Tunguska, un'esplosione potente come migliaia di bombe atomiche causata dall'impatto nella taiga siberiana di un frammento di cometa, una palla di ghiaccio del diametro di circa 65 metri. Se impatti come quello di Tunguska possono essere devastanti come un'arma nucleare, comete più grandi (dell'ordine di qualche chilometro anziché poche decine di metri) avrebbero un effetto davvero catastrofico, in grado di influenzare non solo la regione, ma il mondo intero. Nelle vicinanze del sito d'impatto tutto resterebbe carbonizzato, ma soprattutto la polvere sollevata in aria bloccherebbe la luce del sole, raffreddando il clima e uccidendo la vegetazione in tutto il mondo (il che a sua volta potrebbe causare giganteschi incendi boschivi).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Placare gli Dei</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il mondo ci si è rivoltato contro! Quando la modalità Apocalisse è attivata, siccità, tempeste, inondazioni ed eruzioni vulcaniche sono più frequenti e più pericolose. Per fortuna puoi addestrare un Veggente per rivolgere queste calamità contro i tuoi nemici. Tieni d'occhio il clima: con un ultimo aumento della temperatura il mondo entrerà nell'Apocalisse e i disastri cominceranno a colpire ogni turno!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un fulmine o un errore umano ha scatenato un incendio in un bosco! Le fiamme si diffonderanno in qualsiasi casella di bosco o giungla adiacente. Il fumo potrebbe causarci qualche problema, ma la cenere sarà un ottimo fertilizzante. Quando le fiamme si saranno spente, ovviamente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sono cadute delle meteore dal cielo! Vediamo un po' cosa possiamo recuperare. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Una cometa ha colpito la Terra! Le comete distruggono tutto quello che colpiscono.[NEWLINE]"Dall'inizio di tutto, nulla è durato."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un'eruzione solare sta influenzando tutti i dispositivi elettrici del mondo. Edifici e miglioramenti che generano Energia sono stati danneggiati, persino le nostre unità ad alimentazione elettrica!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Ora possiamo acquistare dei Veggenti in cambio di Fede. I Veggenti possono scatenare disastri naturali contro i nemici. Attraverso una competizione con le altre civiltà, puoi aumentare il loro potere sacrificando le tue unità militari nei vulcani.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il mondo sta per finire! Stanno per scatenarsi disastri su una scala mai vista! Affrettati a vincere prima che ogni cosa sia distrutta!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>"Gli dèi ci hanno avvertito: la fine del mondo è vicina. Essi doneranno potere ai loro seguaci, ma prima dobbiamo dimostrare la nostra fede. Solo i più fervidi credenti saranno ricompensati."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli dèi ci hanno avvertito che la fine è vicina. Essi doneranno potere ai loro seguaci, ma prima dobbiamo dimostrare la nostra fede. Solo i più devoti saranno ricompensati.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli dèi ci hanno avvertito che la fine è vicina. Essi doneranno potere ai loro seguaci, ma prima dobbiamo dimostrare la nostra fede. Solo i più devoti saranno ricompensati.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Usando l'azione Sacrifica unità adiacente, l'unità Veggente fa guadagnare un numero di punti pari alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento dell'unità sacrificata.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Le unità Veggente dei membri potranno utilizzare l'azione Sacrifica unità adiacente su qualsiasi unità amica adiacente a un vulcano attivo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>1 unità Veggente gratuita</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>1 promozione casuale gratuita a tutte le unità Veggente presenti e future</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+2 [ICON_Faith] Fede per turno</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dev'essere adiacente a un'unità militare amica a sua volta adiacente a un vulcano attivo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Deve trovarsi in una casella che può essere colpita da un disastro naturale.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dev'essere in guerra con l'altro giocatore per causare un disastro in territorio straniero.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Causa disastro</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Sacrifica unità adiacente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+1 Carica, +2 al [ICON_Movement] movimento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+1 Carica, guadagna Invisibilità.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+2 Cariche.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+1 Carica. Le unità adiacenti ottengono +5 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+1 Carica. Le città nemiche adiacenti sono automaticamente assediate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Le città nemiche adiacenti sono automaticamente assediate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+5 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento dall'unità Veggente adiacente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+5 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento dal Veggente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Veggente</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Messaggero</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Inquisitore</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Zelota</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Incantesimo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Untore</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>黙示録</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ようこそ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゲームの設定画面で「黙示録」モードを有効にできます。このモードでは災害がより深刻になるほか、新たなスコア型コンペとユニットが登場し、最終的には地表に彗星が落下して世界は終末を迎えます。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「黙示録」モードには新ユニット「終末の預言者」が登場します。このユニットには自然災害を引き起こす固有の能力が備わっています。適切な場所に移動させて「災害を起こす」アクションを実行すると、付近のタイルで水害、嵐、火事、火山の噴火を起こせます。このアクションを実行すると少量のCO2が排出され、気候変動が加速します。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者は、[ICON_Faith] 信仰力でのみ購入でき、護衛可能です。レベルアップとともに終末の預言者は災害を起こすためのチャージを手に入れます。終末の預言者は、経験値でなく新たに導入されるスコア型コンペによってレベルアップを獲得します。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>人身御供</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者のレベルアップを獲得するには、スコア型コンペ「人身御供」に参加しなければなりません。「人身御供」はゲームを通して登場するコンペで、終末の預言者を使って火山の近くで戦闘ユニットを生贄にするとスコアが得られます。高スコアを獲得した文明は、それ以降、すべての終末の預言者についてレベルアップを獲得します。ユニットを生贄にすると少量のCO2が排出され、気候変動が加速します。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>新たな災害</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「黙示録」モードでは、他のモードにはない災害が新たに2つ追加されます。[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]太陽フレア: 太陽から強烈な電磁波が降りそそぎ、全世界に悪影響が生じます。電力関連の建造物や施設が被害を受け、一部の区域が略奪状態になり、ゲーム終盤の高度なユニットもダメージをこうむります。[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]彗星の落下: 彗星が地球に激突し、落下地点にあったあらゆるものを破壊します。都市も例外ではありません。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>この世の終わり</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>気候変動が最大レベルに達すると、彗星の落下のような大被害をもたらす恐ろしい自然災害が起こりやすくなります。そうなってしまったら、早めに勝利条件を満たさなくてはなりません。さもないと、「この世の終わり」によって勝者が決められてしまいます。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>太陽フレア</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>太陽フレアはマップ全体に影響する災害です。太陽フレアが発生したターンは、 [ICON_POWER] 発電所が破壊され、高度なテクノロジーを用いているユニットや施設、 [ICON_POWER] 電力関連の建物やキャンパス、工業地帯、宇宙船基地区域が被害を受けます。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>彗星の落下</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「彗星の落下」は4つの隣接タイルと対象の都心に影響を及ぼします。落下した場所にあったものは完全に消滅し、そのタイルは通行できなくなります。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>危険に満ちた時代には、救いを説く者が渇望される。自然や政治、経済的な秩序が崩れると、決まって預言者が現れ、災害を食い止める方法や生きのびる術、敵に災いを押しつける方法などを人々に語るものだ。本作に登場する「終末の預言者」ユニットは、特定の文化や史実を反映したものではないが、人々がこうした人物に惹かれる例は、世界中の歴史の至るところで見られる。スペイン人の到来に対するメソアメリカ民の反応もそうだし、終末論の一種である千年王国を説くヨーロッパのカルトも同様だ。現代では、ヘヴンズ・ゲート (1997年、ヘーール・ボップ彗星が接近した際に集団自殺を強行した) のような宗教団体も仲間に入れて差し支えないだろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>たとえば、20世紀初頭、東南アジアのラオ語圏に「聖人」と呼ばれる預言者たちが現れた。彼らはフランスとシャムによって領土を分割され、重税に苦しみ、ビエンチャンの街を破壊されていたラオ族の人々に対し、「最悪の出来事が起きる」と説いた。牛や豚は悪魔に変わり、金はその価値を失い、今は無価値な石ころが黄金になり、荒ぶる風が大地を吹き抜け、レモングラスの葉にしがみつけなかった者たちを運び去る、と。こうした預言者の言葉を信じた多くの者が、石ころを集め、家畜を殺し、やがて来るという大いなる変化を待った。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>こうした騒動がハッピーエンドで終わることは滅多にない。ラオ族の運動はシャム軍によって鎮圧され、アステカ人の祈りがスペイン人の征服を止めることはなかったが、終末が到来する気配はないままだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>自分は神と直接対話できると称する預言者は多い。彼らにはいくつかのパターンがある。まずは夢のお告げに触発されて行動を起こした者だ。かつてラオスに現れた「聖者」はこのケースにあたるだろう。次は神から聖なる言葉を授かったと訴える者。20世紀初期のオカルティスト、アレイスター・クロウリーなどだ。自分は神に連なる人物の縁者だと訴える者もいる。イエス・キリストの弟を名乗り、太平天国の乱の中心人物となった洪秀全がこのパターンに当てはまる。共通するのは、いずれも人知の及ばぬどこかからメッセージを受け取り、それを実現しなければならないという思いに駆り立てられていたことだろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「審問」とは、本来は何かを問い質し、話を聞くことでしかない。しかしスペインの異端審問のせいで、今では「審問」と聞くと、異端者を見つけ出して裁判にかけることを思い浮かべるようになってしまった。聖なるメッセージを授かった者は、それに反する存在を抹殺しなくてはならないのだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>さまざまな終末論的運動において、集団をまとめる求心力として働くのが盲信だ。組織に言われたとおりに行動し、命を奪っても平気でいられるのは、信仰という一点において信者たちをが団結しているからにほかならない。だからこそ終末論には一定の説得力がある一方で薄気味が悪いのだろう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末論を説く集団には、えてして秘密の祈りがある。「それさえ唱えれば危険から身を守れる」というのが、うさんくさい預言者の用いる常套句だ。こうした祈りに用いられるのは、神の真名や「楽園」の到来を願う祈祷のこともあれば、神秘的すぎて預言者本人にも意味がわからない謎の言葉である場合もある。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の到来を説く集団は、自分たちで終末を実現しようとして行動を起こすことがある。中世には疫病が生物兵器として利用されることがあった。その最たる例がカッファ包囲だ。街を包囲したモンゴル軍が病気にかかった死体を投げ入れたことで、市内では病気が大流行したのだ。だが、実例を探すのにそれほど過去にさかのぼる必要はない。終末論を唱えるカルト集団 、オウム真理教が地下鉄に猛毒のガスを撒いた「地下鉄サリン事件」の発生は、1995年のことだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1908年、ヴァナヴァラの交易所で働いていたセミョン・セミョーノフは、彼の言葉を借りるなら、「空が二つに割れ、森全体がすさまじい炎に包まれた」のを見た。気温もいきなり上がり、初夏とは思えない耐えがたい暑さとなった。「それから空が閉じ… 大岩が崩れたか、大砲でも撃ったような轟音がして、熱風が家に吹きつけた。それこそ砲弾が落ちたかのように、熱風は地面にすさまじい傷跡を残した」。セミョーノフが体験したこの事件こそ、世に名高い「ツングースカ大爆発」である。原子爆弾の数千倍の威力を発揮したこの爆発は、彗星の破片、より具体的には直径約60メートルの氷塊がシベリアの針葉樹林帯に落下したことが原因と考えられている。ツングースカ大爆発のような彗星の落下は、核兵器に匹敵する被害を生じさせかねない。仮にもっと大きな彗星、すなわちメートル単位ではなくキロメートル単位の物が落下してきたら、それによって生じる被害は想像を絶するものとなるだろう。その影響は落下地域のみならず、全世界に及ぶ。近くにいた人々が瞬時に焼け死ぬだけにとどまらず、大気中に舞い上がった粉塵で日光が遮られることで気候が寒冷化し、世界中の植物が枯れてしまうのだ (枯れた草木が薪となり、大規模な森林火災が起きることも考えられる)。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>人身御供</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>世界が私たちに牙を剥きました！ 「黙示録」モードを有効にすると、干ばつ、嵐、水害、火山の噴火の発生がより頻繁になり、危険度も増します。不幸中の幸いというべきか、「終末の預言者」ユニットを訓練しておくと、こうした災いの矛先を敵に向けることができます。気候変動から目を離さないようにしましょう。最後の気温上昇をきっかけとして世界は終末期に突入し、災害が毎ターン発生するようになります！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>落雷か人災か、原因はわかりませんが、森林火災が発生しました！ 火災は隣接する森や熱帯雨林に燃え広がっていきます。煙は厄介ですが、灰はいい肥料になります。もちろん火が消えた後の話ですが。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>空から隕石が降ってきました！ 何をもたらしたのか確かめてみましょう。 </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>彗星が地球に激突しました！ 落下地点にあったものは壊滅的な被害を受けます。[NEWLINE]「永遠不滅のものなどありはしないのだ。」</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>強烈な太陽フレアが発生し、世界中であらゆる電気機器に異常が生じています。発電所や施設だけでなく、電力を使用するユニットも被害を受けています！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>信仰力を使って「終末の預言者」を獲得できるようになりました。終末の預言者は敵に災害をもたらすことができます。他の文明とのコンペで戦闘ユニットを火山に捧げれば、終末の預言者を強化することができます。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>この世の終わりが近づいています！ 以降の災害はこれまでにない規模で猛威を振るいます！ 滅亡する前に勝利を急ぎましょう！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「神々から、この世の終わりは近いとの警告があった。神々は信じる者を救いたまうが、それにはまず我々の信仰心を示さねばならない。誰よりも篤く神々を信じている者のみが報われるのだ。」</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>神々から、この世の終わりは近いとの警告があった。神々は信じる者を救いたまうが、それにはまず我々の信仰心を示さねばならない。誰よりも篤く神々を信じている者のみが報われるのだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>神々から、この世の終わりは近いとの警告があった。神々は信じる者を救いたまうが、それにはまず我々の信仰心を示さねばならない。誰よりも篤く神々を信じている者のみが報われるのだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者ユニットを使って「隣接ユニットを神に捧げる」アクションを実行すると、捧げたユニットの [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力に等しいスコアを得る。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>参加者の終末の預言者ユニットは、火山に隣接する味方ユニットに「隣接ユニットを神に捧げる」アクションを実行できる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>無償の終末の預言者ユニット1体</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>これ以降、すべての終末の預言者ユニットがランダムなレベルアップを無償で1つ得る</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>毎ターンの [ICON_Faith] 信仰力+2</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>活動中の火山に隣接した味方戦闘ユニットに隣接している必要がある。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>自然災害に影響されるタイルにいなければならない</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>相手と戦争中でなければ、他文明の領土に災害をもたらせない</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>災害を起こす</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>隣接ユニットを神に捧げる</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>チャージ+1。 [ICON_Movement] 移動力+2。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>チャージ+1。ステルスを得る。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>チャージ+2。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>チャージ+1。隣接ユニットの [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+5。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>チャージ+1。隣接する敵都市が攻囲状態になる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>隣接する敵都市が自動的に攻囲状態になる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>隣接する終末の預言者により [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+5。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者により [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+5。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>終末の預言者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>伝令</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>審問官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>盲信者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>まじない</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>病の運び手</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대재앙</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>환영합니다</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>플레이어는 게임 설정에서 대재앙 게임 모드를 활성화하여 자연재해 심각도를 변경하고, 새 점수 경쟁과 유닛을 도입하고, 혜성 강타를 일으켜 온 세상과 문명이 종말을 맞도록 설정할 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대재앙 게임 모드에는 예언자라는 신규 유닛이 등장합니다. 이 유닛은 자연재해를 일으킬 수 있는 능력을 지니고 있습니다. 예언자를 적절한 위치로 이동시킨 후 자연재해 유발 동작을 사용하여 인근 타일에 홍수, 폭풍, 화재, 화산 폭발을 일으킬 수 있습니다. 이로 인해 기후 변화를 가속하는 CO2가 소량 생성됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자는 [ICON_Faith] 신앙으로만 구매할 수 있고, 호위할 수 있습니다. 진급할 때마다 더 많은 자연재해 유발 횟수를 얻습니다. 예언자는 경험치를 획득하지 않는 대신, 새로운 점수 경쟁을 통해 새로운 진급을 잠금 해제합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>신 달래기</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자를 위한 진급을 획득하려면 신 달래기 점수 경쟁에 참가해야 합니다. 점수 경쟁은 게임을 진행하는 동안 나타나며, 예언자로 화산 근처에서 전투 유닛을 희생하여 점수를 얻을 수 있습니다. 높은 점수를 얻은 플레이어는 모든 현재 또는 미래 예언자에 대한 진급을 획득합니다. 유닛을 희생하면 기후 변화를 가속하는 CO2가 소량 생성됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>새로운 자연재해</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대재앙 게임 모드에서는 두 개의 새로운 자연재해를 독점적으로 이용할 수 있습니다. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 태양 플레어: 태양 복사 폭탄이 지구를 강타해 전력 관련 건물과 시설에 피해를 입히고, 특정 특수지구를 약탈하고, 게임 후반용 유닛에 피해를 입힙니다. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 혜성 강타: 혜성이 지구에 떨어져 도시를 비롯한 충돌 지점의 모든 요소를 파괴합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세계의 종말</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>기후 변화가 최고 수준에 다다르면 혜성 강타 같은 끔찍한 대재앙이 더욱 빈번하게 발생합니다. 이런 시점에서 플레이어는 빠르게 승리해야 합니다. 그러지 않으면 세계의 종말이 승자를 결정하게 됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>태양 표면 폭발</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>태양 표면 폭발은 지도 전체에 영향을 줍니다. 태양 표면 폭발이 발생한 턴에는 [ICON_POWER] 전력 관련 건물이 파괴되고, [ICON_POWER] 고급 유닛과 및 시설이 피해를 입으며, 산업구역, 캠퍼스, 우주 공항이 약탈당합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>혜성 강타</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>혜성 강타는 4개의 인접 타일이나 목표 도심부에 영향을 줍니다. 충돌 지점의 모든 요소를 파괴한 후 타일을 통과 불가 상태로 바꾸어놓습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>오래전부터 세상이 위기에 처할 때면 사람들은 구원을 약속하는 존재에 의지하곤 했습니다. 자연, 정치 또는 경제 질서가 무너질 때 예언자들이 나타나 파멸을 피하고, 파멸로부터 살아남고, 적들을 파멸시키는 방법을 사람들에게 전해줍니다. 여기에서 등장하는 예언자 유닛은 특정 문화나 역사적 순간을 반영하지는 않지만, 스페인 탐험대가 도착했을 때 메소아메리카인들의 반응, 유럽의 새천년 사이비 종교, '천국의 문' 같은 사이비 종교 집단 등 전 세계 역사에서 유사한 인물들을 많이 찾을 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예를 들어 20세기에 들어설 무렵 동남아시아의 라오족 언어권에서 "성자"라고 불리는 새로운 선지자들이 나타났습니다. 이 선지자들은 프랑스 군대와 샴 군대에 의한 국토 분할, 새로운 과세 제도와 비엔티안의 파괴를 경험한 라오족 사람들에게 끔찍한 일이 발생한다고 예언했습니다. 소와 돼지들이 악마로 변하고, 돈은 휴짓조각로 변하고, 지금은 쓸모없는 자갈이 황금으로 변할 거라고 말했습니다. 또한 거대한 바람이 대지를 휩쓸어 레몬그라스를 붙잡지 않은 사람들을 데려간다고도 말했습니다. 이 예언자들의 말을 믿은 많은 사람이 자갈을 수집하고 소유한 가축을 도살하며 새로운 시대가 오기를 기다렸습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자들의 예언이 적중한 적은 거의 없었습니다. 라오족의 행동은 샴 군대에 의해 진압되었고, 아즈텍 기도자들은 스페인 정복을 막지 못했으며, 세상의 종말은 한 번도 온 적이 없습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자들은 종종 자신들이 신과 직접 소통할 수 있다고 말합니다. 일부 예언자들은 라오족의 "성자"처럼 성스러운 꿈에서 계시를 받습니다. 반면에 20세기 초 주술사 알레이스터 크로울리의 경우처럼 신에게서 메시지를 받았다고 주장하는 사람도 있습니다. 또한 자기가 예수의 형제라고 주장한 태평천국 지도자 홍수전의 경우처럼 자신이 신들의 혈육이라고 주장하는 자들도 있었습니다. 하지만 모든 예언자는 어딘가로부터 반드시 전달해야 하는 메시지를 받았습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이단심문관은 질문을 하는 사람입니다. 하지만 스페인 종교 재판 이후 이 용어는 이단자들을 찾아 제거하는 사람들이라는 의미를 지니게 되었습니다. 신성한 메시지가 있는 경우 반대 메시지를 제거해야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>다양한 종말론 활동을 하나로 묶는 특징은 광적인 열정입니다. 조직이 요구하는 행동을 수행하고 신자들이 희생하도록 만들기 위해 종말론 단체의 추종자들은 신앙으로 굳게 단결합니다. 이는 추종자들의 믿음을 더욱 강하고 끔찍하게 만듭니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>종말론자 단체들은 종종 비밀 기도회를 열었으며, 예언자는 주문을 외워야만 화를 피할 수 있다고 얘기했습니다. 주문은 신의 비밀 이름, "순수한 땅"을 기원하는 반복적인 외침, 또는 예언자조차도 이해할 수 없는 비밀 언어로 구성되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>종말을 예견하는 단체들은 종말을 불러오기 위한 행동에 나서기도 합니다. 중세 시대에 흑사병은 생물학 무기로 사용되었습니다. 대표적인 예가 카파 함락 작전입니다. 이때 포위 병력은 전염병에 걸린 시체를 도시 안으로 던져 넣어 병을 일으켰습니다. 하지만 그리 멀리 거슬러 올라갈 필요는 없습니다. 1995년 일본의 오움진리교 교주는 새로운 시대를 열기 위해 도쿄 지하철에서 사린 가스 테러를 저질렀습니다. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>S. 세메노프는 1908년에 바나바라 교역소에 앉아 있다가 이렇게 말했습니다. "하늘이 반으로 갈라지고 불길이 숲에서 치솟을 것이다." 여름 날씨가 견딜 수 없게 더워졌습니다. 그리고 "하늘이 닫혔다... 그 후에 바위가 떨어지거나 대포를 발사하는 듯한 소음이 났다... 대포를 쏘는 듯 뜨거운 바람이 집들 사이에 휘몰아쳤으며, 지면에 좁은 길 같은 자국을 남겼다." 세메노프가 경험한 것은 시베리아 타이가에 떨어진 65m 지름의 얼음덩이인 혜성 파편이 원자 폭탄의 수천 배 규모의 폭발을 일으켰던 퉁구스카 대폭발 사건이었습니다. 퉁구스카 대폭발 같은 사건은 핵무기만큼이나 파괴적일 수 있으며, 수백 미터 크기의 더 큰 혜성이 강타한다면 지역뿐만 아니라 전 세계에 영향을 미치는 기하급수적 재앙을 일으킬 것입니다. 사고 근처에 있는 자는 불탈 것이고, 혜성은 대기에 먼지를 일으켜 햇빛을 막고, 기온을 낮추고 전 세계의 식물을 죽일 것입니다. (그에 따라 거대 산불을 초래할 것입니다.)</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>신 달래기</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세상이 우리를 버렸습니다! 대재앙 모드가 활성화되면, 가뭄, 폭풍, 홍수, 화산 폭발이 더 잦아지고 더 위험해집니다. 다행히도 이 재앙을 적에게 돌릴 수 있는 예언자를 훈련시킬 수 있습니다. 기후를 주시하십시오. 최종 기온이 상승하면 세상이 대재앙에 돌입하고, 매 턴 재앙이 들이닥칩니다!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>번개나 인간의 실수가 산불을 일으켰습니다! 불길이 인근 숲이나 정글에 퍼질 것입니다. 연기는 문제를 일으키지만, 재는 좋은 비료가 될 것입니다. 물론 불길이 사그라든 뒤에 말입니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>하늘에서 유성이 떨어졌습니다! 어디 한 번 상황을 봅시다. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>혜성이 지구를 강타했습니다! 혜성 강타는 부딪친 모든 것을 파괴합니다.[NEWLINE]‘처음부터 그 무엇도 남지 않았습니다.’</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세상은 모든 전자 장비를 망가뜨리는 태양 플레어를 겪고 있습니다. 전력 생산 건물 및 시설, 심지어 전기를 사용하는 유닛마저 피해를 입었습니다!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이제 신앙으로 예언자를 구입할 수 있습니다. 예언자는 적에게 재앙을 발생시킬 수 있습니다. 다른 문명과의 경쟁 중, 전투 유닛을 화산에 희생시켜 전력을 향상시킬 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세상에 종말이 다가옵니다! 유례 없는 규모의 재앙이 시작되었습니다! 파괴되기 전에 서둘러 승리하십시오!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>"신이 세계의 종말이 다가왔음을 경고했습니다. 신은 신자들에게 선물을 내리지만, 선물을 받으려면 신앙심을 증명해야 합니다. 신앙심이 가장 높은 자만 보상을 받습니다."</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>신이 세상의 종말이 임박했음을 경고했습니다. 신은 신자들에게 선물을 내리지만, 선물을 받으려면 신앙심을 증명해야 합니다. 신앙심이 가장 높은 자만 보상을 받습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>신이 세상의 종말이 임박했음을 경고했습니다. 신은 신자들에게 선물을 내리지만, 선물을 받으려면 신앙심을 증명해야 합니다. 신앙심이 가장 높은 자만 보상을 받습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자 유닛으로 "인접 유닛 희생" 행동을 사용하면 희생된 유닛의 [ICON_Strength] 전투력에 준하는 점수를 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자 유닛은 활화산에 인접한 아군 유닛에 대해 '인접 유닛 희생' 행동을 사용할 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>무료 예언자 유닛 1개</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>모든 현재 및 미래 예언자 유닛에 무료 무작위 진급 1회를 제공합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>턴마다 [ICON_Faith] 신앙 +2</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>활화산에 인접한 아군 전투 유닛과 인접해야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>자연재해의 영향을 받을 수 있는 타일에 있어야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>외국 영토에 재해를 일으키려면 소유한 플레이어와 전쟁을 해야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>자연재해 유발</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>인접 유닛 희생</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌격 +1과 [ICON_Movement] 이동력 +2를 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌격 +1과 스텔스 능력을 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌격 +2를 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌격 +1을 얻습니다. 인접 유닛에 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +5를 부여합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌격 +1을 얻습니다. 인접 적 도시는 자동으로 포위됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>인접 적 도시는 자동으로 포위됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>인접 예언자로부터 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +5를 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자로부터 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +5를 얻습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>예언자</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>전령</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이단심문관</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>광신자</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>주문</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>역병 운반자</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Apokalipsa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Witaj</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W ustawieniach gry gracze mogą włączyć tryb apokalipsy, zmieniający nasilenie katastrof, wprowadzający nową jednostkę i punktowaną rywalizację oraz ostatecznie doprowadzający do końca świata, który powodują kolizje planety z kometami.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wieszcz</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Tryb apokalipsy wprowadza do gry nową jednostkę – wieszcza. Dysponuje ona unikalną umiejętnością wywoływania katastrof naturalnych. Wystarczy umieścić wieszcza w odpowiedniej lokalizacji i użyć działania „Wywołaj katastrofę”, by na pobliskich polach rozpętała się burza, doszło do powodzi, wybuchu pożaru lub erupcji wulkanu. Działanie to generuje niewielką ilość CO2, która przyśpiesza zmianę klimatu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wieszczy można nabyć jedynie za [ICON_Faith] wiarę; mogą być eskortowani. Z każdym awansem zyskują kolejne punkty potencjału, dzięki którym mogą wywoływać katastrofy. Wieszcze nie zdobywają doświadczenia – ich awanse odblokowywane są dzięki udziałowi w nowej punktowanej rywalizacji.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Przebłaganie bogów</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Aby zdobyć awans dla swoich wieszczy, musisz wziąć udział w punktowanej rywalizacji o nazwie „Przebłaganie bogów”. Podczas rozgrywki twoi wieszcze będą mogli zyskiwać punkty, składając w ofierze należące do ciebie jednostki bojowe, które znajdą się w pobliżu wulkanów. Gracze z najwyższymi wynikami zdobędą awanse dla wszystkich swoich bieżących i przyszłych wieszczy. Poświęcanie jednostek generuje niewielką ilość CO2, która przyśpiesza zmianę klimatu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nowe katastrofy</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W trybie apokalipsy dostępne są dwie nowe katastrofy:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Rozbłyski słoneczne – promieniowanie elektromagnetyczne bombarduje całą planetę, uszkadzając budowle i usprawnienia związane z energią, plądrując część dzielnic i zadając obrażenia jednostkom z późniejszych etapów rozgrywki. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Uderzenia komet – kometa uderza w planetę, niszcząc wszystko, co stanie jej na drodze, nawet miasta.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Koniec świata</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Częstotliwość występowania straszliwych, siejących ogromne zniszczenia katastrof – zwłaszcza uderzeń komet – wzrasta w chwili, gdy zmiany klimatu osiągną maksymalny poziom. Graczom pozostaje wtedy jedynie osiągnięcie szybkiego zwycięstwa, zanim zwycięzcę wyłoni za nich koniec świata.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Rozbłyski słoneczne</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Rozbłyski słoneczne wpływają na całą mapę. W turze, w której do nich dojdzie, niszczą [ICON_POWER] elektrownie oraz mogą uszkodzić zaawansowane jednostki i ulepszenia, budowle związane z [ICON_POWER] energią, kampusy, dzielnice przemysłowe i porty kosmiczne.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Uderzenia komet</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Uderzenia komet wpływają na cztery sąsiednie pola lub centra trafionych miast, usuwają wszystko, co stanie na ich drodze, i sprawiają, że pole staje się nieprzekraczalne.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W czasach kryzysu ludzie od dawna zwracali się ku tym, którzy obiecywali jakąś formę wybawienia. Kiedy załamuje się porządek naturalny, polityczny lub gospodarczy, pojawiają się wieszcze, którzy mogą zapewnić ludziom sposób na powstrzymanie katastrofy, przetrwanie jej lub wykorzystanie, by zaszkodzić wrogom. Chociaż jednostka wieszcza przedstawiona w grze nie odzwierciedla żadnej określonej kultury ani momentu historycznego, to w dziejach ludzkości znaleźć można wiele przykładów zwracania się ku tego typu postaciom – od reakcji rdzennych mieszkańców Mezoameryki na przybycie Hiszpanów po europejskie kulty milenijne czy współczesne grupy pokroju Heaven’s Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dla przykładu, na przełomie XIX i XX wieku w laotańskojęzycznych częściach Azji Południowo-Wschodniej pojawili się nowi prorocy, „święci mężowie”. Przepowiedzieli mieszkańcom Laosu, na których oczach zamieszkiwane przez nich terytorium podzieliły między siebie siły francuskie i syjamskie, wprowadzono nowe systemy opodatkowania i zniszczeniu uległo miasto Wientian, że czekają ich jeszcze gorsze rzeczy. Krowy i świnie miały zmienić się w demony. Pieniądze miały stracić całą wartość, a bezwartościowy żwir – stać się złotem. Przez ląd przetoczyć się miała potężna wichura, która porwie każdego, kto nie będzie w stanie utrzymać się kępy trawy cytrynowej. Wielu uwierzyło tym wieszczom – gromadzili żwir, zabijali własne zwierzęta i wyczekiwali wielkiej zmiany mającej nastąpić już niebawem.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wieszcze rzadko kończą dobrze. Ruchowi laotańskich „świętych mężów” kres położyły odziały syjamskich żołnierzy, modły Azteków nie powstrzymały hiszpańskiego podboju, a data zapowiadanego końca świata jest nieustannie przekładana.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wieszcze często starali się sprawiać wrażenie osób, które pozostają w bezpośrednim kontakcie z boskością. Niektórzy byli inspirowani świętymi snami, jak laotańscy „święci mężowie”. Inni twierdzili, że posiadają boskie teksty dane im przez bóstwa, niczym okultysta z początku XX wieku, Aleister Crowley. Byli nawet tacy, którzy utrzymywali, że sami są spokrewnieni z boskimi postaciami, tak jak Hong Xiuquan, przywódca powstania tajpingów, który twierdził, że jest bratem Jezusa Chrystusa. Wszystkich ich łączyło jednak to, że mieli jakąś wiadomość pochodzącą spoza zwykłego świata i czuli się zobowiązani, by ją doręczyć.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Inkwizytor to po prostu ten, który zadaje pytanie, jednak od czasu hiszpańskiej inkwizycji słowo to jest kojarzony z ludźmi starającymi się wykryć i wyeliminować heretyckie wierzenia. Gdy ktoś niesie święte przesłanie, zwyczajnie musi eliminować przekazy, które mu się przeciwstawiają.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jedyną rzeczą łączącą najróżniejsze ruchy apokaliptyczne jest ich dewocja. Aby wykonywać działania, których żądają takie grupy, i składać ofiary, których dokonują ich wyznawcy, zeloci grup apokaliptycznych są zjednoczeni we wspólnej wierze. To właśnie dzięki temu są tacy przekonujący... i przerażający.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Grupy apokaliptyczne niejednokrotnie miały swą sekretną modlitwę, a wieszcze często obiecywali, że jej intonowanie zapewnia bezpieczeństwo. Modlitwą taką mogły być sekretne imiona boga, powtarzająca się odezwa do „czystej krainy” lub coś w języku tak tajemnym, że nawet wróżbita nie rozumiał z tego ani słowa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Bywa, że grupy, które zapowiadają koniec czasów, podejmują działania mające na celu przyśpieszenie nieuniknionego. W średniowieczu ludzie wykorzystywali dżumę jako broń biologiczną; szczególnie uderzający przykład to oblężenie Kaffy, gdy zainfekowane zwłoki wrzucono za mury twierdzy, by spowodować w niej wybuch epidemii. W poszukiwaniu ilustracji nie musimy się jednak cofać aż tak daleko w czasie – jeszcze w 1995 roku sekta Aum Shinrikyo próbowała rozpocząć nową erę, uwalniając w tokijskim mieście toksyczny gaz sarin. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W 1908 roku S. Semenow siedział w punkcie handlowym Wanawara, kiedy – jak później relacjonował – „niebo rozpadło się na dwie części i wysoko nad lasem pojawił się ogień”. Letni dzień nagle stał się nieznośnie gorący, a później „niebo się zatrzasnęło [...] i rozległ się hałas przypominający kamienną lawinę lub salwę z dział armatnich [...] Między domami zaczął wiać gorący wiatr, który pozostawiał na ziemi ślady przypominające ścieżki”. Wydarzenie opisane przez Semenowa przeszło do historii pod nazwą katastrofy tunguskiej. Była to eksplozja o mocy tysiąc razy większej niż wybuch bomby atomowej, wywołana przez fragment komety – odłamek lodu o średnicy około 65 metrów – który spadł na syberyjską tajgę. Zderzenia takie jak to nad Tunguzką mogą być równie niszczycielskie, co broń nuklearna, a większy obiekt – o średnicy mierzonej w kilometrach – spowodowałby katastrofę o skutkach wykładniczo większych, obejmujących cały świat. Poza spaleniem wszystkiego, co znalazłoby się w pobliżu miejsca jej upadku, taka kometa wzbiłaby też do atmosfery olbrzymie ilości pyłu, blokując światło słoneczne, schładzając klimat i zabijając roślinność (a w ten sposób tworząc podpałkę pod olbrzymie pożary lasów) na globalną skalę.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Przebłaganie bogów|Przebłagania bogów|Przebłaganiu bogów|Przebłaganie bogów|Przebłaganiem bogów|Przebłaganiu bogów|przebłaganie bogów|przebłagania bogów|przebłaganiu bogów|przebłaganie bogów|przebłaganiem bogów|przebłaganiu bogów</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nasz świat zwrócił się przeciwko nam! Po włączeniu trybu apokalipsy susze, burze, powodzie i erupcje wulkanów występują częściej i są bardziej niebezpieczne. Na szczęście możesz wyszkolić wieszcza, który jest w stanie skierować te nieszczęścia na twoich wrogów. Obserwuj stan klimatu; wraz z ostatnim wzrostem temperatury rozpocznie się apokalipsa, a z nią katastrofy w każdej turze!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Błyskawica lub ludzki błąd spowodowały wybuch pożaru lasu! Płomienie rozprzestrzenią się na każde sąsiednie pole z lasem lub lasem deszczowym. Dym spowoduje pewne niedogodności, za to popiół będzie dobrym nawozem – oczywiście, gdy wygasną już płomienie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Z nieba spadły meteoryty! Sprawdźmy, co znajdziemy w miejscu ich upadku. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W Ziemię uderzyła kometa! Uderzenie komety niszczy wszystko, co znajdzie się w jego zasięgu.[NEWLINE]„Od początku samego nic nie trwa wiecznie”.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Świat znalazł się pod wpływem rozbłysku słonecznego, który ma szkodliwe działanie na nasze urządzenia elektryczne. Budowle i ulepszenia związane z generowaniem energii oraz wykorzystujące ją jednostki uległy uszkodzeniu!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Od teraz możemy wykorzystywać wiarę, by pozyskiwać jednostki wieszczy, które są w stanie wywoływać katastrofy szkodzące naszym wrogom. Rywalizując z innymi cywilizacjami, możesz zwiększyć moc wieszczy poprzez poświęcanie w wulkanach własnych jednostek bojowych.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nastał koniec świata! Planetą zawładnęły kataklizmy o niespotykanej dotąd skali! Śpiesz się, by osiągnąć zwycięstwo, zanim twoja cywilizacja ulegnie zniszczeniu!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>„Bogowie ostrzegli nas: zbliża się koniec tego świata. Obdarują swych wyznawców łaskami, lecz by ich dostąpić, musimy wykazać się gorliwością. Tylko najbardziej żarliwi zostaną nagrodzeni”.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Bogowie ostrzegli nas, że koniec jest bliski. Obdarują swych wyznawców łaskami, lecz by ich dostąpić, musimy wykazać się gorliwością. Tylko najbardziej żarliwi zostaną nagrodzeni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Bogowie ostrzegli nas, że koniec jest bliski. Obdarują swych wyznawców łaskami, lecz by ich dostąpić, musimy wykazać się gorliwością. Tylko najbardziej żarliwi zostaną nagrodzeni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wykorzystanie działania „Złóż w ofierze sąsiadującą jednostkę” przez wieszczy zwiększa wynik o punkty, których liczba równa się [ICON_Strength] sile bojowej poświęconej jednostki.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jednostki wieszczy należące do członków mogą używać działania „Złóż w ofierze sąsiadującą jednostkę” na przyjaznych jednostkach, które znajdują się na polach przyległych do aktywnego wulkanu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>1 darmowa jednostka wieszcza.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>1 darmowy losowy awans dla wszystkich istniejących już i przyszłych jednostek wieszczy</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+2 do [ICON_Faith] wiary na turę</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Musi znajdować się w sąsiedztwie przyjaznej jednostki bojowej przebywającej na polu przyległym do aktywnego wulkanu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Musi znajdować się na polu, które może ulec wpływowi klęski naturalnej.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Aby wywołać katastrofę na obcym terytorium, musisz być w stanie wojny z jego właścicielem.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wywołaj katastrofę</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Złóż w ofierze sąsiadującą jednostkę</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+1 punkt potencjału, +2 do [ICON_Movement] ruchu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+1 punkt potencjału, zyskuje możliwość ukrywania się.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+2 punkty potencjału.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+1 punkt potencjału. Sąsiednie jednostki zyskują +5 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+1 punkt potencjału. Sąsiednie wrogie miasta są automatycznie oblężone.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sąsiednie wrogie miasta są automatycznie oblężone.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+5 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej dzięki sąsiadującemu wieszczowi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+5 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej dzięki wieszczowi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wieszcz|Wieszcza|Wieszczowi|Wieszcza|Wieszczem|Wieszczu|wieszcz|wieszcza|wieszczowi|wieszcza|wieszczem|wieszczu</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Posłaniec|Posłańca|Posłańcowi|Posłańca|Posłańcem|Posłańcu|posłaniec|posłańca|posłańcowi|posłańca|posłańcem|posłańcu</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Inkwizytor|Inkwizytora|Inkwizytorowi|Inkwizytora|Inkwizytorem|Inkwizytorze|inkwizytor|inkwizytora|inkwizytorowi|inkwizytora|inkwizytorem|inkwizytorze</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zelota|Zeloty|Zelocie|Zelotę|Zelotą|Zelocie|zelota|zeloty|zelocie|zelotę|zelotą|zelocie</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Inkantacja|Inkantacji|Inkantacji|Inkantację|Inkantacją|Inkantacji|inkantacja|inkantacji|inkantacji|inkantację|inkantacją|inkantacji</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nosiciel plagi|Nosiciela plagi|Nosicielowi plagi|Nosiciela plagi|Nosicielem plagi|Nosicielu plagi|nosiciel plagi|nosiciela plagi|nosicielowi plagi|nosiciela plagi|nosicielem plagi|nosicielu plagi</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Режим апокалипсиса</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Добро пожаловать!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В настройках игры игроки могут включить режим апокалипсиса, при котором меняется серьезность катастроф, появляются новый юнит и новое конкурсное соревнование. Игра завершается концом света, когда на Землю и на все ее цивилизации проливается дождь из комет.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прорицатель</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В режиме апокалипсиса у игроков появляется новый юнит — прорицатель. Этот юнит обладает уникальной способностью вызывать природные катастрофы. Отведите прорицателя в нужное место и выберите действие «Устроить катастрофу», и он вызовет на клетках поблизости паводок, бурю, пожар или извержение вулкана. Это создает небольшой объем СО2, что ускоряет изменение климата.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прорицателей можно купить только за [ICON_Faith] веру. Их можно сопровождать военными юнитами. С каждым повышением у прорицателей становится все больше зарядов для вызова катастроф. Эти юниты не накапливают опыт — для их повышения следует побеждать в конкурсных соревнованиях.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ублажение богов</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Чтобы заработать повышения для своих прорицателей, вам придется принять участие в конкурсном соревновании «Ублажение богов». Оно будет возникать по ходу игры: вы сможете при помощи своих прорицателей приносить боевые юниты в жертву рядом с вулканами и получать за это очки. Игроки с наибольшим количеством очков получают повышения для всех действующих и будущих прорицателей. Жертвы создают небольшой объем СО2, что ускоряет изменение климата.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Новые катастрофы</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В режиме апокалипсиса доступны две новые уникальные катастрофы: [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Солнечные вспышки: на планету обрушиваются мощные потоки солнечной энергии, которые повреждают здания и улучшения, имеющие отношение к производству энергии, разоряют определенные районы и наносят урон юнитам последних этапов игры [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Падение кометы: огромная комета разрушает все в месте своего падения — даже города</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Конец света</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>После того как изменение климата достигнет последней фазы, станут чаще случаться крупные природные катастрофы, например падения комет. С этого момента игрокам нужно скорее добиться победы, пока конец света не рассудил по-своему.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Солнечные вспышки</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Солнечные вспышки влияют на всю карту. На первом ходу они уничтожают постройки и повреждают улучшения, связанные с производством [ICON_POWER] энергии, разоряют промышленные зоны, кампусы и космопорты, а также наносят урон продвинутым юнитам.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Падения комет</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Кометы поражают четыре соседние клетки. Также они могут угодить в городской центр. Все, что находится в пораженных клетках, будет уничтожено, а сами клетки станут непроходимыми.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В тяжелые времена люди всегда готовы идти за тем, кто пообещает им избавление от несчастий. По мере роста природного, политического или экономического беспорядка один за другим поднимают головы прорицатели, готовые помочь несчастным отвадить беду, пережить ее или направить ее на недруга. Прорицатель как юнит не отражает какую-либо конкретную культуру или исторический момент: в любую эпоху и в любом месте были свои пророки апокалипсиса — его возвещали и жрецы Мезоамерики после прибытия испанцев, и хилиастические секты, и современные культы вроде американской секты «Врата рая».</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Так, в начале XX века в лао-язычных районах Юго-Восточной Азии появились новые пророки — «пху ми бун» («благодатные»). Они предрекали новые потрясения лаоссцам, которым уже пришлось пережить разделение своих земель между французскими и сиамскими силами, введение новых налогов и разрушение города Вьентьяна. Коровы и свиньи должны были превратиться в демонов, деньги — обесцениться, а булыжники — обратиться в золото. Следом могучему урагану предстояло унести каждого, кто не успеет ухватиться за пучок лемонграсса. Этим прорицателям верили: многие собирали булыжники и убивали рабочих животных в ожидании грядущих перемен.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Впрочем, судьбы прорицателей зачастую незавидны. Лаосское движение было подавлено сиамскими войсками. Молитвы ацтеков так и не защитили их от испанского завоевания. А конец света все никак не наступит.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прорицатели часто заявляли, что находятся в прямом контакте с небесными силами. Некоторые, такие как «благодатные люди» в Лаосе, видели пророческие сны. Другие — например оккультист начала XX века Алистер Кроули — утверждали, что получили от богов священные тексты. Третьи даже объявляли себя родственниками святых, как, например, лидер Тайпинского восстания Хун Сюцюань, который утверждал, что является братом Иисуса Христа. Каждому прорицателю была открыта священная истина, которую следовало поведать миру.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Слово «инквизитор» переводится как «вопрошающий». Но со времен испанской инквизиции этот термин стал обозначать тех, кто ищет и искореняет ереси. Священная истина может быть только одна, поэтому носителей других религиозных взглядов необходимо истреблять.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Бесчисленные движения свидетелей конца света объединяет одно: их фанатизм. Выполнять все требования таких групп и идти на серьезные жертвы последователям апокалиптических сект помогает сплоченность в вере. Именно поэтому они бывают столь убедительны — и опасны.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Члены апокалиптических сект нередко придумывали тайные молитвы, и прорицатели часто уверяли, что их распевание убережет послушника от зла. Петь можно было тайное имя бога, взывание к некоей «Чистой Земле» или молитвы на языке столь тайном, что его не понимал даже сам прорицатель.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Секты, ожидающие конца света, иногда предпринимали активные действия для того, чтобы его приблизить. В Средние века, например, чуму использовали в качестве бактериологического оружия. Самым показательным примером стала осада Каффы, когда осаждающие забрасывали через крепостные стены зараженные тела, чтобы вызвать среди осажденных эпидемию. Но необязательно заглядывать так далеко в прошлое — совсем недавно, в 1995 году, апокалиптическая секта «Аум синрикё» распылила в токийском метро газ зарин, намереваясь тем самым дать начало новой эпохе. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В 1908 году житель фактории Ванавара Семен Семенов увидел, как «вдруг на севере небо раздвоилось, и в нем широко и высоко над лесом появился огонь». По земле пронеслась волна невыносимого жара, после чего «небо захлопнулось, и [...] пошел такой стук, словно с неба падали камни или стреляли из пушек [...] с севера пронесся горячий ветер, как из пушки, который оставил на земле следы в виде дорожек». Семенов стал свидетелем Тунгусского феномена — взрыва колоссальной силы, мощнее тысячи атомных бомб, вызванного падением фрагмента кометы — глыбы льда диаметром примерно 65 м — в сибирскую тайгу. Столкновения, подобные Тунгусскому феномену, сопровождаются ударами, сопоставимыми по мощности с атомным взрывом. Падение более крупных тел — диаметром в километры — вызовет глобальную катастрофу. Энергия, которая выделится при столкновении, испепелит все живое в округе; облако пепла заслонит собой солнце — это приведет к похолоданию и массовому вымиранию растительности. Кроме того, мертвая биомасса станет топливом для лесных пожаров.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ублажение богов</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Наш мир восстал против нас! В режиме апокалипсиса засухи, ураганы, наводнения и извержения вулканов случаются чаще и оказываются все разрушительней. К счастью, вы можете нанять прорицателя, который сможет повернуть эти катаклизмы против ваших врагов. Следите за климатом: после последнего повышения температуры начнется конец света и катастрофы будут сотрясать мир каждый ход!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Из-за молнии или человеческой небрежности начался лесной пожар! Огонь будет перекидываться на все клетки с лесом или джунглями поблизости. Конечно, дым пощиплет нам глаза, но зато зола отлично удобрит почву. Конечно же, после того как утихнет пламя.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>На землю обрушился град метеоритов! Посмотрим, что он нам принес. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>На землю упала комета! Удары комет уничтожают все на своем пути.[NEWLINE]«С самого начала времен ничто не длилось вечно».</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>На солнце случилась вспышка, и магнитная буря вредит нашим электрическим приборам. Здания и улучшения, производящие энергию, а также наши юниты, использующие электричество, были повреждены!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Теперь за веру мы можем получать прорицателей. Прорицатели умеют насылать на врагов стихийные бедствия. Вы можете состязаться с другими цивилизациями и приносить свои боевые юниты в жертву вулканам, чтобы сделать прорицателей сильнее.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Близится конец света! Землю начинают сотрясать катаклизмы невиданной доселе мощи! Успейте добиться победы, пока не погибнете!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>«Боги предупреждали нас, что конец света скоро наступит. Они даруют милость своим последователям, но сначала потребуется доказать им нашу преданность. Вознаграждены будут лишь самые ревностные».</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Боги предупреждали нас, что конец близок. Они даруют милость своим последователям, но сначала потребуется доказать им нашу преданность. Вознаграждены будут лишь самые ревностные.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Боги предупреждали нас, что конец близок. Они даруют милость своим последователям, но сначала потребуется доказать им нашу преданность. Вознаграждены будут лишь самые ревностные.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Использует действие «Пожертвовать соседним юнитом», получает очки, равные [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи принесенного в жертву юнита.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прорицатели участников могут использовать действие «Пожертвовать соседним юнитом» на дружественных юнитах, находящихся рядом с действующим вулканом.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>1 бесплатный юнит «Прорицатель»</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Одно бесплатное случайное повышение для прорицателей.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+2 [ICON_Faith] ед. веры за ход</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Должен находиться рядом с дружественным боевым юнитом возле действующего вулкана.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Должен находиться на клетке, которая может быть поражена стихийным бедствием.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Для организации катастрофы на чужой территории требуется состояние войны с игроком-владельцем.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Устроить катастрофу</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Пожертвовать соседним юнитом</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+1 заряд, +2 к [ICON_Movement] перемещению.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+1 заряд, получает скрытность.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+2 заряда.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+1 заряд. Соседние юниты получают +5 к [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+1 заряд. Соседние вражеские города автоматически осаждаются.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вражеские города по соседству осаждаются.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+5 к [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи от соседства с прорицателем.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+5 к [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи от прорицателя.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прорицатель|прорицателя|прорицателю|прорицателя|прорицателем|прорицателе</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Посланник|посланника|посланнику|посланника|посланником|посланнике</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Инквизитор|инквизитора|инквизитору|инквизитора|инквизитором|инквизиторе</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зелот|зелота|зелоту|зелота|зелотом|зелоте</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Заклинание|заклинания|заклинанию|заклинание|заклинанием|заклинании</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Заражённый чумой|заражённого чумой|заражённому чумой|заражённого чумой|заражённым чумой|заражённом чумой</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>天启</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>欢迎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在游戏设置中，玩家可打开“天启”游戏模式。此模式灾难的严重程度高于通常，拥有全新的积分竞赛和单位。玩家甚至还能目睹星球和文明被彗星撞击，见证世界末日的来临。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>“天启”游戏模式加入了新单位“预言者”。此单位拥有制造自然灾害的特殊能力。将其带到适当的位置并使用“制造灾难”操作即可在附近的单元格中引发洪水、风暴、火灾或火山喷发。此操作将生成少量二氧化碳，加速气候变化。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者只能以 [ICON_Faith] 信仰值购买、可被护送。每次升级后，其将获得更多制造灾难的次数。预言者无法获得经验值，而是通过全新的积分竞赛来解锁新升级。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>安抚诸神</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>获得预言者升级的方法是参加“安抚诸神”积分竞赛。此竞赛将会在游戏进程中出现，玩家可以使用预言者献祭火山附近的战斗单位，借此获得分数。如玩家获得高分，则当前和未来的预言者均能获得升级。献祭单位将生成少量二氧化碳，加速气候变化。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>全新灾难</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>“天启”游戏模式专属的两个全新灾难：[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 太阳耀斑：太阳辐射影响着整个世界，伤害与电力相关的建筑和改良设施、掠夺特定的区域，并伤害游戏后期的单位[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 彗星撞击：彗星撞击地球，摧毁撞击区的一切，城市也无法幸免</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>世界末日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>气候变化达到最高等级后，破坏性强的恐怖灾难（如彗星撞击）将更为常见。此时，玩家需要尽快达成胜利，否则世界末日便会来临。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>太阳耀斑</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>太阳耀斑会影响整个地图。在触发的回合中，其将破坏 [ICON_POWER] 发电厂，还可能损伤高级单位和改良设施、[ICON_POWER] 电力相关的建筑，以及学院、工业区和宇航中心区域。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>彗星撞击</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>彗星撞击将影响4个相邻的单元格或目标市中心，将移除撞击处单元格上的一切，并使这些单元格变为不可通行。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在危机时刻，人们通常会向那些承诺某种形式拯救的人寻求帮助。随着自然、政治或经济秩序的崩坏，预言者出现了。他们兴许能够带来避免灾难、逃过灾难，或者将灾难加到敌人头上的方法。虽然预言者这个单位并未反映任何特定文化或历史时刻，但我们可以在世界各地和历史上找到类似的例子。比如中美洲人对西班牙人到来的反应、到欧洲的千禧年邪教，再到今天“天堂之门”等团体。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>例如，20世纪初在东南亚的老挝语地区出现了新的先知“圣人”。老挝人民经历了无数苦痛：领土被法国和暹罗军队瓜分、新的课税制度让人苦不堪言、万象市的毁坏令人心痛万分。而这群所谓的“圣人”向老挝人民宣称，更糟糕的事情即将发生，牛和猪会变成恶魔、货币将一文不值，而砂砾将变成黄金。大风会吹过这片土地，未能抓住一丛柠檬草的人便会被风吹走。许多民众迷信这些预言者，开始收集砂砾并杀害自己的动物，等待着巨变的到来。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者通常都没有好下场。老挝运动遭到暹罗军队镇压、阿兹特克祈祷者未能阻止西班牙人的征服，而世界末日也似乎永远不会到来。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者经常自称能够和神直接沟通。一些人受到神圣梦境的启发，老挝的“圣人”便是如此；一些人声称拥有诸神颁发的神圣文书，20世纪早期的神秘学家阿莱斯特·克劳利就是如此。有些人甚至宣称自己便与神紧密相连，太平天国的领袖洪秀全便自称是耶稣的兄弟。但相同点是，所有预言者都收到了来自神界的信息，他们认为必须传递给世人。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>简单来说，审判官就是提问的人。但自从西班牙宗教法庭出现以来，这个词便与致力于寻找异端信仰并将其消灭的人联系了起来。如果要传递神圣的消息，就必须清除相反的消息。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>所有末日运动团体都有一个共性：信徒极为狂热。为了执行这些团体所要求的行动，并执行信徒所需要的献祭，末日运动团体在信仰上紧密团结一致。这也是为何有人会相信他们的原因，也是他们如此可怕的原因。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>天启团体通常有秘密祷告词，而预言者会声称进行祷告便能保证平安无事。这些祷告词可能是神的秘密称号、对“净土”的反复呼唤，或者是某种连预言者都无法理解的秘密语言。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>相信世界末日的团体有时会采取行动来传递消息。在中世纪，瘟疫被用作生物武器，最典型的例子是卡法之围期间，围城部队将感染者尸体投入城中，导致瘟疫爆发。不远的1995年，末日邪教“奥姆真理教”宣称要开创一个新时代，用沙林毒气袭击了东京地铁。 </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1908年的一天，谢尔盖·谢苗诺夫正坐在瓦纳瓦拉贸易站。正如他笔下所述，当时“天空裂成了两半，森林上空出现了又高又宽的火焰。”夏日变得异常炎热，然后“天空就像被封闭了……之后出现的声音类似于岩石坠落或大炮轰鸣……炽热的风疯狂地刮过房屋，就像出膛的炮弹，在地上留下了道路一般的痕迹。”谢苗诺夫经历的事件便是通古斯大爆炸，其当量相当于一颗原子弹的数千倍。爆炸的原因是一颗直径约65米的冰球彗星碎片撞击西伯利亚针叶林。通古斯大爆炸这样的撞击便拥有核武器一般的毁灭性，而更大的彗星撞击（直径以千米为单位）则将产生指数级的灾难性后果。其不仅会影响撞击地区，还将影响整个世界。撞击点附近的彗星碎片将燃烧，同时也会将尘埃混入到大气中，阻挡阳光并使气候变冷，接着全世界植被将逐渐死亡（引发大规模森林火灾）。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>安抚诸神</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>世界已经对我们反目！启用“天启”模式后，干旱、风暴、洪水和火山喷发将更加频繁，也更加危险。幸运的是，您可以生产“预言者”单位，将这些灾难转移到敌人的头上。注意气候变化，随着最终气温的升高，世界将面临灭顶之灾，灾难每回合都将袭来！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>林火燃起！原因可能是闪电，也可能是人为因素。林火将蔓延到相邻的树林或雨林单元格。虽然浓烟会带来一些麻烦，但林火熄灭后留下的灰烬却是极好的肥料。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>流星从天空中坠落！看看它们带来了什么。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>一颗彗星撞击了地球！彗星撞击摧毁了撞击点的一切。[NEWLINE]“一切皆烟消云散。”</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>全世界都受到太阳耀斑的影响，所有电力设施皆受到损害。我们的发电建筑和改良设施、甚至使用电力的单位都遭到了破坏！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>现在我们可以通过信仰值购买预言者。其能在敌人头上召唤出灾难。与其他文明进行积分竞赛、并将战斗单位献祭给火山，便能升级预言者。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>世界末日即将来临！从未见过的大型灾难即将发生！在末日时间快马加鞭获得胜利吧！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>“诸神已发出末日将至的警告。他们将对信徒施与福祉，但我们需要证明自己的虔诚。只有最狂热的信徒才能获得恩泽。”</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>诸神已发出末日将至的警告。他们将对信徒施与福祉，但我们需要证明自己的虔诚。只有最狂热的信徒才能获得恩泽。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>诸神已发出末日将至的警告。他们将对信徒施与福祉，但我们需要证明自己的虔诚。只有最狂热的信徒才能获得恩泽。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>使用单位“预言者”的“献祭相邻单位”操作，获得等同于被牺牲单位 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力的分数。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>成员国的“预言者”单位可以对与活火山相邻的友方单位执行“献祭相邻单位”操作。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1个免费预言者单位</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>当前和之后的所有“预言者”将获得1次免费随机升级</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>每回合的 [ICON_Faith] 信仰值+2。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>必须与紧邻活火山的友方战斗单位相邻。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>必须处于可受自然灾害影响的单元格上</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>必须与拥有领土的玩家处于战争状态，才能在外国领土中制造灾难</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>制造灾难</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>献祭相邻单位</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+1使用次数、+2 [ICON_Movement] 移动力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+1使用次数、获得隐身能力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+2使用次数。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+1使用次数。相邻单位+5 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+1使用次数、相邻的敌方城市将自动被围攻。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>相邻的敌方城市将自动被围攻。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>相邻预言者提供+5 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者提供+5 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>预言者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>信使</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>审判官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>狂信者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>咒语</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>瘟疫使者</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Apocalipsis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Bienvenida</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En la configuración de la partida, los jugadores pueden activar el modo de juego Apocalipsis, cambiar la gravedad de los desastres, introducir una nueva competición por puntos y una unidad más y, por último, contemplar el fin del mundo cuando los cometas acribillen el planeta y sus civilizaciones.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Adivino</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El modo de juego Apocalipsis presenta una nueva unidad, el Adivino. Esta unidad tiene la habilidad exclusiva de causar catástrofes naturales: llévalo a un lugar adecuado y usa la acción Provocar desastre para iniciar una inundación, una tormenta, un incendio o la erupción de un volcán en las casillas cercanas. Esto genera una pequeña cantidad de CO2, que acelera el cambio climático.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los Adivinos solo se pueden comprar con Fe [ICON_Faith] y se pueden escoltar. Con cada ascenso, obtienen más cargas por causar desastres. Los Adivinos no adquieren experiencia; en cambio, desbloquean nuevos ascensos mediante una nueva competición por puntos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Apaciguar a los dioses</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Para ganar ascensos para tus Adivinos, deberás participar en la competición por puntos de Apaciguar a los dioses. Esta aparecerá a lo largo de la partida y te ofrecerá la posibilidad de usar a los Adivinos para sacrificar a otras unidades de combate cerca de los volcanes y obtener así puntos. Los jugadores que obtengan una puntuación alta ganarán ascensos para todos sus Adivinos presentes y futuros. Sacrificar unidades genera una pequeña cantidad de CO2, que acelera el cambio climático.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Nuevos desastres</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Hay dos nuevos desastres exclusivos del modo de juego Apocalipsis: [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Erupciones solares: la radiación solar bombardea todo el planeta y daña los edificios y las mejoras relacionadas con la energía, saquea ciertos distritos e inflige daños a las unidades de las últimas fases. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Caídas de cometas: un cometa se estrella en el planeta y destruye todo lo que encuentra a su paso, incluso las ciudades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El fin del mundo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Se vuelven más frecuentes los grandes desastres que causan enormes daños, en especial las caídas de cometas, después de que el cambio climático alcance su nivel máximo. Llegados a ese punto, los jugadores tendrán que ganar con rapidez o el fin del mundo decidirá el vencedor por ellos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Erupciones solares</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Las erupciones solares afectan a todo el mapa. Durante el turno en el que surgen destruyen Plantas eléctricas [ICON_POWER] y pueden dañar unidades avanzadas y mejoras, edificios relacionados con la Energía [ICON_POWER] y los distritos de Campus, Zonas industriales y Puertos espaciales.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Caídas de cometas</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Las caídas de cometas afectan a cuatro casillas adyacentes o Centros urbanos objetivo, eliminan cualquier cosa que encuentren en el camino y hacen la casilla infranqueable.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En tiempos de crisis, la gente se vuelve hacia aquellos que prometen alguna forma de liberación. A medida que se desmorona el orden natural, político o económico, surgen adivinos que pueden proporcionarles una forma de evitar el desastre, de sobrevivir a este o de infligírselo a los enemigos. Si bien la unidad del Adivino no está destinada aquí a reflejar una cultura o momento histórico en concreto, podemos encontrar versiones similares de tales personajes en todo el mundo y en la historia, desde la reacción mesoamericana a la llegada de los españoles hasta las sectas milenarias europeas, pasando por cultos más o menos actuales como Heaven's Gate.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Por ejemplo, a principios del siglo XX, en las partes laoparlantes del sudeste asiático, surgieron unos profetas, los "hombres santos". Prometieron a los laosianos –que habían visto su territorio dividido entre las fuerzas francesas y siamesas, nuevos sistemas de impuestos y la destrucción de la ciudad de Vientián– que vendrían cosas peores. Por ejemplo, que las vacas y los cerdos se convertirían en demonios, que el dinero dejaría de tener valor, mientras que la despreciable gravilla se convertiría en oro. Y que un gran viento barrería la tierra y se llevaría consigo a cualquiera que no pudiera agarrarse a una mata de citronela. Muchos creyeron a estos adivinos, recogieron gravilla y mataron a sus animales, esperando el gran cambio que estaba por venir.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los adivinos rara vez terminan bien. El movimiento de Laos se vio reprimido por las tropas siamesas, las oraciones aztecas no detuvieron la conquista española y parece ser que el final de los tiempos nunca llega.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los adivinos a menudo decían estar en comunicación directa con lo divino. Algunos se veían inspirados por sueños sagrados, como los "hombres santos" de Laos; otros afirmaban tener textos divinos que les habían dado los dioses, igual que el ocultista de principios del siglo XX Aleister Crowley; y unos pocos llegaron incluso a decir que estaban emparentados con personajes divinos, como Hong Xiuquan, el líder de la Rebelión de Taiping, que afirmaba ser el hermano de Jesucristo. Pero todos tenían un mensaje de algún lugar del más allá que se sintieron obligados a predicar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En sentido literal, un inquisidor es simplemente alguien que inquiere algo. Pero, desde la Inquisición española, el término se ha asociado con aquellos que pretenden descubrir creencias heréticas y acabar con ellas. Si uno tiene un mensaje sagrado, se deduce que debe erradicar los mensajes opuestos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Lo único que une a estos movimientos apocalípticos tan dispares es su fanatismo. Para llevar a cabo los actos que dichos grupos exigen y hacer esos sacrificios, los fieles están unidos en su fe. En parte, por ello son tan convincentes... y aterradores.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los grupos apocalípticos solían tener una oración secreta, y los adivinos solían prometer que cantarla mantendría a sus seguidores a salvo. Estos ensalmos podían ser los nombres secretos de Dios, el llamamiento incesante a una "tierra pura" o algo en un idioma tan secreto que ni siquiera el adivino entendía.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los grupos que anticipan el final de los tiempos a veces toman medidas para lograrlo. La peste se usó como arma biológica en la Edad Media, sobre todo durante el asedio de Caffa, donde las tropas sitiadoras arrojaron cuerpos infectados a la ciudad, lo cual causó un brote de la pandemia. Pero no hace falta retroceder tanto: en 1995, la secta Aum Shinrikyo (Verdad Suprema) intentó auspiciar una nueva era atacando el metro de Tokio con gas sarín. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En 1908, S. Semenov estaba sentado en el apartado puesto comercial de Vanavara cuando, según sus palabras, "el cielo se abrió y apareció fuego en lo alto, sobre todo el bosque". El día de verano se volvió de un calor insoportable y luego "el cielo se cerró de golpe... y después se oyó un ruido, como si cayeran rocas o dispararan cañones... Un viento caliente corrió entre las casas, como si se tratara de desfiladeros, y dejó unos rastros como caminos en el suelo". Lo que vio Semenov fue el suceso de Tunguska, una explosión de unos miles de veces la potencia de una bomba atómica causada por la caída de un fragmento de cometa (una bola de hielo de unos 65 metros de diámetro) en la taiga siberiana. Si bien los impactos como el de Tunguska pueden ser tan devastadores como un arma nuclear, los cometas más grandes (del orden de kilómetros en lugar de metros) tendrían efectos catastróficos exponenciales que sufrirían no solo la zona, sino todo el mundo. Los que estuvieran cerca del impacto se quemarían, pero el cometa también levantaría una gran cantidad de polvo en la atmósfera que taparía la luz solar, enfriaría el clima y mataría la vegetación (lo cual crearía broza y madera, ideales para incendios forestales masivos) por todo el mundo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Aplacar a los dioses</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡El mundo se ha vuelto contra nosotros! Con el modo Apocalipsis activado, sequías, tormentas, inundaciones y erupciones volcánicas son más frecuentes y peligrosas. Por suerte, es posible entrenar a un Adivino para que pueda volver estas calamidades contra tus enemigos. No pierdas de vista el clima; con un aumento final de la temperatura, el mundo conocerá el Apocalipsis y se producirán desastres cada turno.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Un rayo o un error humano han provocado un incendio forestal! Las llamas se propagarán a todos los Bosques o Selvas adyacentes. Aunque el humo nos causará algunos problemas, las cenizas serán un buen fertilizante. Cuando se apaguen las llamas, claro.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Han caído meteoritos! Vamos a ver qué han traído. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡Un cometa ha caído en la Tierra! Los cometas destruyen todo cuanto tocan.[NEWLINE]"Desde el principio, nada ha perdurado".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El mundo está sufriendo una erupción solar que daña todo el equipamiento eléctrico. Los edificios y mejoras que producen Energía se han visto dañados. ¡Y también las unidades que usan electricidad!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Ya tenemos Adivinos disponibles a través de la Fe. Los Adivinos pueden invocar desastres sobre los enemigos. Compitiendo con otras civilizaciones, puedes aumentar el poder de estos si sacrificas unidades de combate en los volcanes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>¡El mundo se acaba! ¡Empiezan a producirse catástrofes de una magnitud jamás vista! ¡Apresúrate a conseguir la victoria antes de que te destruyan!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>"Los dioses nos avisan de que se acerca el fin del mundo. Ayudarán a sus seguidores, pero primero debemos demostrarles nuestro fervor. Solo se recompensará a los más entusiastas".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los dioses nos avisan de que se acerca el fin del mundo. Ayudarán a sus seguidores, pero primero debemos demostrarles nuestro fervor. Solo se recompensará a los más entusiastas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los dioses nos avisan de que se acerca el fin del mundo. Ayudarán a sus seguidores, pero primero debemos demostrarles nuestro fervor. Solo se recompensará a los más entusiastas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Usar la acción "Sacrificar unidad adyacente" con la unidad de Adivino da una puntuación igual a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] de la unidad sacrificada.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Las unidades de Adivinos de los miembros pueden usar la acción "Sacrificar unidad adyacente" con las unidades amistosas que estén junto a volcanes activos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>1 unidad de Adivino gratis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un ascenso aleatorio gratis para todas las unidades de Adivinos presentes y futuras.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+2 a Fe [ICON_Faith] por turno.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Debe estar adyacente a una unidad de combate aliada que esté adyacente a un Volcán activo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Debe estar en una casilla que pueda verse afectada por un desastre natural.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Para provocar un desastre en territorio extranjero hay que estar en guerra con el jugador al que pertenezca este.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Provocar desastre</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Sacrificar unidad adyacente</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+1 carga, +2 al Movimiento [ICON_Movement].</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+1 carga, gana Invisibilidad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+2 cargas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+1 carga. Las unidades adyacentes ganan +5 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength].</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+1 carga. Las ciudades adyacentes enemigas quedan asediadas automáticamente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Las ciudades adyacentes enemigas quedan asediadas automáticamente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+5 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] por Adivino adyacente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+5 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] por Adivino.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Adivino</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mensajero</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Inquisidor</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Zelote</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Ensalmo</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Apestado</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>末日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>歡迎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在遊戲設置中，玩家可打開「末日」遊戲模式。此模式災難的嚴重程度高於尋常，並且擁有全新的積分競賽和單位。玩家甚至還能目睹星球和文明遭到彗星撞擊，見證世界末日的來臨。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>「末日」遊戲模式加入了新單位「卜術士」。此單位擁有製造自然災害的特殊能力。將其帶到適當的位置並使用「造成災害」行動即可在附近的單元格中引發洪水、風暴、核事故或大火。此行動將生成少量二氧化碳，加快氣候變遷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SOOTHSAYER_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士只能以 [ICON_Faith] 信仰值購買且可進行護送。每次升級後，便可獲得更多造成災害次數。卜術士無法獲得經驗值，而是透過全新的積分競賽來解鎖新升級。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>安撫眾神</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_SCORED_COMPETITION_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士獲得升級的方法便是參加「安撫眾神」積分競賽。此競賽將會在遊戲進程中出現，玩家可以使用卜術士犧牲火山附近的戰鬥單位，從而獲得分數。如玩家獲得高分，則能為當前和未來的卜術士獲得升級。獻祭單位將生成少量二氧化碳，加快氣候變遷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>全新災難</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_NEW_DISASTERS_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>「末日」遊戲模式專屬的兩個全新災難：[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 閃焰：太陽輻射轟炸全世界，損傷與電力相關的建築和改良設施、掠奪特定的區域，並傷害遊戲後期的單位[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] 彗星撞擊：彗星撞地球，摧毀撞擊區的一切，城市也無法倖免</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>世界末日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MEGADISASTERS_CHAPTER_END_OF_WORLD_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>氣候變遷達到極點後，如彗星撞擊等破壞性強大的恐怖災難將更為常見。此時，玩家需要儘快達成勝利，否則世界末日便會來臨。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>閃焰</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FLARES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>閃焰會影響整個地圖。在觸發的回合中，其將破壞 [ICON_POWER] 發電廠；並可能損傷高級單位與改良設施、[ICON_POWER] 電力相關的建築，以及學院、工業區和太空中心區域。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>彗星撞擊</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_COMETS_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>彗星撞擊將影響4個相鄰的單元格，毀去這些單元格上的一切，並導致單元格無法通行。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在危急時刻，人們通常會向那些承諾某種拯救形式的人尋求幫助。隨著自然、政治或經濟秩序的崩毀，卜術士出現了。他們興許能夠趨吉避凶，或者將災難轉嫁到敵人頭上的方法，雖然卜術士這個單位並未反映任何特定文化或歷史時刻，但我們可以在世界各地和歷史上找到類似的例子。比如中美洲人對西班牙人到來的反應、到歐洲的千禧年邪教，再到今天的「天堂之門」等團體。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>例如，20世紀初在東南亞的寮語地區出現了新的先知「聖人」。寮國人民經歷了無數苦痛：領土被法國和暹羅軍隊瓜分、新的課稅制度讓人苦不堪言、永珍市的毀壞令人心痛萬分。而這群所謂的「聖人」向寮國人民宣稱，更糟糕的事情即將發生，牛和豬會變成惡魔、貨幣將一文不值，而砂礫將變成黃金。大風會吹過這片土地，未能抓住一叢檸檬草的人便會被風吹走。許多民眾迷信這些卜術士，開始收集砂礫並殺害自己的動物，等待著巨變的到來。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_SOOTHSAYER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士通常都沒有好下場，寮國運動遭到暹羅軍隊鎮壓、阿茲特克祈禱者未能阻止西班牙人的征服，而世界末日也似乎永遠不會到來。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士經常自稱能夠和神直接溝通。一些人受到神聖夢境的啟發，寮國的「聖人」便是如此；一些人聲稱擁有諸神頒發的神聖文書，20世紀早期的神秘學家阿萊斯特·克勞利就是如此。有些人甚至宣稱自己便與神緊密相連，太平天國的領袖洪秀全便自稱是耶穌的兄弟。但相同點是，所有卜術士都收到來自神界的資訊，他們認為必須傳遞給世人。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>簡單來說，審判官就是提問的人。但自從西班牙宗教法庭出現以來，這個詞便與致力於尋找異端信仰並將其消滅的人聯相互連結。如果要傳遞神聖的消息，就必須清除相反的消息。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>所有末日運動團體都有一個共性：信徒極為狂熱。為了執行這些團體所要求的行動，並執行信徒所需要的獻祭，末日運動團體在信仰上緊密團結一致。這也是為何有人會相信他們的原因，也是他們如此可怕的原因。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>末日團體通常有秘密禱告詞，而卜術士會聲稱進行禱告便能保證平安無事。這些禱告詞可能是神的秘密稱號、對「淨土」的反復呼喚，或者是某種連卜術士都無法理解的秘密語言。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>相信世界末日的團體有時會採取行動來傳遞消息。在中世紀，瘟疫被用作生化武器，最典型的例子是卡法之圍期間，圍城部隊將感染者屍體投入城中，導致瘟疫爆發。距今不遠的1995年，末日邪教「奧姆真理教」便宣稱要開創一個新時代，用沙林毒氣襲擊了東京地鐵。 </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_COMET_LAKE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>1908年的一天，謝爾蓋‧席美諾夫正坐在瓦納瓦拉貿易站。如他所述，當時「天空裂成了兩半，森林上空出現了又高又寬的火焰。」那天的夏日突然變得異常炎熱，然後「天空就像被封閉了...之後出現的聲音類似於岩石墜落或大炮轟鳴...熾熱的風瘋狂地刮過房屋，就像出膛的炮彈，在地上留下了道路一般的痕跡。」席美諾夫經歷的事件便是通古斯大爆炸，其當量相當於一顆原子彈的數千倍。爆炸的原因是一顆直徑約65公尺的冰球彗星碎片撞擊西伯利亞針葉林。通古斯大爆炸這種規模的撞擊便擁有如核子武器一般的破壞力，倘若遇到更大的彗星（例如直徑以公里計的隕石）撞擊，其災難性後果將以指數性增長。其不僅會影響撞擊地區，還將影響整個世界。撞擊點附近會起火燃燒，而彗星的塵埃同時也會混入大氣中，阻擋陽光並使氣候變冷，接著全世界植被將逐漸枯死（進而製造出發生大規模森林火災的條件）。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_APPEASE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>安撫眾神</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>我們的世界向我們反撲了！啟用「末日模式」後，旱災、風暴、洪災及火山爆發皆會更為頻繁且更加危險。好險，玩家可以生產卜術士來將這些災殃轉到敵人身上。隨時留意氣候環境，最後一次氣溫升高後，全世界將進入末日，屆時每回合都會有天災來襲！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>閃電或人禍引發了森林大火！野火會傳播至相鄰的森林或叢林。儘管煙霧會造成不少麻煩，但其灰燼將會是良好的肥料。當然，這得先等火勢消退以後。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>隕石從天而降了！來看看它們當中蘊含些什麼吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>彗星撞地球了！彗星撞擊會摧毀所有擊中的地區。[NEWLINE]「打從最一開始便注定無事能夠長存。」</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>全世界經歷了一次閃焰，損壞了所有電子設備。我們產生電力的建築與改良設施，甚至是使用電力的單位，全數遭到損傷！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士現在可供我們使用信仰值購買。卜術士能在敵人頭上降下災難。與其他文明競爭時，玩家可以透過將自己的戰鬥單位獻祭至火山中來提升其威力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>世界要末日了！天災開始以人類前所未見的規模展開！在遭到摧毀之前快速取得勝利！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_CONGRESS_APPEASE_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>「眾神早已預警世界末日將臨。祂們將賜與信徒豐饒，但我們必須先證明自己的熱忱。只有最狂信之人才能獲得獎賞。」</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_DESCRIPTION_APPEASE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>眾神早已預警末日將臨。祂們將賜與信徒豐饒，但我們必須先證明自己的熱忱。只有最狂信之人才能獲得獎賞。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_FLAVOR_APPEASE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>眾神早已預警末日將臨。祂們將賜與信徒豐饒，但我們必須先證明自己的熱忱。只有最狂信之人才能獲得獎賞。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_SCORE_APPEASE_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>利用他們的卜術士單位使用「獻祭相鄰單位」行動，可獲得與遭獻祭單位 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力相等的分數。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_MEMBER_BUFF_DESCRIPTION_ACCESS_TO_APPEASE_UNIT_ACTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>成員的卜術士單位可對鄰近活火山的友方單位使用「獻祭相鄰單位」行動。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FREE_SOOTHSAYER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>1個免費的卜術士單位</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_SOOTHSAYER_PROMOTION_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>所有當前和未來的卜術士單位獲得1個隨機的免費強化</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_EMERGENCY_REWARD_FAITH_PER_TURN_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>每回合+2 [ICON_Faith] 信仰值</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NO_ADJACENT_VOLCANO" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>必須相鄰於活火山旁邊的友方戰鬥單位。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_DISASTER_TILE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>必須位在能受到天災影響的單元格</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ACTIVATE_BLOCKER_NOT_VALID_TERRITORY_TILE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>要在外國領土中造成災害，則必須與擁有此領土的玩家開戰</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_CAUSE_DISASTER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>造成災害</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITOPERATION_SACRIFICE_UNIT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>獻祭相鄰單位</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+1使用次數，+2 [ICON_Movement] 移動力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+1使用次數，獲得匿蹤效果。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+2使用次數。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+1使用次數。相鄰單位+5[ICON_Strength]戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+1使用次數。相鄰的敵方城市自動受到圍攻。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_AUTO_SIEGE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>相鄰的敵方城市自動受到圍攻。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>相鄰卜術士提供+5 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SOOTHSAYER_AOE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士提供+5 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_CLASS_SOOTHSAYER_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>卜術士</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_MESSENGER_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>信使</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INQUISITOR_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>審判官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_ZEALOT_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>狂信徒</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_INCANTATION_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>咒語</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROMOTION_SOOTHSAYER_PLAGUE_BEARER_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>瘟疫使者</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>